<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://sivers.org/en.atom</id>
  <title>Derek Sivers</title>
  <updated>2014-03-13T14:45:53+01:00</updated>
  <link href="http://sivers.org/"/>
  <author>
    <name>Derek Sivers</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>How will this game end?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/game</id>
    <updated>2014-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/game"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You might have heard this one before.  If not, pay attention.  It’s a good one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Imagine I announce &lt;strong&gt;I am going to sell a $100 bill by auction, and the bidding starts at only $1.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The only rule of the game is this: &lt;strong&gt;if you are the 2nd-highest bidder, you still have to pay what you bid&lt;/strong&gt;, but you don’t get the $100 bill. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course I get some bids for $1, $2, $3.  Why not?  Hey - a chance to get $100 for $3!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The bids keep coming in.  By $51 I’m happy - I’m going to profit now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once they get to $90, there’s less enthusiasm, but reason to stay in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once they get to $99, though, the person offering $98 thinks, “Uh oh. The other person isn’t backing down,” and raises their bid to $100 so as not to be 2nd-lowest and lose the entire $99.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But now the person offering $99 raises their bid to $101.  Better to lose only $1 than $99, right?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Soon they’re offering $110, $120, $150.  This game could go on forever.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The real problem: not thinking it through in advance.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When the game starts, it’s easy to think short-term and say, “Ooh! Good deal!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then when it’s too late, you slowly realize, ”Uh-oh. What have I done?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A lot of people get into life situations like this.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The entrepreneur who borrows a lot of money to test an idea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The homeowner who bought a house at the top end of their budget.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The romantic who gets into a relationship with someone who is already in a relationship.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can hear them whining about how they’re so in debt, or their sweetheart is cheating.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Oops!  Didn’t think that one through, huh?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The game was clearly rigged against them, so the smart choice is to not play that game at all.
We should always ask, “How will this game end?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It’s &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; to think through the long-term implications of everything we’re doing now.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s hard, but it’s worth the effort.  I’m just posting this here as a reminder (to myself, too).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/bull.jpg" width="650" height="502" alt="bull staring at man"/&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vinothchandar/6748059859/"&gt;Vinoth Chandar&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Imitate. We are imperfect mirrors.</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/mirror</id>
    <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/mirror"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You know that song you love, that you wish you wrote?  Copy it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You know that existing business, that you wish you had thought of?  Copy it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because humans are imperfect mirrors.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Like a funhouse mirror that distorts what it reflects&lt;/strong&gt;, even if you try to imitate something, it will turn out much different than the original.
Maybe better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When a musician covers someone else's song, they clearly reveal their own warped perspective, since we know what the original looks (sounds) like.
Because of this, a cover song is actually a great way to define who you are as an artist.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When a musician writes a new song, imitating someone else's song, it's usually unrecognizable.
You have to tell people of its inspiration, for them to make the connection.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So an entrepreneur can imitate someone else's business, and still be adding a unique service to the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I resisted this lesson as long as I could.&lt;/strong&gt;
It offended my instincts as an artist.
I felt that everything I did had to be 100% original.
Everything “not invented here” was out of the question.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Back in my CD Baby days, my only direct competitor had one awesome advantage: old fashioned credit card swiping machines that musicians could use to sell CDs at gigs, even without electricity or a 3G connection.
Musicians would tell me how much they loved that service, and even told me they wish we had it too.
I said, “Yeah. Damn. Oh well.”
Because imitating their offering didn't even enter my mind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It took a whole year for me to swallow my pride, and realize I'd be doing my clients a favor if I imitated that idea.
&lt;strong&gt;It turned out to be one of the most successful things I ever did.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Those little credit card swiping machines charged over $8.5 million for thousands of musicians, which meant $7.75 million paid out to the musicians, and $750k profit for us.
And the whole thing only took two weeks to make, and one employee to run.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So look around at those existing ideas in the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Get over that self-important resistance, and do the world a favor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/mirror.jpg" width="420" height="627" alt="funhouse mirror" /&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Vietnam</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/vn14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/vn14"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is by Jeremy Wellard, who is based in Hanoi at &lt;a href="http://c3vietnam.com/"&gt;C3 Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, and is founding director of &lt;a href="http://communehanoi.com/"&gt;Commune Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;, a co-working cafe and creative hub.  This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing most people know of Vietnam is the Vietnam War.  In Vietnam, they call it the American War, and it’s just old history.  There is so much more to this youthful, thriving country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has long been considered the cultural and artistic heart of Asia, and the Vietnamese are the “Italians of Asia”. Highly social and heart-driven, with a penchant for drama and performance they are quick to raise their voices to sway a discussion, but equally quick to laugh off a misunderstanding. One of the greatest strengths of Vietnamese is their ability to find joy in everyday moments. Whether laboring in the fields or rushing through busy urban lives, they still find any excuse to put down their tools and laugh in conversation over a cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since opening up to the world in the late 1980s, the Vietnamese have been racing ahead at full speed. Years of struggle under a system of collective production left people ready to enthusiastically embrace capitalist ideals. Since the late 1990s, Vietnam has had one of the highest economic growth rates in the world. This rapid growth created a highly entrepreneurial environment where everyone seems to have a second or third business on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is the world’s only “Socialist-Oriented Market Economy”. This means the government maintains a large ownership and control of major companies, while small and medium businesses are left to develop freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget any notions of the frugal communist lifestyle. Wealth and possessions are flaunted as signs of success. People will spend many months’ salary for a status symbol like an iPhone, fancy motorbike, or designer clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there’s a deep-seated habit of saving money wherever possible. This can be seen in shops, where the air-conditioning is turned off until a customer walks in, or in the recycling culture where even used plastic bags have value. Vietnamese take great pride in their bargaining skills. When a new purchase is shown to friends, someone will immediately ask how much they paid for it. Ability to negotiate a good price demonstrates not just savvy but strong relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading on relationships is key.  A popular saying is, “First your family, second your friends, third comes money.”  This means people will always look out for family and friends, but for outsiders their help comes at a price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong family networks define the career and social lives of many Vietnamese. The government strongly recommends families have only two children, and most do. There are highly traditional expectations regarding responsibility to family, education, career choices, gender roles, marriage, and children. Newly wed couples live at the home of the husband’s parents until they can afford to buy their own house. Three generations often live together under one roof, and grandparents play an important role in providing childcare. Because of this in-home care, mothers usually return to work much sooner than the six months of maternity leave given by Vietnam’s labor laws, which strongly favor worker’s rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Vietnam, the year and date of a person’s birth is very important. It influences their whole life, including when they are allowed to marry, open a business, hold important meetings and have children. Social interactions and forms of address are determined by age, so upon meeting a new person, one of the first questions Vietnamese will ask is what year they were born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of a strongly collective past, where standing out from the crowd was potentially dangerous, new ideas may be regarded with caution.  But once the viability of an idea is demonstrated, acceptance, imitation and adaptation rapidly follow.  This tendency to follow others can lead Vietnamese to seem unoriginal in their thinking. But in fact their ability to quickly see an opportunity and willingness to capitalize on it creates a very dynamic and exciting environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the collective past, upwardly mobile Vietnamese have fully embraced the concept that the individual who works smarter and has more relationships can have more than their neighbor. A new “me-first” culture is rising. But there still remains a highly structured society underneath. In many ways, Vietnam is perhaps both the most-collective and least-collective of the Asian cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese have been living with occupation, change and uncertainty for thousands of years and have developed community-based social systems that preserve order and personal freedom at a micro level, regardless of macro changes. As the local saying goes, “The rules of the village are stronger than the rules of the king.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike common misconceptions regarding Communist states, Vietnam is actually a democracy, and all citizens have the right to vote every three years. Although they can only choose candidates from one political party, within this party there are factions with very different viewpoints. Individuals have a lot of freedom in most areas of everyday life. Overall though, they tend to avoid openly discussing political issues. Speaking against the government, protesting high-level corruption, or promoting other political systems can incur severe punishments for locals and expulsion for foreigners.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is chaotic, but far from lawless. The country has an advanced legal system. But there are many ways in which rules can seem more like guidelines. A “no” can become a “yes” with the right timing and persuasion. This can seem daunting, but those who understand the system are great at navigating its complexities. This is one of the main reasons foreign business people need a trusted local partner or good lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreigners are surprised that sociopolitical tensions are actually highest with China, rather than the United States, France, or Japan.  Vietnam is increasingly wary of China’s growing power and territorial ambitions.  This has caused a strong wave of anti-China sentiment where Chinese products, particularly food, are considered poor quality and unhealthy. It has also driven a celebration of products “Made in Vietnam” and is combining with a growing awareness of health and safety to birth a clean-food movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing constant in Vietnam is change. Trends come and go, businesses open and close, and construction is a constant. The pervasive dust and noise are the sweat and tears of progress. But underneath this turmoil, there is a country that remains deeply Vietnamese, and people who are proud, ambitious, and happy to be open to a world of opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-VN-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Singapore</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/sg14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/sg14"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tell people I live in Singapore, the most common misunderstandings I hear are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How can you live in that sterile squeaky-clean police state?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Isn’t that where they cane people for chewing gum?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Disneyland with a death penalty! Haha!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What part of China is that in?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not surprised when people misunderstand Singapore, because it requires a little explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First - some important context:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore is an island so small you can drive around the whole country in two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1819, it was set up by the British as a tax-free trading port, instantly attracting business from the entire region.  So it’s always had a mix of Malay, Indian, and Chinese people, though the majority are Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It quickly became an anything-goes town, with opium, prostitution and gambling, run by secret societies.  Its nickname was “Sin-Galore”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1963, Singapore became a part of Malaysia.  But racial tensions between the Malay and Chinese populations led to ongoing race riots.  So in 1965, Singapore was kicked out of Malaysia, making it suddenly (and reluctantly) an independent country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Singapore had no natural resources, no local industry, and was geographically vulnerable, few people believed it would survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being a do-or-die survival situation, the government and people of Singapore got extremely focused, pragmatic, and competitive to do whatever it takes to make this tiny island thrive against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their main survival strategy was to focus on making Singapore an ideal place for big business — attracting multinational corporations to set up their Asian headquarters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these historical ingredients are important for the rest of this explanation to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why so clean?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Singapore is so small, keeping it clean is a manageable job.  (You can’t easily clean India or China.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really the cleanliness is marketing.  What better way to prove to multinational corporations that Singapore is a stable, trustable, and efficient place to set up your headquarters?  It’s no coincidence that the highway leading from the airport to downtown has the most perfectly manicured landscape.  First impressions matter to visiting CEOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why the country’s leaders all wear white.  It’s a show of incorruptibility — a metaphor for being orderly and transparent with attention to detail.  Getting to know Singapore’s government is like looking under the hood of a Ferrari.  It’s incredibly well-designed and well-run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore is always selling itself to the world.  The chairman of the government’s Economic Development Board told his colleagues, “We are in the hospitality business.”  The government works hard to stay competitive on every international measure.  Any time there are international rankings comparing countries, you’ll find Singapore near the top of the list.  Except for free speech, but I’ll cover that next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly: why no chewing gum?  Purely pragmatic.  It was gumming up the subway system, causing delays, and was too hard to clean off surfaces, so the sale of it was banned.  Keeping the country clean and running smoothly was more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s why Singapore has an international reputation for being so clean.  It’s brilliant marketing — visual proof of the order and cleanliness you can expect if you set up your business or banking here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why so strict?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three reasons: transformation, size, and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: transformation.  To quickly turn Singapore from “Sin-Galore” to being the Switzerland of Asia would require great strategy and strict, uncompromising execution of that strategy.  We’re used to seeing this in corporations, like Jack Welch at GE or Steve Jobs returning to Apple, but it’s surprising to see it carried out successfully in a government.  (Many say Singapore is more like a corporation than a country.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it worked!  In one generation, Singapore went through the most dramatic increase in the standard of living that the world has ever seen.  In one generation, this tiny dot went from being broke to being one of the richest countries in the world, without any natural resources, purely by strict execution of a great strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its lack of corruption was an important ingredient in its success.  In a region where political corruption is rampant, Singapore is the only country that severely punishes corruption.  It regularly ranks in the top 5 least corrupt countries in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next: size.  Singapore’s UN representative once said, “America is like an aircraft carrier.  If you jump up and down, it’s not going to shake.  Singapore is like a canoe.  If you jump up and down, it will sink.  If you lose stability in Singapore, you lose everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly: marketing.  When an American teenager vandalized 18 cars in Singapore, he was sentenced to jail and caning.  This turned into an international incident, with Bill Clinton asking Singapore not to prosecute him.  But as a government official said, “It was a way of demonstrating that Singapore was prepared to stand up against the mighty America.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, that’s brilliant marketing.  A memorable way for a country to prove to the world that they obey the rule of law, without exception, and don’t waive the laws for special requests from powerful people.  I think this kind of approach makes corporate leaders more likely to do their business and banking in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, you could argue that Singapore is not so strict — less strict than Switzerland or California — because it’s a &lt;em&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/em&gt; “do what you want” approach where life and business are not regulated for most of us in the middle.  Only the behavior that clearly hurts others or society is punished.  Everyone else gets to live in an incredibly safe, crime-and-corruption-free place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So very pragmatic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common thread behind everything here is pragmatism.  The country’s leadership consistently makes rational choices to improve the strength and profitability of Singapore.  It’s pragmatic, not dogmatic.  It’s not that the leaders of Singapore hate chewing gum or are neat freaks.  These were just rational decisions to do what was best for the country at that time.  The prime minister has a degree in Computer Science, as does the deputy prime minister.  This is a country run by engineers and economists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s important to know that these things are changing fast.  The government is constantly but conservatively re-assessing its stance on everything, to keep up with the times.  The last few years have seen a huge move towards more democracy and free speech, with the theater and arts scene blossoming because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore’s #1 enemy is complacency.  Now that Singapore is one of the most successful countries in the world, the top priority is to keep that competitive edge.  This “keep on your toes” message is constantly communicated at all levels — a reminder to never assume that things will stay this good.  Keep pushing.  Stay on top.  Don’t let your guard down.  Always be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore was founded on the ideals of the Age of Enlightenment — the age of reason and rationality — and its founder built those lofty ideals into its blueprint.  So to understand Singapore, you need to understand that it’s always been designed top-down, from the beginning, to realize these rational ideals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-SG-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Indonesia</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/id14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/id14"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danielziv"&gt;Daniel Ziv&lt;/a&gt;, who has worked in Indonesia for 14 years as a journalist, editor, and now filmmaker. He wrote the bestselling book “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/9799589878"&gt;Jakarta Inside Out&lt;/a&gt;” and directed the award-winning new documentary film &lt;a href="http://jalananmovie.com/"&gt;JALANAN&lt;/a&gt;, about the lives of three Jakarta street musicians.  This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia is the world’s 4th biggest country by population, but is still a work in progress - a beta version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia 1.0 began in 1945, when they gained independence from the Dutch and became a country.  Suddenly, 17,000 islands, 300 ethnic groups and 700 languages needed to be held together under one flag and one language.  These indigenous cultures were officially co-opted as caricatures rather than being allowed to grow organically.  The new official language was imposed very effectively at the expense of preserving local dialects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia 2.0 began in 1998, with the toppling of Suharto, the country’s dictator of 32 years. This new era of reform and democratization has seen impressive stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s talk about the best part of Indonesia - its people: warm, open-minded, easygoing and always lots of fun. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians are acrobats.  They’ve learned the hard way not to trust the system, but also to rarely challenge it. So they find resourceful ways of solving problems, relying on each other and adopting an optimistic, can-do attitude in any circumstance. Flexibility, elasticity and teamwork are key in nearly every walk of life, and Indonesians prize the following traits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-confrontation:&lt;/strong&gt; Indonesians put a premium on getting along and not making each other lose face. Confrontation is truly a last resort. Indonesians love group consensus as a solution to any debate. The outcome is not as important as the fact that the decision was arrived at inclusively.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patience:&lt;/strong&gt; A favorite Indonesian phrase is “jam karet”, which literally means “rubber time”, suggesting that time is a flexible, unpredictable commodity. It’s common for Indonesians to arrive an hour late to a meeting, and just as common for their colleagues to accept this as routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule-bending:&lt;/strong&gt; If time is rubber, so are rules, which are meant to be delightfully broken. Fees are waived, timetables sped up, and restrictions ignored, all for the right payment, family member, or childhood buddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-reliance:&lt;/strong&gt; In a society where very few people have health insurance, social security, or even life savings, mutual help is very common. If someone is very ill, the entire family and even neighbors pitch in to cover costs. If an uncle can’t afford his own motorbike, his son-in-law and two school friends will cover the down payment. If the government won’t fix an awful road, local residents mobilize their own resources to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians are fundamentally good, honest people born into a system that is utterly corrupt. So deeply rooted is the graft that just to get things done, one must either be corrupt or play along with corruption. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corruption is therefore a double-edged sword: it’s totally unjust and results in exorbitant costs, but it also allows people to get things done easily and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians resent paying huge bribes just to start up a small, legitimate business, yet love paying $25 to obtain an instant drivers license instead of the official $10 with its days of bureaucracy and road tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some cynically view low-level corruption as a tax system in a non-tax-paying society  Since the government cannot afford to pay police or teachers a livable wage, traffic cops demand petty bribes from drivers wanting to avoid hefty official fines, while teachers will accept payment to give students passing grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pleasure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you thought this is a conservative nation of Muslim puritans, think again. Indonesia is a surprisingly hedonistic society that could teach America a thing or two about the “pursuit of happiness” and pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians sometimes have it rough - with poverty, poor health, traffic jams, and pollution - but they constantly and unapologetically compensate themselves for these hardships. In Western countries, salons and spas are for the affluent, while in Indonesia even slum dwellers set aside the time (and as little as 50 cents) for a cream bath scalp massage or foot reflexology at a local spa shack. Infidelity, drugs and prostitution are rampant across all social classes in Indonesia.  Why?  Because people enjoy it, and deny themselves very little. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Religion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See all the young women wearing headscarves on the streets? Muslim extremists? Not even close. In fact many probably work as office girls for multinational companies and might even join colleagues at a karaoke lounge at night. Indonesia is a constant interplay between surface and substance, and nowhere is this more apparent than in the confusing, paradoxical attitude toward religion. The country is a cradle of “nominal Islam” – around 85% identify themselves as Muslims, yet very few are religious in the orthodox sense.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government dictates that every citizen must belong to one of the country’s six official religions, and this gets listed on every Indonesian’s ID card.  But for most Indonesians, religion is more of an identity label, security blanket or family tradition than a matter of orthodox belief or practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These official religious labels mask over society’s far deeper influences: pre-Islamic animist and Hindu roots, folk superstitions, and possibly more time spent worshiping English football matches or pop stars than praying in mosques or churches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Openness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians take humble pride in their own culture and achievements, but are incredibly open to outside influence. (Unlike the Thais, for example.) They are very welcoming and adaptive toward foreigners.  There’s no xenophobia here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the business world too: foreigners have been welcomed into many of Indonesia’s largest conglomerates as both senior directors and shareholders, while many have started major local companies of their own. This open-minded society has resulted in an open market full of opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This openness may explain why travel is booming.  Indonesians are increasingly traveling overseas, interacting more intensively with the world and global economy.  Indonesian expats are returning from years overseas to participate in the nation-building at home, becoming local entrepreneurs, academics, NGO types, lawyers, etc.  And Indonesians are suddenly eagerly touristing locally, discovering their own country in a way they never did before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future looks bright for Indonesia. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been three democratic, peaceful regime changes in the 15 years since the big reform, and no real fear that Indonesia will return to dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia is today the most democratic country in Southeast Asia, having surpassed more “progressive” neighbors like Thailand, the Philippines and Malaysia. (Just fifteen years ago, Indonesia would have trailed far behind.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite criticism of the current government - which in itself is a breath of fresh air - President Susilo Bambang Yudhoyono managed to steer the economy very skillfully, attracting huge foreign direct investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Indonesia, one must always look beyond the surface at the substance. It’s easy to be intimidated by corruption, traffic and pollution. But those frustrations are merely superficial distractions in a country that is unbelievably welcoming and more open for business than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-ID-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Japan</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/jp14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/jp14"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is adapted from an excerpt of the (great and highly recommended) book “&lt;a href="http://www.kirainet.com/english/a-geek-in-japan-the-book/#author"&gt;A Geek in Japan&lt;/a&gt;” by my hero &lt;a href="http://www.kirainet.com/english/"&gt;Héctor Garcia&lt;/a&gt;.  It is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If three Japanese people are talking together, and a fourth one joins the conversation, he will apologize upon approach for breaking the harmony of the group.  Why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In Japan, everything looks like it works to perfection.  People do what they’re supposed to.  Trains run well.  Everybody has a job.  Everybody has money to live.  It has one of the lowest crime rates in the world.  Children study well and are some of the best in the world.  Tokyo is one of the cleanest cities you’ll ever see despite being the largest urban area in the world.  It seems to be a perfect place.  How have they achieved this?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To understand the Japanese way, you must understand a few concepts that are deeply rooted into the culture.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Samurai role model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The samurai adhered to a way of life, ethics, rules, and a code that spread to all branches of society, and even today affects the way Japanese think.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buddhism taught them to stay calm and patient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucianism taught them that relationships between people are the basis of society - to respect our ancestors, relatives, and superiors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loyalty, justice, and honor are central.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sincerity, compassion, courtesy, and honesty are important key values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Though the samurai no longer exist, this way of viewing life is ever-present in society.  Students are loyal to their teachers.  Workers are loyal to their companies, putting in long overtime hours.  Japanese are loyal, honest, sincere, and disciplined at work.  They follow rules and try to improve themselves every day, just as the samurai did in their time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A high compliment is the word “iki” (粋).  You say a person is iki if they are original, calm, refined, and sophisticated, without being too perfect, complicated, or self-conscious.  It’s similar to the word “elegant” or “graceful”.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“Honne”, “tatemae”, and no “no”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Honne (本音) refers to the opinions and true feelings that everybody has.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Tatemae (建前) refers to social obligations, and opinions that have been adjusted to be socially acceptable - when words and true intentions don’t fully coincide.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What someone really thinks is “honne”, but what they actually express is “tatemae”.  In Western countries we could call it hypocrisy, but in Japan knowing how to express tatemae and honne at the right time is considered a virtue.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From the Western point of view, concealing the truth may be looked on with disfavor, but in Japan, preserving harmony is more important.  That’s why true thoughts (honne) are not expressed in a straightforward way, for fear of hurting people’s feelings.  It’s used to ease relationships and business, where established conventions have to be followed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Japanese hardly ever use the word “no”.  Using it is considered very curt.  Instead, there are many ways to say “no” delicately, such as, “A little bit…,” or “This is very interesting,” or “We will study your proposal,” or “This is complicated but…”  When someone says these things, they are very politely but clearly telling you “no”.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
An example: Imagine you want to buy a ticket and there are no seats left.  The ticket salesperson won’t give you a straight answer like, “There are no tickets left.”  Instead he will probably keep you waiting, pretending he is looking into something on his computer, make weird faces, and say something like, “Finding seats can be difficult.”  This is tatemae at its best.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Modesty and humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No matter what their social class, talent, studies, or job, Japanese people are expected to behave with modesty.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The most typical way to show our humility is by diminishing our own achievements while praising those of others.  If someone tells you that your recent work has been great, you must answer that the credit is not yours, that the latest successes have been achieved thanks to what your boss and company have taught you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If someone is too ambitious or flaunts their power too much, he ends up being ostracized by his company and society.  There are many cases where a person of great promise was too ambitious, and his/her superiors reassigned him/her to tasks such as serving tea in meetings or even cleaning the company bathrooms.  The Japanese see ambition as a threat to the inner balance of the system, which might bring them down in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The way of elegance and perfection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A deep-rooted Japanese concept is “do” (道), which means “the way”.  Look at many of the Japanese words we use in English.  “Judo” is the gentle way.  “Aikido” is the way of the union of spirit and mind.  “Dojo” is the place of the way.  There are hundreds of words with the character “do”, so it’s not merely a character but a whole philosophical concept and a way of life that has been deeply rooted in Japanese thinking for centuries.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here is one important application of this concept:  it is very common to seek perfection in some tasks as a means to acquire spiritual satisfaction.  Education is repetition, following the set path, “the way”.  Through repetition of certain patterns, they get to be very good at what they do.  But this also makes it very difficult for them to depart from their routine.  Now you can see why Japanese companies have a reputation for being slow to change and avoiding innovation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In individualistic societies (America, Europe, Australia, etc.), the common belief is that if you pursue your own self-interest this will automatically help with the interests of your society.  In Japan, the belief is reversed.  If you give your utmost in your work to serve your company, customers, and society, then this will automatically serve your own self-interest.  This is why Japanese companies are known for having such incredible customer service.  This helps you have a better life, and in turn you help others have a better life, while benefitting companies and the Japanese economy in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-JP-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Same word. Different places? Different meanings.</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/quality</id>
    <updated>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/quality"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I had just moved to Singapore when I met the brilliant &lt;a href="http://www.plus8star.com/"&gt;Benjamin Joffe&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/benjaminjoffe"&gt;@benjaminjoffe&lt;/a&gt;) - a startup consultant and investor from France, who has spent the last 13 years living around Asia: a few years each in &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I asked him if he could tell me the most important thing he learned from living in these different countries.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He said, “&lt;strong&gt;Even though we are all using English as a common language, the same word can mean very different things in different places&lt;/strong&gt;.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I looked confused, so he said, “&lt;strong&gt;When I say the word ‘quality’, what do you think it means?&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I thought and said, “Quality means &lt;strong&gt;it works&lt;/strong&gt;.  It’s well-built.  It will last.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He beamed a big smile and said, “Exactly!  I knew you were going to say that, because you’re American!  If you ask almost any American what ‘quality’ means, they’ll say ‘it works’.  To you, that’s the definition of the word, but it’s actually just the American definition of the word.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“In &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;, if I ask almost anyone what quality means, they’ll say, ‘&lt;strong&gt;it’s brand new&lt;/strong&gt;’.  In Korea, newness is important.  Don’t go to Korea trying to emphasize the timeless long-lasting quality of your product.  What matters is what’s new.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“In &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;, if I ask almost anyone what quality means, they’ll say, ‘&lt;strong&gt;it’s perfect - zero defects&lt;/strong&gt;’.  Japanese culture emphasizes the importance of striving for perfection.  I saw a company ship a huge box of their products to Japan, but the shipment was not accepted because the shipping container was dented.  Although the items inside were fine, it was no longer a ‘quality’ shipment, since it was no longer perfect.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“In &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, if I ask almost anyone what quality means, they’ll say, ‘&lt;strong&gt;it gives status&lt;/strong&gt;’.  &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guanxi"&gt;Guanxi&lt;/a&gt; is everything - your standing in a personal network - so any item that gives you social status is considered quality.  It doesn’t matter if it’s well-built or will last, as long as it raises your social status.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He waited while I digested this thought.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then he said, “This is why you can’t just take your brilliant American business idea and go make it happen in any country.  ‘Quality’ is just one word, but imagine the different cultural meanings of words like ‘music’, ‘romantic’, ‘friends’, or even ‘fun’!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;This conversation is a big reason I started my &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;Wood Egg book series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;  Understanding the different mindsets of different cultures has interested me ever since, so it’s fun to keep diving deeper and deeper into the subject.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Later, I asked a Singaporean friend why high-tech always-online &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt; has almost no online shopping.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He said, “Shopping is something you go out and do with your friends!  A few companies have tried to popularize online shopping in Singapore, but it has never worked.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I explained how it would save people a lot of time and money to being able to buy anything at home, without having to go out to the mall, he smiled and said, “What if I came to America and tried to start a company that helped people stay at home and get drunk alone, while sitting at their computer, so that they didn’t need to go out to bars with friends anymore?  Wouldn’t that save them a lot of time and money?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Touché.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Click any book cover, below, to jump to the page for it.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh" title="Cambodia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-KH-200.jpg" alt="Cambodia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn" title="China 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-CN-200.jpg" alt="China 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk" title="Hong Kong 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-HK-200.jpg" alt="Hong Kong 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in" title="India 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-IN-200.jpg" alt="India 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id" title="Indonesia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-ID-200.jpg" alt="Indonesia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp" title="Japan 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-JP-200.jpg" alt="Japan 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr" title="Korea 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-KR-200.jpg" alt="Korea 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my" title="Malaysia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MY-200.jpg" alt="Malaysia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn" title="Mongolia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MN-200.jpg" alt="Mongolia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm" title="Myanmar 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MM-200.jpg" alt="Myanmar 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph" title="Philippines 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-PH-200.jpg" alt="Philippines 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg" title="Singapore 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-SG-200.jpg" alt="Singapore 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk" title="Sri Lanka 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-LK-200.jpg" alt="Sri Lanka 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw" title="Taiwan 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-TW-200.jpg" alt="Taiwan 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th" title="Thailand 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-TH-200.jpg" alt="Thailand 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn" title="Vietnam 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-VN-200.jpg" alt="Vietnam 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/aa" title="Asia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-AA-200.jpg" alt="Asia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wood Egg 2014 books are on sale now</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/we14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/we14"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
If you know you’ll never go to Asia, you can skip this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re looking for a travel guide, you can skip this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you might do business in Asia, have thought about moving to Asia, or just want to understand the cultures of Asia, you will love this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They’re all &lt;strong&gt;ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Plus this year there’s &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/aa"&gt;a 17th book, combining all 16 books into one massive 4448-page ebook&lt;/a&gt;, for easy comparison between different countries.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please &lt;strong&gt;go to &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;woodegg.com&lt;/a&gt; to check them out now.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These 2014 editions were &lt;strong&gt;all written in the last three months, based on research from the last six months.&lt;/strong&gt;  They’re the most current and thorough guides of their kind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The 2013 editions were OK, but I never promoted them because I wanted them to be deeper, more thorough, and more insightful.  But these 2014 editions were created by some amazing researchers and writers, so I can now proudly say these books are really very good.  (I’ll save the superlatives for future editions, since we’ll be re-writing them every year - an annual improvement process.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ll have more to say about them in the coming weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But for now, I just want to say &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;they’re here&lt;/a&gt;.  Two years of effort by over 140 people.  I’m so thrilled, and honestly a little in awe of what we’ve created.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I hope you &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;buy one&lt;/a&gt;, and hope you like it. &lt;strong&gt;Click any book cover, below, to jump to the page for it.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh" title="Cambodia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-KH-200.jpg" alt="Cambodia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn" title="China 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-CN-200.jpg" alt="China 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk" title="Hong Kong 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-HK-200.jpg" alt="Hong Kong 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in" title="India 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-IN-200.jpg" alt="India 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id" title="Indonesia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-ID-200.jpg" alt="Indonesia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp" title="Japan 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-JP-200.jpg" alt="Japan 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr" title="Korea 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-KR-200.jpg" alt="Korea 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my" title="Malaysia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MY-200.jpg" alt="Malaysia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn" title="Mongolia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MN-200.jpg" alt="Mongolia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm" title="Myanmar 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-MM-200.jpg" alt="Myanmar 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph" title="Philippines 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-PH-200.jpg" alt="Philippines 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg" title="Singapore 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-SG-200.jpg" alt="Singapore 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk" title="Sri Lanka 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-LK-200.jpg" alt="Sri Lanka 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw" title="Taiwan 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-TW-200.jpg" alt="Taiwan 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th" title="Thailand 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-TH-200.jpg" alt="Thailand 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn" title="Vietnam 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-VN-200.jpg" alt="Vietnam 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/aa" title="Asia 2014"&gt;&lt;img src="http://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-AA-200.jpg" alt="Asia 2014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jac Holzman</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/jac</id>
    <updated>2013-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/jac"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I met Jac Holzman the same day I met Bill Gates, but Jac made a much bigger impression, and he’s been my friend and mentor ever since.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Jac Holzman is a living legend.
He founded &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elektra_Records"&gt;Elektra Records&lt;/a&gt; in 1950.
(Yeah! 1950! Let that soak in a minute. That’s years before rock music was even invented!)
He signed artists like The Doors, Carly Simon, Harry Chapin, and Judy Collins to their first record deal.
In 1964, he founded the amazing &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonesuch_Records"&gt;Nonesuch Records&lt;/a&gt;, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He’s done a lot more than that, so you can &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jac_Holzman"&gt;read his Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt; for more.
He was inducted into the Rock &amp;amp; Roll Hall of Fame, so &lt;a href="http://www.rockhall.com/inductees/jac-holzman/bio/"&gt;there’s a good biography of him on their site&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
About 10 years ago, a mutual friend (the brilliant &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_L._Nash"&gt;Michael Nash&lt;/a&gt;) said Jac wanted to meet me, so we set a lunch date a couple weeks in advance, because I wanted to read his autobiography first.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was deep in the middle of running CD Baby.
Business was booming almost out of control.
It was a little lonely, because all my friends are musicians but the stuff I was going through — trying to lead a company of 85 employees and thousands of clients — was something that none of my friends could relate to.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But when I read Jac’s book, &lt;strong&gt;it was like I had been walking a mountain path alone, then came upon a cabin with the diaries of someone who had walked that track 50 years earlier.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everything I was going through, he had gone through 50 years ago.
Keeping musicians happy, managing crazy employees, satisfying the needs of music lovers, navigating a booming music business — I thought it was just me, but nope.
Jac had been there and done that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The book is called “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0966122100?tag=sivers-20"&gt;Follow the Music: The Life and High Times of Elektra Records in the Great Years of American Pop Culture&lt;/a&gt;.”
I spent 16 kindred hours in his head, reading that 400 page book, before we finally met.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was nervous before our lunch.
I expected him to be aloof on a pedestal, while I fawned over him in awe.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Instead, he bounded up to me, warm as can be, giving me a big hug, saying he was so honored to meet me, and had been looking forward to our lunch for weeks.
To this day, I think it’s one of the warmest greetings I’ve ever had from anyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We talked for hours about music, and had lots of questions for each other. 
It was awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Jac has these enormous blue eyes.
It’s amazing to think about what his eyes have seen.
Not just Jim Morrison showing up drunk on his doorstep and all of that.
&lt;strong&gt;This world of modern music that has been my whole life — Jac was right there in the middle of the creation of it.
The stories and the characters are mythical legends to me, but recent memories to him.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He’s a real music and audio afficianado.
He always puts the music and musicians first, whether it later made money or not.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He has this great story about needing to get the Beatles’ permission to license something from them in the 60s.
He met with them and asked.
George said, “Elektra Records? Didn’t you put out &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koerner,_Ray_%26_Glover"&gt;Koerner, Ray &amp;amp; Glover&lt;/a&gt;?”
When Jac said yes, John said, “Anyone who puts out Koerner, Ray &amp;amp; Glover is OK by us,” and gave his OK.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He later told me that it was actually a long-term strategy of Elektra.
That sometimes he’d release records by amazing artists, knowing they’d probably lose money, because not only was it the right thing to do, but other successful artists would later choose to sign with Elektra instead of another label, because he had proven that Elektra would support their artistic exploration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href="/jac#ps"&gt;See my P.S.&lt;/a&gt;, below.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I look up to him so much that when he tells me to do something, I do it.
He’s the one that told me to go to New Zealand, the first time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He tried to get CD Baby to work with Warner Music at one point, which was a nice gesture, though not the best fit.
Still it led to some priceless moments like sitting around the pool at the Beverly Hills Hotel, talking with a shirtless &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyor_Cohen"&gt;Lyor Cohen&lt;/a&gt;, smoking a cigar.
(No, he didn’t use a hundred dollar bill to light it.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Jac is such a perfectionist, always insisting that everything is the best possible quality it can be.
From his early hands-on audio recordings in the early 1950s — bringing his equipment on his back on his Vespa, recording in musicians’ apartments — to 2013 when he just spent countless hours making &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-doors/id609344635?mt=8"&gt;The Doors iPad app&lt;/a&gt;.
(It’s an incredible labor of love.  If you have an iPad, absolutely &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-doors/id609344635?mt=8"&gt;buy The Doors app now&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Clearly, we hit it off so well that we made a point of meeting up every month or so after that.
He’s an avid hiker, so many times we’d go on long hikes up the hills of Los Angeles.
He was impressed I could keep up with him.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There’s no conclusion to this story.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I called Jac just now while writing this article, and he wanted to hear all about how my wife and baby are doing.
Warm as always.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ever the perfectionist, he said I should sit on this article for a few weeks, and have a few editors read it, but for once I’m going to disagree.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Go &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0966122100?tag=sivers-20"&gt;get his autobiography of the Elektra years&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=jac+holzman"&gt;search YouTube for Jac Holzman&lt;/a&gt; to see some great interviews and such.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/JacHolzman-600x300.jpg" width="600" height="300" alt="Jac Holzman photo"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Jac Holzman then and now. Both at home with a microphone.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/JacHolzman-600x359.jpg" width="600" height="359" alt="Jac Holzman photo"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id="ps"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;P.S.  One more story:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I was 16, I heard this album called “&lt;a href="http://www.nonesuch.com/albums/bali-music-from-the-morning-of-the-world"&gt;Music From the Morning of the World&lt;/a&gt;”.
It blew my mind.
It changed my life.
I listened to that album over and over again all year, and a hundred times since.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because of that album, I got interested in Asia in general, and Bali in particular.
I swear it’s to blame for a lot of my life’s journeys.
So &lt;strong&gt;24 years after hearing that album, I finally booked my flight to Bali.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The night before I left, Jac called out of the blue to say hi, and ask what I was doing.
I said I was packing to go to Bali, and how it’s something I’ve always wanted to do, since I was 16 and heard this record…
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I stopped.
Wait.
Wasn’t that album on Nonesuch Records?
Yes! It was!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I said, “Jac! &lt;strong&gt;I’m going to Bali because of YOU!&lt;/strong&gt; Because of the obscure record of Balinese Gamelan music you put out in 1967, I moved to Asia, and now I’m about to go to Bali for the first time because of you!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ah, the loops and circles of life.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why am I here?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/here</id>
    <updated>2013-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/here"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Looking around the room.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“Why am I here?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s a useful question to ask often.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Either it will &lt;strong&gt;re-focus&lt;/strong&gt; your reasons for being where you are, or it will make you realize your reasons have &lt;strong&gt;expired&lt;/strong&gt; and you should be somewhere else.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a little apartment in Singapore, I ask it again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“Why am I here?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because of the brilliant and fascinating people here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(But I’m refusing all requests to meet, to stay focused on my work.  For the past 3 years I was very social, but now I’m not.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because I love learning about Asia, and Singapore is a great central home base for that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(But I’m not exploring Asia right now.  For the past 3 years I was, but now I’m inwardly-focused on my writing and programming.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because I love and admire it, and it feels like home.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(But I’ve loved everywhere I’ve lived, from California to New York to London to Portland.  They’ve all felt like home.  Future places will feel like home, too.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because I’m here right now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(But there are airplanes.  You can sit in them.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Most of us are where we are because of decisions we made years ago.  But are those reasons still current for what we need now?  Ask again.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“Why am I here?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Damn.  I ran out of reasons.  I should be somewhere else.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I want silence, solitude, and wide open spaces.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I want to work all day while listening to nothing but birds and wind in the trees.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I want an intentional lack of distractions, far far away, to cure my tendency to say yes to intellectually stimulating events.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So the answer was clear.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I moved to New Zealand’s South Island.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.newzealand.com/int/nelson/"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; I am.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“Why am I here?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To work.  To focus.  To write.  To code.  To launch.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes. Good answer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuckincustoms/7960290272/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/milford.jpg" width="680" height="617" alt="New Zealand photo"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="small"&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuckincustoms/7960290272/"&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt; by Trey Ratcliff)&lt;/span&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why my code and ideas are public</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/ws</id>
    <updated>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/ws"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Over dinner my friend Valerie said, “I’m not worried about someone finding out my secrets, because secrets are just facts, right?  So if someone is going through my private things, for example, and gets upset about what they find, then that’s their problem, not mine!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I liked that attitude, and kept thinking about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Later as we were leaving, I helped her put on her coat, and picked up her purse.  It was so heavy, I had to ask, “What’s in here?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She said, “Oh probably my two big diaries.  I have one diary that’s private, and another that’s like super-super private.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because of what she just said about secrets, I had to ask: “Can I read the super-super private one, then?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She was a little shocked, thought for a few seconds, laughed, and said OK.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We got two ciders and she patiently waited while I spent 20 minutes reading through it.  Pages filled with words about processing family drama, formulating goals, plans for life changes, romantic details, lists of regrets, contemplations, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was surprised &lt;strong&gt;it was all meaningless to me&lt;/strong&gt;.  These pages meant the world to her, but to me they meant no more than any non-secret conversation we’d ever had.  It was the same stuff that we all think.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Later, I thought about the stuff I keep secret.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like my programming code, for example.  I had it locked in an SSH-only server, on an encrypted partition.  My current life’s work.  Super-super private.  Can’t let anyone get access to this!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But what did I think would really happen if someone read my code?  They’d steal it and thrive?  &lt;a href="/multiply"&gt;Really?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I realized it’s like Valerie’s diary.  Meaningful to me.  Meaningless to others.  So why go to the trouble to keep it so secret?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(I realize there’s an argument on the other side.  Why go to the trouble to make it public?)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But life is an ongoing experiment, so &lt;strong&gt;I decided to make all my programming code and business ideas public and open source&lt;/strong&gt;, just to see what happens.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wanted to &lt;strong&gt;challenge that fear that someone is going to steal our ideas&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Actually all those business ideas have been posted freely on my site for over two years now, and nobody has “stolen” them, yet.  You’re welcome to try.  I’ll keep adding more.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everything is listed at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/projects"&gt;http://sivers.org/projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  Enjoy!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;P.S. I never said everything should be public.  I only said I’m making my code and ideas public.  That’s all.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is not about what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; should make public or keep secret.  Everyone has different criteria.  It’s worth re-evaluating the choices you’ve made, to see if they’re still applicable to you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/diary.jpg" width="500" height="611" alt=""&gt;&lt;p class="small"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/insomnia90/3875374318/"&gt;Silvia Viñuales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OK, Milt Olin, I’ll start writing again</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/milt</id>
    <updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/milt"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Last night I spent far too much time tinkering with setting up both the &lt;a href="http://www.freebsd.org/"&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.openbsd.org/"&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; operating systems to dual-boot on my laptop.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This morning I found out one of my best friends died yesterday.  He was in great health, was out on a bike ride on a quiet street, and a car swerved into the bike lane, &lt;a href="http://losangeles.cbslocal.com/2013/12/08/bicyclist-struck-and-killed-by-sheriffs-radio-car-in-calabasas/"&gt;killing him instantly&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I let him share my online music account.  He had just downloaded the entire Bruce Springsteen and Neil Young catalog yesterday before he left on his ride.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ve been crying off and on all morning, thinking about the things we do with our time.  What’s worthy and what’s a waste.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It really is limited.  We can’t pretend it’s not.  Time spent doing one thing is time spent not doing something else.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s so easy to waste time doing that stuff that’s of no importance, no challenge, no benefit to anyone, not even yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s so hard to fight the &lt;a href="/book/WarOfArt"&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt; to do the more difficult but more important thing.  Finishing that book.  Writing that song.  Launching that project.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I spent this morning thinking about what doesn’t matter (like dual-booting FreeBSD and OpenBSD) and what does.  For me, &lt;strong&gt;writing&lt;/strong&gt; is about the most worthy thing I can do with my time.  I love how the distributed word is eternal - that every day I get emails from strangers thanking me for things I wrote years ago that helped them today.  I love how those things will continue to help people long after I’m gone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So this lesson is dedicated to you, Milt.  I’m going to start writing again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/miltolin.jpg" width="315" height="199" alt="Milt Olin Twitter page"&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fragile Plan vs Robust Plan</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/robust</id>
    <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/robust"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
When I &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/eg"&gt;first had the idea for Wood Egg&lt;/a&gt; - publishing 16 books about 16 countries every year - I thought I would write them all &lt;strong&gt;myself&lt;/strong&gt;.  Visit 16 countries for 3 weeks each, doing intensive research the whole time.  That’s 48 weeks, so I could do it again each year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But I had a baby on the way, so that idea lasted about a minute.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I thought of &lt;strong&gt;a journalist&lt;/strong&gt; I know who would love that kind of life.  I asked, she said yes, she flew to Singapore, and started working.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But it was a really bad fit, so after five weeks, we called it quits.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I decided to hire &lt;strong&gt;one writer per-country&lt;/strong&gt;.  16 authors to write 16 books.  This went OK at first.  &lt;a href="http://mohitpawar.com/about/"&gt;Mohit Pawar&lt;/a&gt; did a great job with India, and &lt;a href="http://www.cameronkeng.com/about/"&gt;Cameron Keng&lt;/a&gt; did a great job with Taiwan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But the people I hired for the other countries flaked out, so I realized this plan was still too fragile.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Making a Robust Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I really wanted this to work.  I had to be smart.  I had to make a better plan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I re-read my notes on &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/EMythRevisited"&gt;E-Myth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/WisdomOfCrowds"&gt;The Wisdom of Crowds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/Crowdsourcing"&gt;Crowdsourcing&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/HereComesEverybody"&gt;Here Comes Everybody&lt;/a&gt;.  (In fact, I re-read &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book"&gt;my notes on ALL 130 books&lt;/a&gt;. It was an enlightening week.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I learned a few things:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want help, it helps to get specific.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A plan that’s too dependent on any one person is too fragile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting Specific:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before, I had a very vague outline of what I wanted the book to cover.  I asked the authors to include sections on culture, government, business setup, hiring, banking, and marketing.  That was it.  The details were up to them.  Go!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In hindsight, I can see how daunting it was.  Too wide open.  I’ve written about the need to get specific before - (see “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/get-specific"&gt;Get specific&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/restrictions-will-set-you-free"&gt;Restrictions will set you free&lt;/a&gt;”) - but I had forgotten to apply it to this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I spent a couple weeks and &lt;strong&gt;came up with &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in#toc"&gt;200 specific questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  Now, to write the book, we just had to answer those 200 questions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s infinitely easier to find someone to answer a specific question than to find someone to impart wisdom on a vague topic.  It &lt;strong&gt;puts the burden on the asker&lt;/strong&gt;, to come up with a good question, and &lt;strong&gt;lifts the burden from the answerer.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Multiple People:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So that the book was not dependent on any one person, and the book was not one person’s opinion, I made a system where each of those 200 questions had to be &lt;strong&gt;answered by three different people&lt;/strong&gt;.  Ideally, one local, one foreigner, and one other.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
16 countries × 3 researchers = 48 people.  I used &lt;a href="https://www.elance.com/"&gt;Elance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.odesk.com/"&gt;oDesk&lt;/a&gt; to find people in each country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course, some disappeared, some never finished, and a few gave bad answers, but that was OK.  Life happens. People’s circumstances change. I understand. But it won’t hurt my plan.  If any one person is gone, I can still carry on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When all 200 questions had 3 answers each, (16 × 200 × 3 = 9600 answers), I hired a few writer/editors to combine the answers into one essay per question.  Again, one person disappeared, but it was easy for another to step in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And that was the robust plan that got it &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;done&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(Note: I was also visiting every country myself, and contributing my own research to the books. But it was important that the plan didn’t require me, either.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you’re starting a project or company:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t expect anyone to care as much as you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t require them to think as hard about this as you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do expect them to change their mind and disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a robust plan that includes #1-3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;As the founder, the burden is on you to come up with a great plan, to lift the burden from the people helping you.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then, when you find some &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/Linchpin"&gt;brilliant people&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a great bonus, instead of an absolute necessity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/table-many-legs.jpg" width="543" height="343"&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wood Egg (my new company)</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/eg</id>
    <updated>2013-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/eg"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Like everyone, I can get deeply curious about something, and dive in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Starting five years ago, I got deeply curious about the differences between countries and cultures, fascinated with understanding the different perspectives. I talked about a few fun ones in &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_weird_or_just_different.html"&gt;this 2-minute TED talk&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So two years ago, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/singapore"&gt;I moved to Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, and started visiting all the countries in Asia, asking dumb questions, making good friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Getting to know these countries is endlessly interesting.  I want to understand them as well as I understand the 50 U.S. states.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But my learning felt too unstructured.  So while walking around Yogyakarta, Indonesia, remembering “&lt;strong&gt;the best way to learn something is to teach it&lt;/strong&gt;”, I came up with an ambitious plan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I decided to produce and publish &lt;strong&gt;16 books per year on 16 countries in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: Cambodia, China, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Japan, Korea, Malaysia, Mongolia, Myanmar, Philippines, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Taiwan, Thailand, and Vietnam. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sure, they wouldn’t be great at first, but I committed to &lt;strong&gt;improving them every year for many years&lt;/strong&gt;.  After a few years of doing this, they should be pretty awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Instead of being all-encompassing, I decided to focus just on entrepreneurship: a network I was already tapped into, a good filter for understanding a country’s culture, and a subject that may be useful to others.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What to name it?  That only took a minute.  I like &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2003/06/naming_a_busine.html"&gt;Seth Godin’s advice about naming&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;ntrepreneur’s &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;uide?  E… G…  Egg!  Golden Egg?  Too cliché.  &lt;strong&gt;Wood Egg?&lt;/strong&gt;  Yep!  Sounds like an exotic carved Thai or Indonesian treasure.  Good enough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I set up a Singapore corporation for it from my Yogyakarta hotel room that night in August 2011, and began the next day.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And now, &lt;strong&gt;after a year and a half of work&lt;/strong&gt; - (and some hard lessons learned that I’ll write about soon) - &lt;strong&gt;they’re done!  So my new company is launched:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;Wood Egg - the entrepeneur’s guides to Asia&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;woodegg.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please check it out.  And if you’re also interested in this subject, &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/help"&gt;see the help wanted page&lt;/a&gt;, because I’m starting on the 2014 guides immediately.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center" style="background-color: #000"&gt;&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wood-egg-450-450.jpg" width="450" height="450" alt="wood egg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Some will always say you're wrong</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/wrong</id>
    <updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/wrong"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Some people are into money.  Some aren’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some people are inspired by helping the needy.  Some aren’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some are into fame, power, and prestige.  Others are into anonymity and freedom from responsibility.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It gets more interesting when you realize people have different preferences in the different parts of their life.  Famous online, but anonymous in their local community.  Generous with time, stingy with money.  Introvert when working, extrovert when not.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/grade"&gt;know your preferences well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, because &lt;strong&gt;no matter what you do, someone will tell you you’re wrong&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into money, many people will say you’re foolish.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into charity, many people will say you’re greedy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into crowds, many people will say you’re missing out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some careers come with excuses:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The classic novelist thrives in solitude.  Alone in a cabin in the woods, writing books that reach millions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The classic journalist thrives in a crowd.  Talking with everyone, building the story from a thousand accounts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The shy librarian.  The aggressive lawyer.  The flaky artist.  No explanation needed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;But some careers need explanations when you go against the mold:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The entrepreneur who’s not into money.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The musician who avoids crowds.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The ambitious conservationist.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The artist into discpline.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/HowToGetRich"&gt;rich poet&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you &lt;strong&gt;expect this criticism in advance&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;take pride in your stance&lt;/strong&gt;, you can bash on with a smile, being who you want to be.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then every time they say you’re wrong, that’s a sign you’re doing it right.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/HermitCrab.jpg" width="600" height="392"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(image by &lt;a href="http://www.finland.org/public/default.aspx?contentid=181860&amp;nodeid=35833"&gt;Alex Marttunen&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>No rules in this game</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/360</id>
    <updated>2013-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/360"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Everyone thinks you have to move to the big music cities. But Mihkel Raud in Estonia sold thousands of albums, 100% independent, without leaving Estonia. &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00007MB39"&gt;Rondellus Sabbatum&lt;/a&gt; was an album so unique that word-of-mouth sold thousands, with hardly any promotion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everyone says you need to make your music appeal to the masses. But Regina Spektor proved that emphasizing your quirks gets you further. &lt;a href="http://www.cdbaby.com/artist/ReginaSpektor"&gt;Listen to her early albums from 2001 and 2002&lt;/a&gt;. She was being more mainstream fit-the-mold piano vocal. But the weirder she got with &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ycum4o6jlzQ"&gt;Soviet Kitsch&lt;/a&gt;, the more remarkable and noteworthy she became, and that’s when her career really took off.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everyone is worried about piracy, copyright, and trademark. But &lt;a href="http://www.jonathancoulton.com/"&gt;Jonathan Coulton&lt;/a&gt; writes a song a day, gives most away, and is one of the most successful independent artists today. By making more and more music, and letting it flow, his music has gotten into unusual places like webcomics, audiobooks, comedy shows, and others’ YouTube videos. He disclosed that he makes about $500,000 a year by licensing, touring, donations, and people choosing to buy his music from his site, even though they could get it for free.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because the music business is mostly perception, and minds are irrational, you can really have some fun with the counter-intuitive pop-psychology of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to win fans is to target a sharp niche - to &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/proudly-exclude-most"&gt;proudly exclude&lt;/a&gt; 99% of the public. So the way to win fans is to exclude almost everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to get funding is to act as if you’ll never get funding - to make &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/good-biz-plan"&gt;a plan that doesn’t need it&lt;/a&gt;. So the way to get funding is to ignore funding.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to have a serious career in music is to take nothing seriously. Do the opposite of other musicians. Make up your own game.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Gurus will say what you must do or can’t do. They mean well, but they’re wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For every rule they tell you, there’s an exception. &lt;strong&gt;They are just telling you their specific past, not your specific future.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are no rules in this game. You change them as you go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was my contribution to Andrew Dubber’s great book, “&lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/360deal"&gt;The 360 Deal: A collection of genuinely helpful advice for people starting out in the music industry&lt;/a&gt;”. You should buy it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/bloodyclown.jpg" width="600" height="521"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zickie/4025087286/"&gt;zickie&lt;/a&gt;. (Sorry I couldn't find a free &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes#Calvinball"&gt;Calvinball&lt;/a&gt; image.)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Seeking inspiration?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/io</id>
    <updated>2013-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/io"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
The word “inspiration” usually means something that mentally stimulates you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But “inspiration” also means to &lt;a href="http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/inspiration"&gt;breathe in&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The meanings poetically combine when you think of yourself breathing in thoughts, filling your body with ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But don’t forget to breathe out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some people watch hundreds of &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/speakers/derek_sivers.html"&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;, looking for inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Tech entrepreneurs visit &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; every few hours, looking for new inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Musicians, writers, artists, and everyone else, all scouring the world for inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Breathing in, and in, and in, and in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yet most of them aren’t feeling inspired enough.  They’re looking for more, thinking something else out there will truly inspire them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Want to know why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Because nothing is truly inspiring unless you apply it to your work.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;em&gt;(“work” meaning your life’s output, whether creative, business, or personal.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In other words, &lt;strong&gt;your work, itself, is the inspiration.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You may hear something or see something that gives you a new idea.But it’s only when you stop and think of your work through this new perspective, that you actually &lt;strong&gt;jump up and go turn the idea into reality.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;That’s the real inspiration that everyone is looking for!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The inspiration is not the receiving of information.  The inspiration is &lt;strong&gt;applying&lt;/strong&gt; what you’ve received.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
People think that if they keep reading articles, browsing books, listening to talks, or meeting people, that they’re going to suddenly get inspired.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;constantly seeking inspiration is anti-inspiring.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have to pause the input, and focus on your output.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For every bit of inspiration, use it and amplify it by applying it to your work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then you’ll finally feel the inspiration you’ve been looking for.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Breathe in. Breathe out. Breathe in. Breathe out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/handwriting.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/beth19/4866638272/"&gt;bethan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Great Movies</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/ebert2</id>
    <updated>2013-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/ebert2"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
A friend I hadn’t heard from in years called me out of the blue yesterday, and just said, “Dude... did you hear?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I went home and before she even saw me, my wife asked from the next room, “Babe... I heard the news. Are you OK?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They all know I’m a fan of &lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/"&gt;Roger Ebert&lt;/a&gt;. He died yesterday.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was also a massive James Brown fan, but I wasn’t as affected when he died, because it’s not like I was tuning in weekly to hear what new music he was making.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But Ebert... ooof....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every Friday since 1994 (yes 1994), I’d go to rogerebert.suntimes.com to read his new in-depth film reviews. I feel like I’ve been in his part-time film school class for the last 19 years. My life is so much richer from it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is going to be a hard habit to break.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every time we’d watch a movie, I’d go back and read Ebert’s essay on it, to get a different perspective. My wife would joke, after the credits rolled, “OK, now go find out what Ebert said about it. I know you want to. I’ll wait.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“The Great Movies” was his collection of films he felt were the best. Years after his initial review, he’d go back and watch it at least once more, then write a deeper essay about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A few years ago, I subscribed to Netflix and put all 300-or-so of “The Great Movies” in my queue.  We’d watch one or two a week, not reading his essay until afterwards.  I've seen most but not all of them now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A hidden world opens up to you when you dive deep into an art form.  Years of studying jazz at Berklee School of Music opened up that world to me.  Art is so much deeper when you get the contexts and references.  Ebert single-handedly did that for me for movies.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Someone recently &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/cekj0/roger_ebert/"&gt;asked him&lt;/a&gt;, “Do you think a more innocent viewpoint, not marred by technical knowledge, leads to a more ‘pure’ watching experience - the emotional elements without being distracted by technicalities?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He answered, “The more movies you see and write about, the more you know about them. Consider baseball. The ‘innocent’ crowd member sees a bunch of guys running after a little ball while wearing funny costumes. The Cubs fan sees inevitable tragedy unfolding.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, yeah.  I recommend you watch as many of these movies and read as many of these 364 essays as you can.  Especially the ones you think you’d be least likely to enjoy.  I’ll keep the links here permanently.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Roger Ebert’s “The Great Movies” essays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-12-angry-men-1957"&gt;12 Angry Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ace-in-the-hole-1951"&gt;Ace in the Hole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-adaptation-2002"&gt;Adaptation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-adventures-of-robin-hood-1938"&gt;The Adventures of Robin Hood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-after-dark-my-sweet-1990"&gt;After Dark, My Sweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/after-hours-1985-1"&gt;After Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-age-of-innocence-1993"&gt;The Age of Innocence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-aguirre-the-wrath-of-god-1972"&gt;Aguirre, the Wrath of God&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ai-artificial-intelligence-2001"&gt;A.I. Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ali-fear-eats-the-soul-1974"&gt;Ali: Fear Eats the Soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-alien-1979"&gt;Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-all-about-eve-1950"&gt;All About Eve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-amadeus-1984"&gt;Amadeus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-amarcord-1974"&gt;Amarcord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-annie-hall-1977"&gt;Annie Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-apartment-1960"&gt;The Apartment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-apocalypse-now-1979"&gt;Apocalypse Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-apu-trilogy-1959"&gt;The Apu Trilogy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-army-of-shadows-1969"&gt;Army of Shadows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-atlantic-city-1980"&gt;Atlantic City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-au-hasard-balthazar-1966"&gt;Au Hasard Balthazar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-au-revoir-les-enfants-1987"&gt;Au Revoir, les Enfants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-an-autumn-afternoon-1962"&gt;An Autumn Afternoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/babel-2006"&gt;Babel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-badlands-1973"&gt;Badlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-ballad-of-narayama-1958"&gt;The Ballad of Narayama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-band-wagon-1953"&gt;The Band Wagon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bank-dick-1940"&gt;The Bank Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-baraka-1992"&gt;Baraka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/barry-lyndon-1975"&gt;Barry Lyndon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-battle-of-algiers-1967"&gt;The Battle of Algiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-battleship-potemkin-1925"&gt;The Battleship Potemkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-beat-the-devil-1954"&gt;Beat the Devil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-beauty-and-the-beast-1946"&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-being-there-1979"&gt;Being There&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-belle-de-jour-1967"&gt;Belle de Jour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/la-belle-noiseuse-1991"&gt;La Belle Noiseuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-best-years-of-our-lives-1946"&gt;The Best Years of Our Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bicycle-thief--bicycle-thieves-1949"&gt;The Bicycle Thief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-heat-1953"&gt;The Big Heat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-lebowski-1998"&gt;The Big Lebowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-red-one-1980"&gt;The Big Red One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-sleep-1946"&gt;The Big Sleep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-birth-of-a-nation-1915"&gt;The Birth of a Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-blade-runner-the-final-cut-1982"&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-blow-up-1966"&gt;Blow-Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-blue-kite-1993"&gt;The Blue Kite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bob-le-flambeur-1955"&gt;Bob le Flambeur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-body-heat-1981"&gt;Body Heat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bonnie-and-clyde-1967"&gt;Bonnie and Clyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-breathless-1960"&gt;Breathless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bride-of-frankenstein"&gt;Bride of Frankenstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bridge-on-the-river-kwai-1957"&gt;The Bridge on the River Kwai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bring-me-the-head-of-alfredo-garcia-1974"&gt;Bring Me the Head of Alfredo Garcia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-broken-blossoms-1919"&gt;Broken Blossoms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-cabinet-of-dr-caligari-1920"&gt;The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cabiria-1914"&gt;Cabiria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cache-2005"&gt;Cache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-casablanca-1942"&gt;Casablanca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cat-people-1942"&gt;Cat People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-ceremonie-1995"&gt;La Ceremonie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-un-chien-andalou-1928"&gt;Un Chien Andalou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-children-of-paradise-1945"&gt;Children of Paradise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chimes-at-midnight-1965"&gt;Chimes at Midnight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chinatown-1974"&gt;Chinatown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/chop-shop-2008-1"&gt;Chop Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-christmas-story-1983"&gt;A Christmas Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chuck-jones-three-cartoons"&gt;Chuck Jones: Three Cartoons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-circus-1928"&gt;The Circus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-citizen-kane-1941"&gt;Citizen Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-city-lights-1931"&gt;City Lights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-collectionneuse-1967"&gt;La Collectionneuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-color-purple-1985"&gt;The Color Purple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-come-and-see-1985"&gt;Come and See&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-contact-1997"&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-conversation-1974"&gt;The Conversation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cool-hand-luke-1967"&gt;Cool Hand Luke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cries-and-whispers-1972"&gt;Cries and Whispers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-crimes-and-misdemeanors-1989"&gt;Crimes and Misdemeanors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-crumb-1994"&gt;Crumb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dark-city-2005"&gt;Dark City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-day-for-night-1973"&gt;Day for Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-days-of-heaven-1978"&gt;Days of Heaven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-dead-1987"&gt;The Dead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-decalogue-1988"&gt;The Decalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-departures-2009"&gt;Departures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-detour-1945"&gt;Detour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-diary-of-a-country-priest-1951"&gt;Diary of a Country Priest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-diary-of-a-lost-girl-1929"&gt;Diary of a Lost Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-discreet-charm-of-the-bourgeoisie-1972"&gt;The Discreet Charm of the Bourgeoisie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/diva-2008"&gt;Diva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-do-the-right-thing-1989"&gt;Do the Right Thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dog-day-afternoon-1975"&gt;Dog Day Afternoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dont-look-now-1974"&gt;Don't Look Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-double-indemnity-1944"&gt;Double Indemnity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-double-life-of-veronique-1991-1"&gt;The Double Life of Veronique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dr-strangelove-1964"&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dracula-1931"&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-duck-soup-1933"&gt;Duck Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982"&gt;E.T. -- The Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-earrings-of-madame-de-1953"&gt;The Earrings of Madame de...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-easy-rider-1969"&gt;Easy Rider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-8-12--eight-and-a-half-1963"&gt;8½ / Eight and a Half&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-el-norte-1983"&gt;El Norte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-el-topo-1970"&gt;El Topo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-enigma-of-kaspar-hauser-1974"&gt;The Enigma of Kaspar Hauser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-mind-2004-1"&gt;Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/exotica-1994"&gt;Exotica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-exterminating-angel-1962"&gt;The Exterminating Angel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-fall-of-the-house-of-usher-1928"&gt;The Fall of the House of Usher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fanny-and-alexander-1983"&gt;Fanny and Alexander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fargo-1996"&gt;Fargo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-faust-1926"&gt;Faust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-firemens-ball-1968"&gt;The Firemen's Ball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fitzcarraldo-1982"&gt;Fitzcarraldo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-five-easy-pieces-1970"&gt;Five Easy Pieces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-floating-weeds-1959"&gt;Floating Weeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-forbidden-games-1952"&gt;Forbidden Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-400-blows-1959"&gt;The 400 Blows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-french-cancan-1954"&gt;French Cancan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gates-of-heaven-1978"&gt;Gates of Heaven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-general-1927"&gt;The General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-godfather-1972"&gt;The Godfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-godfather-part-ii-1974"&gt;The Godfather, Part II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-goldfinger-1964"&gt;Goldfinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gone-with-the-wind-1939"&gt;Gone With the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-1968"&gt;The Good, the Bad and the Ugly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-goodfellas-1991"&gt;GoodFellas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gospel-according-to-st-matthew-1964"&gt;Gospel According to St. Matthew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-grand-illusion-1937"&gt;Grand Illusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-grapes-of-wrath-1940"&gt;The Grapes of Wrath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-grave-of-the-fireflies-1988"&gt;Grave of the Fireflies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-great-dictator-1940"&gt;The Great Dictator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-great-expectations-1946"&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-greed-1925"&gt;Greed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-grey-zone-2001"&gt;The Grey Zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-groundhog-day-1993"&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-hairdressers-husband-1990"&gt;The Hairdresser's Husband&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-harakiri-1962"&gt;Harakiri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-hard-days-night-1964"&gt;A Hard Day's Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-heart-of-glass-1976"&gt;Heart of Glass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-hoop-dreams-1994"&gt;Hoop Dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-house-of-games-1987"&gt;House of Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-howards-end-1992"&gt;Howards End&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-hustler-1961"&gt;The Hustler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ikiru-1952"&gt;Ikiru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/in-a-lonely-place-1950"&gt;In a Lonely Place&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-in-cold-blood-1967"&gt;In Cold Blood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-inherit-the-wind-1960"&gt;Inherit the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-its-a-wonderful-life-1946"&gt;It's a Wonderful Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ivan-the-terrible-parts-i-and-ii"&gt;Ivan the Terrible, Parts I &amp;amp; II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jaws-1975"&gt;Jaws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jfk-1991"&gt;JFK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/johnny-guitar-1954"&gt;Johnny Guitar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jules-and-jim-1961"&gt;Jules and Jim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-juliet-of-the-spirits-1965"&gt;Juliet of the Spirits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-films-of-buster-keaton"&gt;The Films of Buster Keaton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-killer-of-sheep-1977"&gt;Killer of Sheep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-killing-1956"&gt;The Killing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-kind-hearts-and-coronets-1949"&gt;Kind Hearts and Coronets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-king-kong-1933"&gt;King Kong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-latalante-1934"&gt;L'Atalante&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lavventura-1960"&gt;L'Avventura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-confidential-1997"&gt;L.A. Confidential&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-dolce-vita-1960"&gt;La Dolce Vita&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-lady-eve-1941"&gt;The Lady Eve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-last-laugh-1924"&gt;The Last Laugh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-last-picture-show-1971"&gt;The Last Picture Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-last-tango-in-paris-1972"&gt;Last Tango in Paris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-last-temptation-of-christ-1988"&gt;The Last Temptation of Christ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-last-year-at-marienbad-1961"&gt;Last Year at Marienbad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-late-spring-1972"&gt;Late Spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-laura-1944"&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lawrence-of-arabia-1962"&gt;Lawrence of Arabia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-le-boucher--the-butcher-2003"&gt;Le Boucher / The Butcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-le-samourai-1967"&gt;Le Samourai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-leaving-las-vegas-1995"&gt;Leaving Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-leolo-1993"&gt;Leolo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/leon-morin-priest-1961"&gt;Leon Morin, Priest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-leopard-1963"&gt;The Leopard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-life-and-death-of-colonel-blimp-1943"&gt;The Life and Death of Colonel Blimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-river-le-fleuve-1951"&gt;The River (Le Fleuve)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-life-of-oharu-1952"&gt;The Life of Oharu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-long-goodbye-1973"&gt;The Long Goodbye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lost-in-translation-2003"&gt;Lost in Translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-m-1931"&gt;M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-magnolia-1999"&gt;Magnolia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/make-way-for-tomorrow-1937"&gt;Make Way for Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-maltese-falcon-1941"&gt;The Maltese Falcon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-man-escaped-1956"&gt;A Man Escaped&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-man-who-laughs-1928"&gt;The Man Who Laughs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-man-who-shot-liberty-valance-1962"&gt;The Man Who Shot Liberty Valance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-man-with-a-movie-camera-1929"&gt;Man With a Movie Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-manchurian-candidate-1962"&gt;The Manchurian Candidate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-manhattan-1979"&gt;Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-marriage-of-maria-braun-1979"&gt;The Marriage of Maria Braun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-match-factory-girl-1990"&gt;The Match Factory Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mccabe-and-mrs-miller-1971"&gt;McCabe &amp;amp; Mrs. Miller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mean-streets-1973"&gt;Mean Streets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mephisto-1981"&gt;Mephisto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-metropolis-1927"&gt;Metropolis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-metropolis-2010-restoration-1927"&gt;Metropolis-2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mishima-a-life-in-four-chapters-1985"&gt;Mishima: A Life in Four Chapters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mon-oncle-1958"&gt;Mon Oncle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mon-oncle-antoine-1971"&gt;Mon Oncle Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/mon-oncle-damerique-1980"&gt;Mon Oncle d'Amerique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-monsieur-hire-1989"&gt;Monsieur Hire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-moolaade-2007"&gt;Moolaade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-moonstruck-1987"&gt;Moonstruck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mr-hulots-holiday-1953"&gt;Mr. Hulot's Holiday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mulholland-dr-2001"&gt;Mulholland Dr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-music-room-1958"&gt;The Music Room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-darling-clementine-1946"&gt;My Darling Clementine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-dinner-with-andre-1981"&gt;My Dinner With Andre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-fair-lady-1964"&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-man-godfrey-1936"&gt;My Man Godfrey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-neighbor-totoro-1993"&gt;My Neighbor Totoro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mystery-train-1989"&gt;Mystery Train&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nanook-of-the-north-1922"&gt;Nanook of the North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nashville-1975"&gt;Nashville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-network-1976"&gt;Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-night-moves-1975"&gt;Night Moves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-night-of-the-hunter-1955"&gt;The Night of the Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nights-of-cabiria-1957"&gt;Nights of Cabiria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nosferatu-1922"&gt;Nosferatu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nosferatu-the-vampyre-1979"&gt;Nosferatu the Vampyre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-notorious-1946"&gt;Notorious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-on-the-waterfront-1954"&gt;On the Waterfront&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-one-flew-over-the-cuckoos-nest-1975"&gt;One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-only-son-1936"&gt;The Only Son&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ordet-1955"&gt;Ordet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-orpheus-1949"&gt;Orpheus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-out-of-the-past-1947"&gt;Out of the Past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pale-flower-1964"&gt;Pale Flower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pans-labyrinth-2006"&gt;Pan's Labyrinth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pandoras-box-1928"&gt;Pandora's Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-paris-texas-1984"&gt;Paris, Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-passion-of-joan-of-arc-1928"&gt;The Passion of Joan of Arc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-paths-of-glory-1957"&gt;Paths of Glory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-patton-1970"&gt;Patton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-peeping-tom-1960"&gt;Peeping Tom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-persona-1966"&gt;Persona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-phantom-of-the-opera-1925"&gt;The Phantom of the Opera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pickpocket-1959"&gt;Pickpocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-picnic-at-hanging-rock-1975"&gt;Picnic at Hanging Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pink-floyd-the-wall-1982"&gt;Pink Floyd: The Wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pinocchio-1940"&gt;Pinocchio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pixote-1981"&gt;Pixote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-planes-trains-and-automobiles-1987"&gt;Planes, Trains and Automobiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-playtime-1967"&gt;Playtime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-pledge-2001"&gt;The Pledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/a-prairie-home-companion-2006-1"&gt;A Prairie Home Companion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-producers-1968"&gt;The Producers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-psycho-1960"&gt;Psycho&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pulp-fiction-1994"&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raging-bull-1980"&gt;Raging Bull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raiders-of-the-lost-ark-1981"&gt;Raiders of the Lost Ark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raise-the-red-lantern-1990"&gt;Raise the Red Lantern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ran-1985"&gt;Ran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rashomon-1950"&gt;Rashomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rear-window-1954"&gt;Rear Window&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rebel-without-a-cause-1955"&gt;Rebel Without a Cause&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-red-beard-1965"&gt;Red Beard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-red-river-1948"&gt;Red River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-red-shoes-1948"&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/richard-iii-1996-1"&gt;Richard III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rififi-1954"&gt;Rififi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-right-stuff-1983"&gt;The Right Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/rio-bravo-1959"&gt;Rio Bravo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ripleys-game-2002"&gt;Ripley's Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rocco-and-his-brothers-1960"&gt;Rocco and His Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-romeo-and-juliet-1968"&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-rules-of-the-game-1939"&gt;The Rules of the Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-safety-last-1923"&gt;Safety Last&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-samurai-rebellion-1967"&gt;Samurai Rebellion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sansho-the-bailiff-1954"&gt;Sansho the Bailiff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-santa-sangre-1989"&gt;Santa Sangre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-saturday-night-fever-1977"&gt;Saturday Night Fever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-say-anything-1989"&gt;Say Anything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-scarface-1983"&gt;Scarface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-scarlet-empress-1934"&gt;The Scarlet Empress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-schindlers-list-1993"&gt;Schindler's List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-searchers-1956"&gt;The Searchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/secrets-and-lies-1996-1"&gt;Secrets &amp;amp; Lies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-senso-1954"&gt;Senso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-seven-1995"&gt;Seven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-seven-samurai-1954"&gt;The Seven Samurai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-seventh-seal-1957"&gt;The Seventh Seal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shadow-of-a-doubt-1943"&gt;Shadow of a Doubt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shane-1953"&gt;Shane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-shawshank-redemption-1994"&gt;The Shawshank Redemption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-shining-1980"&gt;The Shining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shoah-1985"&gt;Shoah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-silence-of-the-lambs-1991"&gt;The Silence of the Lambs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-silence-1963"&gt;The Silence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-singin-in-the-rain-1952"&gt;Singin' in the Rain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-smiles-of-a-summer-night-1955"&gt;Smiles of a Summer Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-snow-white-and-the-seven-dwarfs-1937"&gt;Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-solaris-1972"&gt;Solaris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-some-like-it-hot-1959"&gt;Some Like It Hot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/souls-for-sale-1923"&gt;Souls For Sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-spirit-of-the-beehive-1973"&gt;Spirit of the Beehive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-spirited-away-2002"&gt;Spirited Away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/spring-summer-fall-winter_and-spring-2003"&gt;Spring, Summer, Fall, Winter and Spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-stagecoach-1939"&gt;Stagecoach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope-1977"&gt;Star Wars (Episode IV: A New Hope)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-strangers-on-a-train-1951"&gt;Strangers on a Train&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-stroszek-1977"&gt;Stroszek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-sunday-in-the-country-1984"&gt;A Sunday in the Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sunrise-1928"&gt;Sunrise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sunset-boulevard-1950"&gt;Sunset Boulevard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-superman-1978"&gt;Superman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-sweet-smell-of-success-1957"&gt;The Sweet Smell of Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-swing-time-1936"&gt;Swing Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-tale-of-winter-1992"&gt;A Tale of Winter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-taxi-driver-1976"&gt;Taxi Driver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-tender-mercies-1983"&gt;Tender Mercies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-terrorist-2000"&gt;The Terrorist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-thief-of-bagdad-1940"&gt;The Thief of Bagdad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-thin-man-1934"&gt;The Thin Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-third-man-1949"&gt;The Third Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-this-is-spinal-tap-1984"&gt;This Is Spinal Tap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-three-colors-trilogy-blue-white-red"&gt;Three Colors Trilogy: Blue, White, Red&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-3-women-1977"&gt;3 Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-through-a-glass-darkly-1961"&gt;Through a Glass Darkly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-tokyo-story-1953"&gt;Tokyo Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-top-hat-1935"&gt;Top Hat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-touch-of-evil-1958"&gt;Touch of Evil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-touchez-pas-au-grisbi-1954"&gt;Touchez Pas au Grisbi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-treasure-of-the-sierra-madre-1948"&gt;The Treasure of the Sierra Madre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-triumph-of-the-will-1935"&gt;Triumph of the Will&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-trouble-in-paradise-1932"&gt;Trouble in Paradise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/25th-hour-2002"&gt;25th Hour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-2001-a-space-odyssey-1968"&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ugetsu-1953"&gt;Ugetsu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-umberto-d-1952"&gt;Umberto D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-unforgiven-1992"&gt;Unforgiven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-up-documentaries-1985"&gt;The Up Documentaries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/vengeance-is-mine-2008"&gt;Vengeance Is Mine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-veronika-voss-1982"&gt;Veronika Voss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-vertigo-1958"&gt;Vertigo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-victim-1961"&gt;Victim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-viridiana-1961"&gt;Viridiana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-vivre-sa-vie--my-life-to-live-1963"&gt;Vivre sa Vie / My Life to Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/waking-life-2001-1"&gt;Waking Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-walkabout-1971"&gt;Walkabout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/werckmeister-harmonies-2000"&gt;Werckmeister Harmonies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-west-side-story-1961"&gt;West Side Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-what-ever-happened-to-baby-jane-1962"&gt;What Ever Happened to Baby Jane?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-wild-bunch-1969"&gt;The Wild Bunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-wings-of-desire-1988"&gt;Wings of Desire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-winter-light-1962"&gt;Winter Light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/withnail-and-i-1987"&gt;Withnail &amp;amp; I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-wizard-of-oz-1939"&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-woman-in-the-dunes-1964"&gt;Woman in the Dunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-woman-under-the-influence-1974"&gt;A Woman Under the Influence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-womans-tale-1992"&gt;A Woman's Tale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-woodstock-1970"&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-wr-mysteries-of-the-organism-1971"&gt;WR -- Mysteries of the Organism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-written-on-the-wind-1956"&gt;Written on the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yankee-doodle-dandy-1942"&gt;Yankee Doodle Dandy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-year-of-the-quiet-sun-1984"&gt;A Year of the Quiet Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yellow-submarine-1968"&gt;Yellow Submarine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yojimbo-1961"&gt;Yojimbo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="small"&gt;(and a cache of them &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/file/ebert.zip"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, just in case)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Learning JavaScript - my experience and advice</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/learn-js</id>
    <updated>2013-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/learn-js"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Since I've &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/prog"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/os"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; that I just learned JavaScript over the last few months, a bunch of people have emailed to ask what I used and recommend to learn it. So here's my experience and best advice for 2013.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
NOTE: I wanted to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; learn JavaScript - not shortcuts, quick tricks, or meta-tools&lt;/strong&gt; that keep me from having to learn JavaScript. I want to learn it, get it, read it, understand it, and memorize it, so that I can understand all the other cool things written in JavaScript for years to come.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First - a bunch of people will tell you to get &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do"&gt;JavaScript: The Good Parts - by Douglas Crockford&lt;/a&gt;. But when I started reading it, it was so dense and succinct that I had no idea what it was talking about!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You know when an expert is talking about their field, and don't know how to simplify it for just anyone? Well, this book felt like it'd be perfect for someone who's been programming for 20 years in C, Java, and C++, and just needs a quick overview of what they should know about JavaScript.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But it doesn't really TEACH you. It doesn't guide you through anything. So I recommend skipping it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Instead, &lt;strong&gt;start with &lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/"&gt;Eloquent JavaScript - by Marijn Haverbeke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It starts so simple, so easy, almost too simple, but this is encouraging. You get your swagger back as you say, “This is easy!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/contents.html"&gt;Do the online version, here&lt;/a&gt;, because you can test and experiment directly in your browser.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then, after a few chapters of that, &lt;strong&gt;switch over to &lt;a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html"&gt;Professional JavaScript for Web Developers, 3rd Edition - by Nicholas Zakas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;THAT is the ultimate tutorial.&lt;/strong&gt; It takes the time to explain everything thoroughly, and it covers pretty much everything. Put aside a few hours per chapter, and &lt;strong&gt;by the time you're done with this one book, you'll know as much as most people who call themselves JavaScript programmers.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Funny thing is, I went back to &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do"&gt;JavaScript: The Good Parts&lt;/a&gt; after finishing this one, and now I understood it. But because &lt;a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html"&gt;Professional JavaScript for Web Developers&lt;/a&gt; was so thorough, it had already covered all of the “good parts”, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course &lt;strong&gt;you have to retain what you're learning&lt;/strong&gt;, so I highly recommend you &lt;strong&gt;write down every new thing you learn&lt;/strong&gt;, ideally into a flashcard program, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;. It's a lot to take in, so you'll have to remind yourself of what you've learned in the weeks and months afterwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
If you're in the mood for more books to really solidify JavaScript in your head, go through:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596806149.do"&gt;JavaScript Cookbook - by Shelley Powers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://effectivejs.com/"&gt;Effective JavaScript - by David Herman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/resig/"&gt;Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja - by John Resig and Bear Bibeault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All of these are great, and you'll notice you go through them much faster now that you're fluent. Do the examples. Play around.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Read some real-world JavaScript code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After a thousand pages of tiny example code snippets, you'll love looking at the code to two very popular and powerful JavaScript projects:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://underscorejs.org/docs/underscore.html"&gt;Underscore.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org/docs/backbone.html"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You'll notice that it all makes sense, now. You're now functionally fluent in reading and understanding JavaScript.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Then jQuery, and more...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://jquery.com/"&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt; is absolutely everywhere, and you must learn it for your JavaScript tutorial to be complete.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now that you've learned the plain-JavaScript long and verbose way of doing things, you'll appreciate the shortcuts that jQuery provides.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I really liked &lt;a href="http://www.headfirstlabs.com/books/hfjquery/"&gt;Head First jQuery&lt;/a&gt;, as goofy as it is. It walks you through jQuery wonderfully well, and has you apply what you've learned, as you go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And if you're still hungry to learn more JavaScript, dive into:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://coffeescript.org/"&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920024309.do"&gt;The Little Book on CoffeeScript - by Alex MacCaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org/"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://javascriptissexy.com/learn-backbone-js-completely/"&gt;following this path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://javascriptissexy.com/learn-node-js-completely-and-with-confidence/"&gt;following this path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Then put down the books and go use it!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You would think this goes without saying, but if I didn't say it, someone would complain. So look at your existing sites, and go apply what you've learned.  Or start a new site from scratch and make it all with JavaScript, even if just as an experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Any other suggestions? What worked for you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well... that's what I did, and I'm quite happy with the results.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please share any other suggestions or experiences, here:
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Human Intervention as a Competitive Advantage</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/hi</id>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/hi"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The listening algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A year after I started CD Baby, when it was still just me in my bedroom, the CEO and VP of a hugely-funded Silicon Valley online music company contacted me, saying they wanted to fly out to New York to meet me.  I said OK, and we met a week later for dinner.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Dinner was a lot of blah blah blah smalltalk, and I wondered what they really wanted.  Then they finally got to the real point:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“The reason we flew out to meet you is because we’ve been looking at many music recommendation engines, and the one that’s powering cdbaby.com is one of the best we’ve found.  Could you tell us a little something about the algorithms and data points you’re using?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Uh...  I was confused, and asked what they meant.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They said, “The «if you like this you will like that» recommendations. We’ve been testing them on your site, but they don’t seem to be sales-driven like Amazon. The music-matching algorithm comes up with incredible recommendations. What software are you using for that?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ah!  I get it.  I smiled and pointed to my ear.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“No software. &lt;strong&gt;I just listen to everything that comes in, and recommend other good stuff like it.&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now they looked confused.  “&lt;strong&gt;But how will that scale?&lt;/strong&gt;  You can’t just listen to every single album!  What will you do when you start getting a hundred albums a day?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I said, “Maybe hire someone just to listen.  I don’t know.  I’m not there yet.  I’ll worry about it then.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(And that’s what I did, when we were getting a hundred albums a day. The coolest full-time job in the world went to Pamela Rooney, who would listen to every new arrival, and do the internal recommendations.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Minimizing or Maximizing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;When everyone else is trying to automate everything, using a little human intervention can be a competitive advantage.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The problem is when business owners see it as a cost, instead of an opportunity.  &lt;strong&gt;Trying to minimize costs, instead of maximize income, quality, loyalty, happiness, connection, and all those other wonderful things that come from real human attention.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can buy a fancy phone routing system, so people have to listen to 9 options, choose option 5, then listen to 6 more options...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... or ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... you can hire a charming person to pick up the phone on the first ring, and make a great impression.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Which one do you think will win you new fans?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can put rules into your online forms, so if someone puts a dash in their phone number, or writes “coming soon” as their URL, it tells them they’re wrong and makes them do it over again....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... or ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... you can have new submissions be checked-over quickly by a real person.  It’s worth the 10 seconds of human effort, to &lt;strong&gt;keep the end-user experience easy&lt;/strong&gt; but the internal data correct.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s fun for techies to try to find the tech solution to everything, but don’t forget that even a tiny touch from a real person can be the best alogrithm, and a massive business maximizer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who should do the work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I get the mindset.  It’s saying, “By having our software and our users do most of the work, we can keep our business efficient and scalable.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you want them to pay you, if you want to be more valuable, you have to &lt;a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/schlep.html"&gt;take on more of that work&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I meet so many entrepreneurs who are convinced their thing will be as big as Facebook, so they can’t afford to have a personal touch for all those BILLIONS of users that are going to start flowing through their app.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But by removing all human contact, they’re making their app less valuable, so that they’ll never get big enough for it “how does it scale?” to matter.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/carrying_crate.png" alt="carrying crate" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
