<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://sivers.org/en.atom</id>
  <title>Derek Sivers</title>
  <updated>2013-07-30T15:06:05+12:00</updated>
  <link href="http://sivers.org/"/>
  <author>
    <name>Derek Sivers</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Fragile Plan vs Robust Plan</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/robust</id>
    <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/robust"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
When I &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/eg"&gt;first had the idea for Wood Egg&lt;/a&gt; - publishing 16 books about 16 countries every year - I thought I would write them all &lt;strong&gt;myself&lt;/strong&gt;.  Visit 16 countries for 3 weeks each, doing intensive research the whole time.  That’s 48 weeks, so I could do it again each year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But I had a baby on the way, so that idea lasted about a minute.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I thought of &lt;strong&gt;a journalist&lt;/strong&gt; I know who would love that kind of life.  I asked, she said yes, she flew to Singapore, and started working.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But it was a really bad fit, so after five weeks, we called it quits.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I decided to hire &lt;strong&gt;one writer per-country&lt;/strong&gt;.  16 authors to write 16 books.  This went OK at first.  &lt;a href="http://mohitpawar.com/about/"&gt;Mohit Pawar&lt;/a&gt; did a great job with India, and &lt;a href="http://www.cameronkeng.com/about/"&gt;Cameron Keng&lt;/a&gt; did a great job with Taiwan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
… But the people I hired for the other countries flaked out, so I realized this plan was still too fragile.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Making a Robust Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I really wanted this to work.  I had to be smart.  I had to make a better plan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I re-read my notes on &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/EMythRevisited"&gt;E-Myth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/WisdomOfCrowds"&gt;The Wisdom of Crowds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/Crowdsourcing"&gt;Crowdsourcing&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/HereComesEverybody"&gt;Here Comes Everybody&lt;/a&gt;.  (In fact, I re-read &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book"&gt;my notes on ALL 130 books&lt;/a&gt;. It was an enlightening week.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I learned a few things:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want help, it helps to get specific.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A plan that’s too dependent on any one person is too fragile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting Specific:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before, I had a very vague outline of what I wanted the book to cover.  I asked the authors to include sections on culture, government, business setup, hiring, banking, and marketing.  That was it.  The details were up to them.  Go!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In hindsight, I can see how daunting it was.  Too wide open.  I’ve written about the need to get specific before - (see “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/get-specific"&gt;Get specific&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/restrictions-will-set-you-free"&gt;Restrictions will set you free&lt;/a&gt;”) - but I had forgotten to apply it to this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I spent a couple weeks and &lt;strong&gt;came up with &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in#toc"&gt;200 specific questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  Now, to write the book, we just had to answer those 200 questions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s infinitely easier to find someone to answer a specific question than to find someone to impart wisdom on a vague topic.  It &lt;strong&gt;puts the burden on the asker&lt;/strong&gt;, to come up with a good question, and &lt;strong&gt;lifts the burden from the answerer.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Multiple People:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So that the book was not dependent on any one person, and the book was not one person’s opinion, I made a system where each of those 200 questions had to be &lt;strong&gt;answered by three different people&lt;/strong&gt;.  Ideally, one local, one foreigner, and one other.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
16 countries × 3 researchers = 48 people.  I used &lt;a href="https://www.elance.com/"&gt;Elance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.odesk.com/"&gt;oDesk&lt;/a&gt; to find people in each country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course, some disappeared, some never finished, and a few gave bad answers, but that was OK.  Life happens. People’s circumstances change. I understand. But it won’t hurt my plan.  If any one person is gone, I can still carry on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When all 200 questions had 3 answers each, (16 × 200 × 3 = 9600 answers), I hired a few writer/editors to combine the answers into one essay per question.  Again, one person disappeared, but it was easy for another to step in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And that was the robust plan that got it &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;done&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(Note: I was also visiting every country myself, and contributing my own research to the books. But it was important that the plan didn’t require me, either.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you’re starting a project or company:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t expect anyone to care as much as you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t require them to think as hard about this as you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do expect them to change their mind and disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a robust plan that includes #1-3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;As the founder, the burden is on you to come up with a great plan, to lift the burden from the people helping you.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then, when you find some &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/Linchpin"&gt;brilliant people&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a great bonus, instead of an absolute necessity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/table-many-legs.jpg" width="543" height="343"&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wood Egg (my new company)</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/eg</id>
    <updated>2013-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/eg"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Like everyone, I can get deeply curious about something, and dive in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Starting five years ago, I got deeply curious about the differences between countries and cultures, fascinated with understanding the different perspectives. I talked about a few fun ones in &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_weird_or_just_different.html"&gt;this 2-minute TED talk&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So two years ago, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/singapore"&gt;I moved to Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, and started visiting all the countries in Asia, asking dumb questions, making good friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Getting to know these countries is endlessly interesting.  I want to understand them as well as I understand the 50 U.S. states.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But my learning felt too unstructured.  So while walking around Yogyakarta, Indonesia, remembering “&lt;strong&gt;the best way to learn something is to teach it&lt;/strong&gt;”, I came up with an ambitious plan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I decided to produce and publish &lt;strong&gt;16 books per year on 16 countries in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: Cambodia, China, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Japan, Korea, Malaysia, Mongolia, Myanmar, Philippines, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Taiwan, Thailand, and Vietnam. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sure, they wouldn’t be great at first, but I committed to &lt;strong&gt;improving them every year for many years&lt;/strong&gt;.  After a few years of doing this, they should be pretty awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Instead of being all-encompassing, I decided to focus just on entrepreneurship: a network I was already tapped into, a good filter for understanding a country’s culture, and a subject that may be useful to others.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What to name it?  That only took a minute.  I like &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2003/06/naming_a_busine.html"&gt;Seth Godin’s advice about naming&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;ntrepreneur’s &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;uide?  E… G…  Egg!  Golden Egg?  Too cliché.  &lt;strong&gt;Wood Egg?&lt;/strong&gt;  Yep!  Sounds like an exotic carved Thai or Indonesian treasure.  Good enough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I set up a Singapore corporation for it from my Yogyakarta hotel room that night in August 2011, and began the next day.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And now, &lt;strong&gt;after a year and a half of work&lt;/strong&gt; - (and some hard lessons learned that I’ll write about soon) - &lt;strong&gt;they’re done!  So my new company is launched:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;Wood Egg - the entrepeneur’s guides to Asia&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;woodegg.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please check it out.  And if you’re also interested in this subject, &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/help"&gt;see the help wanted page&lt;/a&gt;, because I’m starting on the 2014 guides immediately.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center" style="background-color: #000"&gt;&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wood-egg-450-450.jpg" width="450" height="450" alt="wood egg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Some will always say you're wrong</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/wrong</id>
    <updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/wrong"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Some people are into money.  Some aren’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some people are inspired by helping the needy.  Some aren’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some are into fame, power, and prestige.  Others are into anonymity and freedom from responsibility.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It gets more interesting when you realize people have different preferences in the different parts of their life.  Famous online, but anonymous in their local community.  Generous with time, stingy with money.  Introvert when working, extrovert when not.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/grade"&gt;know your preferences well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, because &lt;strong&gt;no matter what you do, someone will tell you you’re wrong&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into money, many people will say you’re foolish.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into charity, many people will say you’re greedy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re not into crowds, many people will say you’re missing out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some careers come with excuses:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The classic novelist thrives in solitude.  Alone in a cabin in the woods, writing books that reach millions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The classic journalist thrives in a crowd.  Talking with everyone, building the story from a thousand accounts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The shy librarian.  The aggressive lawyer.  The flaky artist.  No explanation needed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;But some careers need explanations when you go against the mold:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The entrepreneur who’s not into money.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The musician who avoids crowds.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The ambitious conservationist.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The artist into discpline.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/HowToGetRich"&gt;rich poet&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you &lt;strong&gt;expect this criticism in advance&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;take pride in your stance&lt;/strong&gt;, you can bash on with a smile, being who you want to be.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then every time they say you’re wrong, that’s a sign you’re doing it right.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/HermitCrab.jpg" width="600" height="392"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(image by &lt;a href="http://www.finland.org/public/default.aspx?contentid=181860&amp;nodeid=35833"&gt;Alex Marttunen&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>No rules in this game</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/360</id>
    <updated>2013-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/360"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Everyone thinks you have to move to the big music cities. But Mihkel Raud in Estonia sold thousands of albums, 100% independent, without leaving Estonia. &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00007MB39"&gt;Rondellus Sabbatum&lt;/a&gt; was an album so unique that word-of-mouth sold thousands, with hardly any promotion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everyone says you need to make your music appeal to the masses. But Regina Spektor proved that emphasizing your quirks gets you further. &lt;a href="http://www.cdbaby.com/artist/ReginaSpektor"&gt;Listen to her early albums from 2001 and 2002&lt;/a&gt;. She was being more mainstream fit-the-mold piano vocal. But the weirder she got with &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ycum4o6jlzQ"&gt;Soviet Kitsch&lt;/a&gt;, the more remarkable and noteworthy she became, and that’s when her career really took off.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everyone is worried about piracy, copyright, and trademark. But &lt;a href="http://www.jonathancoulton.com/"&gt;Jonathan Coulton&lt;/a&gt; writes a song a day, gives most away, and is one of the most successful independent artists today. By making more and more music, and letting it flow, his music has gotten into unusual places like webcomics, audiobooks, comedy shows, and others’ YouTube videos. He disclosed that he makes about $500,000 a year by licensing, touring, donations, and people choosing to buy his music from his site, even though they could get it for free.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because the music business is mostly perception, and minds are irrational, you can really have some fun with the counter-intuitive pop-psychology of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to win fans is to target a sharp niche - to &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/proudly-exclude-most"&gt;proudly exclude&lt;/a&gt; 99% of the public. So the way to win fans is to exclude almost everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to get funding is to act as if you’ll never get funding - to make &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/good-biz-plan"&gt;a plan that doesn’t need it&lt;/a&gt;. So the way to get funding is to ignore funding.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A great way to have a serious career in music is to take nothing seriously. Do the opposite of other musicians. Make up your own game.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Gurus will say what you must do or can’t do. They mean well, but they’re wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For every rule they tell you, there’s an exception. &lt;strong&gt;They are just telling you their specific past, not your specific future.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are no rules in this game. You change them as you go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was my contribution to Andrew Dubber’s great book, “&lt;a href="https://leanpub.com/360deal"&gt;The 360 Deal: A collection of genuinely helpful advice for people starting out in the music industry&lt;/a&gt;”. You should buy it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/bloodyclown.jpg" width="600" height="521"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zickie/4025087286/"&gt;zickie&lt;/a&gt;. (Sorry I couldn't find a free &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvin_and_Hobbes#Calvinball"&gt;Calvinball&lt;/a&gt; image.)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Seeking inspiration?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/io</id>
    <updated>2013-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/io"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
The word “inspiration” usually means something that mentally stimulates you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But “inspiration” also means to &lt;a href="http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/inspiration"&gt;breathe in&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The meanings poetically combine when you think of yourself breathing in thoughts, filling your body with ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But don’t forget to breathe out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some people watch hundreds of &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/speakers/derek_sivers.html"&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;, looking for inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Tech entrepreneurs visit &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; every few hours, looking for new inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Musicians, writers, artists, and everyone else, all scouring the world for inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Breathing in, and in, and in, and in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yet most of them aren’t feeling inspired enough.  They’re looking for more, thinking something else out there will truly inspire them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Want to know why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Because nothing is truly inspiring unless you apply it to your work.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;em&gt;(“work” meaning your life’s output, whether creative, business, or personal.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In other words, &lt;strong&gt;your work, itself, is the inspiration.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You may hear something or see something that gives you a new idea.But it’s only when you stop and think of your work through this new perspective, that you actually &lt;strong&gt;jump up and go turn the idea into reality.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;That’s the real inspiration that everyone is looking for!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The inspiration is not the receiving of information.  The inspiration is &lt;strong&gt;applying&lt;/strong&gt; what you’ve received.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
People think that if they keep reading articles, browsing books, listening to talks, or meeting people, that they’re going to suddenly get inspired.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;constantly seeking inspiration is anti-inspiring.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have to pause the input, and focus on your output.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For every bit of inspiration, use it and amplify it by applying it to your work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then you’ll finally feel the inspiration you’ve been looking for.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Breathe in. Breathe out. Breathe in. Breathe out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/handwriting.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/beth19/4866638272/"&gt;bethan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Great Movies</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/ebert2</id>
    <updated>2013-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/ebert2"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
A friend I hadn’t heard from in years called me out of the blue yesterday, and just said, “Dude... did you hear?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I went home and before she even saw me, my wife asked from the next room, “Babe... I heard the news. Are you OK?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They all know what an Ebert fan I am.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was also a massive James Brown fan, but I wasn’t as affected when he died, because it’s not like I was tuning in weekly to hear what new music he was making.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But Ebert... ooof....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every Friday since 1994 (yes 1994), I’d go to rogerebert.suntimes.com to read his new in-depth film reviews. I feel like I’ve been in his part-time film school class for the last 19 years. My life is so much richer from it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is going to be a hard habit to break.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Every time we’d watch a movie, I’d go back and read Ebert’s essay on it, to get a different perspective. My wife would joke, after the credits rolled, “OK, now go find out what Ebert said about it. I know you want to. I’ll wait.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“The Great Movies” was his collection of films he felt were the best. Years after his initial review, he’d go back and watch it at least once more, then write a deeper essay about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A few years ago, I subscribed to Netflix and put all 300-or-so of “The Great Movies” in my queue.  We’d watch one or two a week, not reading his essay until afterwards.  I've seen most but not all of them now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A hidden world opens up to you when you dive deep into an art form.  Years of studying jazz at Berklee School of Music opened up that world to me.  Art is so much deeper when you get the contexts and references.  Ebert single-handedly did that for me for movies.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Someone recently &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/cekj0/roger_ebert/"&gt;asked him&lt;/a&gt;, “Do you think a more innocent viewpoint, not marred by technical knowledge, leads to a more ‘pure’ watching experience - the emotional elements without being distracted by technicalities?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He answered, “The more movies you see and write about, the more you know about them. Consider baseball. The ‘innocent’ crowd member sees a bunch of guys running after a little ball while wearing funny costumes. The Cubs fan sees inevitable tragedy unfolding.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, yeah.  I recommend you watch as many of these movies and read as many of these 364 essays as you can.  Especially the ones you think you’d be least likely to enjoy.  I’ll keep the links here permanently.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Roger Ebert’s “The Great Movies” essays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-12-angry-men-1957"&gt;12 Angry Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ace-in-the-hole-1951"&gt;Ace in the Hole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-adaptation-2002"&gt;Adaptation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-adventures-of-robin-hood-1938"&gt;The Adventures of Robin Hood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-after-dark-my-sweet-1990"&gt;After Dark, My Sweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/after-hours-1985-1"&gt;After Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-age-of-innocence-1993"&gt;The Age of Innocence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-aguirre-the-wrath-of-god-1972"&gt;Aguirre, the Wrath of God&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ai-artificial-intelligence-2001"&gt;A.I. Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ali-fear-eats-the-soul-1974"&gt;Ali: Fear Eats the Soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-alien-1979"&gt;Alien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-all-about-eve-1950"&gt;All About Eve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-amadeus-1984"&gt;Amadeus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-amarcord-1974"&gt;Amarcord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-annie-hall-1977"&gt;Annie Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-apartment-1960"&gt;The Apartment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-apocalypse-now-1979"&gt;Apocalypse Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-apu-trilogy-1959"&gt;The Apu Trilogy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-army-of-shadows-1969"&gt;Army of Shadows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-atlantic-city-1980"&gt;Atlantic City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-au-hasard-balthazar-1966"&gt;Au Hasard Balthazar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-au-revoir-les-enfants-1987"&gt;Au Revoir, les Enfants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-an-autumn-afternoon-1962"&gt;An Autumn Afternoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/babel-2006"&gt;Babel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-badlands-1973"&gt;Badlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-ballad-of-narayama-1958"&gt;The Ballad of Narayama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-band-wagon-1953"&gt;The Band Wagon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bank-dick-1940"&gt;The Bank Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-baraka-1992"&gt;Baraka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/barry-lyndon-1975"&gt;Barry Lyndon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-battle-of-algiers-1967"&gt;The Battle of Algiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-battleship-potemkin-1925"&gt;The Battleship Potemkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-beat-the-devil-1954"&gt;Beat the Devil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-beauty-and-the-beast-1946"&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-being-there-1979"&gt;Being There&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-belle-de-jour-1967"&gt;Belle de Jour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/la-belle-noiseuse-1991"&gt;La Belle Noiseuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-best-years-of-our-lives-1946"&gt;The Best Years of Our Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bicycle-thief--bicycle-thieves-1949"&gt;The Bicycle Thief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-heat-1953"&gt;The Big Heat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-lebowski-1998"&gt;The Big Lebowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-red-one-1980"&gt;The Big Red One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-big-sleep-1946"&gt;The Big Sleep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-birth-of-a-nation-1915"&gt;The Birth of a Nation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-blade-runner-the-final-cut-1982"&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-blow-up-1966"&gt;Blow-Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-blue-kite-1993"&gt;The Blue Kite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bob-le-flambeur-1955"&gt;Bob le Flambeur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-body-heat-1981"&gt;Body Heat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bonnie-and-clyde-1967"&gt;Bonnie and Clyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-breathless-1960"&gt;Breathless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bride-of-frankenstein"&gt;Bride of Frankenstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-bridge-on-the-river-kwai-1957"&gt;The Bridge on the River Kwai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-bring-me-the-head-of-alfredo-garcia-1974"&gt;Bring Me the Head of Alfredo Garcia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-broken-blossoms-1919"&gt;Broken Blossoms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-cabinet-of-dr-caligari-1920"&gt;The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cabiria-1914"&gt;Cabiria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cache-2005"&gt;Cache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-casablanca-1942"&gt;Casablanca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cat-people-1942"&gt;Cat People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-ceremonie-1995"&gt;La Ceremonie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-un-chien-andalou-1928"&gt;Un Chien Andalou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-children-of-paradise-1945"&gt;Children of Paradise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chimes-at-midnight-1965"&gt;Chimes at Midnight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chinatown-1974"&gt;Chinatown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/chop-shop-2008-1"&gt;Chop Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-christmas-story-1983"&gt;A Christmas Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-chuck-jones-three-cartoons"&gt;Chuck Jones: Three Cartoons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-circus-1928"&gt;The Circus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-citizen-kane-1941"&gt;Citizen Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-city-lights-1931"&gt;City Lights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-collectionneuse-1967"&gt;La Collectionneuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-color-purple-1985"&gt;The Color Purple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-come-and-see-1985"&gt;Come and See&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-contact-1997"&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-conversation-1974"&gt;The Conversation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cool-hand-luke-1967"&gt;Cool Hand Luke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-cries-and-whispers-1972"&gt;Cries and Whispers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-crimes-and-misdemeanors-1989"&gt;Crimes and Misdemeanors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-crumb-1994"&gt;Crumb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dark-city-2005"&gt;Dark City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-day-for-night-1973"&gt;Day for Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-days-of-heaven-1978"&gt;Days of Heaven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-dead-1987"&gt;The Dead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-decalogue-1988"&gt;The Decalogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-departures-2009"&gt;Departures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-detour-1945"&gt;Detour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-diary-of-a-country-priest-1951"&gt;Diary of a Country Priest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-diary-of-a-lost-girl-1929"&gt;Diary of a Lost Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-discreet-charm-of-the-bourgeoisie-1972"&gt;The Discreet Charm of the Bourgeoisie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/diva-2008"&gt;Diva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-do-the-right-thing-1989"&gt;Do the Right Thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dog-day-afternoon-1975"&gt;Dog Day Afternoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dont-look-now-1974"&gt;Don't Look Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-double-indemnity-1944"&gt;Double Indemnity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-double-life-of-veronique-1991-1"&gt;The Double Life of Veronique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dr-strangelove-1964"&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-dracula-1931"&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-duck-soup-1933"&gt;Duck Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-et-the-extra-terrestrial-1982"&gt;E.T. -- The Extra-Terrestrial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-earrings-of-madame-de-1953"&gt;The Earrings of Madame de...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-easy-rider-1969"&gt;Easy Rider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-8-12--eight-and-a-half-1963"&gt;8½ / Eight and a Half&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-el-norte-1983"&gt;El Norte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-el-topo-1970"&gt;El Topo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-enigma-of-kaspar-hauser-1974"&gt;The Enigma of Kaspar Hauser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/eternal-sunshine-of-the-spotless-mind-2004-1"&gt;Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/exotica-1994"&gt;Exotica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-exterminating-angel-1962"&gt;The Exterminating Angel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-fall-of-the-house-of-usher-1928"&gt;The Fall of the House of Usher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fanny-and-alexander-1983"&gt;Fanny and Alexander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fargo-1996"&gt;Fargo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-faust-1926"&gt;Faust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-firemens-ball-1968"&gt;The Firemen's Ball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-fitzcarraldo-1982"&gt;Fitzcarraldo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-five-easy-pieces-1970"&gt;Five Easy Pieces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-floating-weeds-1959"&gt;Floating Weeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-forbidden-games-1952"&gt;Forbidden Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-400-blows-1959"&gt;The 400 Blows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-french-cancan-1954"&gt;French Cancan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gates-of-heaven-1978"&gt;Gates of Heaven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-general-1927"&gt;The General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-godfather-1972"&gt;The Godfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-godfather-part-ii-1974"&gt;The Godfather, Part II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-goldfinger-1964"&gt;Goldfinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gone-with-the-wind-1939"&gt;Gone With the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-1968"&gt;The Good, the Bad and the Ugly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-goodfellas-1991"&gt;GoodFellas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-gospel-according-to-st-matthew-1964"&gt;Gospel According to St. Matthew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-grand-illusion-1937"&gt;Grand Illusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-grapes-of-wrath-1940"&gt;The Grapes of Wrath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-grave-of-the-fireflies-1988"&gt;Grave of the Fireflies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-great-dictator-1940"&gt;The Great Dictator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-great-expectations-1946"&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-greed-1925"&gt;Greed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-grey-zone-2001"&gt;The Grey Zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-groundhog-day-1993"&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-hairdressers-husband-1990"&gt;The Hairdresser's Husband&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-harakiri-1962"&gt;Harakiri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-hard-days-night-1964"&gt;A Hard Day's Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-heart-of-glass-1976"&gt;Heart of Glass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-hoop-dreams-1994"&gt;Hoop Dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-house-of-games-1987"&gt;House of Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-howards-end-1992"&gt;Howards End&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-hustler-1961"&gt;The Hustler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ikiru-1952"&gt;Ikiru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/in-a-lonely-place-1950"&gt;In a Lonely Place&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-in-cold-blood-1967"&gt;In Cold Blood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-inherit-the-wind-1960"&gt;Inherit the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-its-a-wonderful-life-1946"&gt;It's a Wonderful Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ivan-the-terrible-parts-i-and-ii"&gt;Ivan the Terrible, Parts I &amp;amp; II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jaws-1975"&gt;Jaws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jfk-1991"&gt;JFK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/johnny-guitar-1954"&gt;Johnny Guitar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-jules-and-jim-1961"&gt;Jules and Jim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-juliet-of-the-spirits-1965"&gt;Juliet of the Spirits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-films-of-buster-keaton"&gt;The Films of Buster Keaton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-killer-of-sheep-1977"&gt;Killer of Sheep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-killing-1956"&gt;The Killing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-kind-hearts-and-coronets-1949"&gt;Kind Hearts and Coronets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-king-kong-1933"&gt;King Kong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-latalante-1934"&gt;L'Atalante&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lavventura-1960"&gt;L'Avventura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-confidential-1997"&gt;L.A. Confidential&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-la-dolce-vita-1960"&gt;La Dolce Vita&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-lady-eve-1941"&gt;The Lady Eve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-last-laugh-1924"&gt;The Last Laugh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-last-picture-show-1971"&gt;The Last Picture Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-last-tango-in-paris-1972"&gt;Last Tango in Paris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-last-temptation-of-christ-1988"&gt;The Last Temptation of Christ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-last-year-at-marienbad-1961"&gt;Last Year at Marienbad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-late-spring-1972"&gt;Late Spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-laura-1944"&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lawrence-of-arabia-1962"&gt;Lawrence of Arabia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-le-boucher--the-butcher-2003"&gt;Le Boucher / The Butcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-le-samourai-1967"&gt;Le Samourai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-leaving-las-vegas-1995"&gt;Leaving Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-leolo-1993"&gt;Leolo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/leon-morin-priest-1961"&gt;Leon Morin, Priest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-leopard-1963"&gt;The Leopard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-life-and-death-of-colonel-blimp-1943"&gt;The Life and Death of Colonel Blimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-river-le-fleuve-1951"&gt;The River (Le Fleuve)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-life-of-oharu-1952"&gt;The Life of Oharu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-long-goodbye-1973"&gt;The Long Goodbye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-lost-in-translation-2003"&gt;Lost in Translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-m-1931"&gt;M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-magnolia-1999"&gt;Magnolia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/make-way-for-tomorrow-1937"&gt;Make Way for Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-maltese-falcon-1941"&gt;The Maltese Falcon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-man-escaped-1956"&gt;A Man Escaped&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-man-who-laughs-1928"&gt;The Man Who Laughs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-man-who-shot-liberty-valance-1962"&gt;The Man Who Shot Liberty Valance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-man-with-a-movie-camera-1929"&gt;Man With a Movie Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-manchurian-candidate-1962"&gt;The Manchurian Candidate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-manhattan-1979"&gt;Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-marriage-of-maria-braun-1979"&gt;The Marriage of Maria Braun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-match-factory-girl-1990"&gt;The Match Factory Girl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mccabe-and-mrs-miller-1971"&gt;McCabe &amp;amp; Mrs. Miller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mean-streets-1973"&gt;Mean Streets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mephisto-1981"&gt;Mephisto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-metropolis-1927"&gt;Metropolis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-metropolis-2010-restoration-1927"&gt;Metropolis-2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mishima-a-life-in-four-chapters-1985"&gt;Mishima: A Life in Four Chapters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mon-oncle-1958"&gt;Mon Oncle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mon-oncle-antoine-1971"&gt;Mon Oncle Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/mon-oncle-damerique-1980"&gt;Mon Oncle d'Amerique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-monsieur-hire-1989"&gt;Monsieur Hire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-moolaade-2007"&gt;Moolaade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-moonstruck-1987"&gt;Moonstruck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mr-hulots-holiday-1953"&gt;Mr. Hulot's Holiday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mulholland-dr-2001"&gt;Mulholland Dr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-music-room-1958"&gt;The Music Room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-darling-clementine-1946"&gt;My Darling Clementine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-dinner-with-andre-1981"&gt;My Dinner With Andre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-fair-lady-1964"&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-man-godfrey-1936"&gt;My Man Godfrey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-my-neighbor-totoro-1993"&gt;My Neighbor Totoro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-mystery-train-1989"&gt;Mystery Train&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nanook-of-the-north-1922"&gt;Nanook of the North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nashville-1975"&gt;Nashville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-network-1976"&gt;Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-night-moves-1975"&gt;Night Moves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-night-of-the-hunter-1955"&gt;The Night of the Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nights-of-cabiria-1957"&gt;Nights of Cabiria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nosferatu-1922"&gt;Nosferatu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-nosferatu-the-vampyre-1979"&gt;Nosferatu the Vampyre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-notorious-1946"&gt;Notorious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-on-the-waterfront-1954"&gt;On the Waterfront&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-one-flew-over-the-cuckoos-nest-1975"&gt;One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-only-son-1936"&gt;The Only Son&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ordet-1955"&gt;Ordet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-orpheus-1949"&gt;Orpheus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-out-of-the-past-1947"&gt;Out of the Past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pale-flower-1964"&gt;Pale Flower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pans-labyrinth-2006"&gt;Pan's Labyrinth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pandoras-box-1928"&gt;Pandora's Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-paris-texas-1984"&gt;Paris, Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-passion-of-joan-of-arc-1928"&gt;The Passion of Joan of Arc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-paths-of-glory-1957"&gt;Paths of Glory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-patton-1970"&gt;Patton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-peeping-tom-1960"&gt;Peeping Tom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-persona-1966"&gt;Persona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-phantom-of-the-opera-1925"&gt;The Phantom of the Opera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pickpocket-1959"&gt;Pickpocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-picnic-at-hanging-rock-1975"&gt;Picnic at Hanging Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pink-floyd-the-wall-1982"&gt;Pink Floyd: The Wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pinocchio-1940"&gt;Pinocchio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pixote-1981"&gt;Pixote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-planes-trains-and-automobiles-1987"&gt;Planes, Trains and Automobiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-playtime-1967"&gt;Playtime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-pledge-2001"&gt;The Pledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/a-prairie-home-companion-2006-1"&gt;A Prairie Home Companion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-producers-1968"&gt;The Producers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-psycho-1960"&gt;Psycho&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-pulp-fiction-1994"&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raging-bull-1980"&gt;Raging Bull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raiders-of-the-lost-ark-1981"&gt;Raiders of the Lost Ark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-raise-the-red-lantern-1990"&gt;Raise the Red Lantern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ran-1985"&gt;Ran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rashomon-1950"&gt;Rashomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rear-window-1954"&gt;Rear Window&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rebel-without-a-cause-1955"&gt;Rebel Without a Cause&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-red-beard-1965"&gt;Red Beard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-red-river-1948"&gt;Red River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-red-shoes-1948"&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/richard-iii-1996-1"&gt;Richard III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rififi-1954"&gt;Rififi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-right-stuff-1983"&gt;The Right Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/rio-bravo-1959"&gt;Rio Bravo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ripleys-game-2002"&gt;Ripley's Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-rocco-and-his-brothers-1960"&gt;Rocco and His Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-romeo-and-juliet-1968"&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-rules-of-the-game-1939"&gt;The Rules of the Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-safety-last-1923"&gt;Safety Last&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-samurai-rebellion-1967"&gt;Samurai Rebellion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sansho-the-bailiff-1954"&gt;Sansho the Bailiff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-santa-sangre-1989"&gt;Santa Sangre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-saturday-night-fever-1977"&gt;Saturday Night Fever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-say-anything-1989"&gt;Say Anything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-scarface-1983"&gt;Scarface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-scarlet-empress-1934"&gt;The Scarlet Empress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-schindlers-list-1993"&gt;Schindler's List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-searchers-1956"&gt;The Searchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/secrets-and-lies-1996-1"&gt;Secrets &amp;amp; Lies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-senso-1954"&gt;Senso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-seven-1995"&gt;Seven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-seven-samurai-1954"&gt;The Seven Samurai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-seventh-seal-1957"&gt;The Seventh Seal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shadow-of-a-doubt-1943"&gt;Shadow of a Doubt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shane-1953"&gt;Shane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-shawshank-redemption-1994"&gt;The Shawshank Redemption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-shining-1980"&gt;The Shining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-shoah-1985"&gt;Shoah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-silence-of-the-lambs-1991"&gt;The Silence of the Lambs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-silence-1963"&gt;The Silence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-singin-in-the-rain-1952"&gt;Singin' in the Rain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-smiles-of-a-summer-night-1955"&gt;Smiles of a Summer Night&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-snow-white-and-the-seven-dwarfs-1937"&gt;Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-solaris-1972"&gt;Solaris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-some-like-it-hot-1959"&gt;Some Like It Hot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/souls-for-sale-1923"&gt;Souls For Sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-spirit-of-the-beehive-1973"&gt;Spirit of the Beehive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-spirited-away-2002"&gt;Spirited Away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/spring-summer-fall-winter_and-spring-2003"&gt;Spring, Summer, Fall, Winter and Spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-stagecoach-1939"&gt;Stagecoach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope-1977"&gt;Star Wars (Episode IV: A New Hope)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-strangers-on-a-train-1951"&gt;Strangers on a Train&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-stroszek-1977"&gt;Stroszek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-sunday-in-the-country-1984"&gt;A Sunday in the Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sunrise-1928"&gt;Sunrise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-sunset-boulevard-1950"&gt;Sunset Boulevard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-superman-1978"&gt;Superman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-sweet-smell-of-success-1957"&gt;The Sweet Smell of Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-swing-time-1936"&gt;Swing Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-tale-of-winter-1992"&gt;A Tale of Winter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-taxi-driver-1976"&gt;Taxi Driver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-tender-mercies-1983"&gt;Tender Mercies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-terrorist-2000"&gt;The Terrorist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-thief-of-bagdad-1940"&gt;The Thief of Bagdad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-thin-man-1934"&gt;The Thin Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-third-man-1949"&gt;The Third Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-this-is-spinal-tap-1984"&gt;This Is Spinal Tap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-three-colors-trilogy-blue-white-red"&gt;Three Colors Trilogy: Blue, White, Red&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-3-women-1977"&gt;3 Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-through-a-glass-darkly-1961"&gt;Through a Glass Darkly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-tokyo-story-1953"&gt;Tokyo Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-top-hat-1935"&gt;Top Hat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-touch-of-evil-1958"&gt;Touch of Evil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-touchez-pas-au-grisbi-1954"&gt;Touchez Pas au Grisbi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-treasure-of-the-sierra-madre-1948"&gt;The Treasure of the Sierra Madre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-triumph-of-the-will-1935"&gt;Triumph of the Will&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-trouble-in-paradise-1932"&gt;Trouble in Paradise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/25th-hour-2002"&gt;25th Hour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-2001-a-space-odyssey-1968"&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-ugetsu-1953"&gt;Ugetsu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-umberto-d-1952"&gt;Umberto D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-unforgiven-1992"&gt;Unforgiven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-up-documentaries-1985"&gt;The Up Documentaries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/vengeance-is-mine-2008"&gt;Vengeance Is Mine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-veronika-voss-1982"&gt;Veronika Voss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-vertigo-1958"&gt;Vertigo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-victim-1961"&gt;Victim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-viridiana-1961"&gt;Viridiana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-vivre-sa-vie--my-life-to-live-1963"&gt;Vivre sa Vie / My Life to Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/waking-life-2001-1"&gt;Waking Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-walkabout-1971"&gt;Walkabout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/werckmeister-harmonies-2000"&gt;Werckmeister Harmonies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-west-side-story-1961"&gt;West Side Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-what-ever-happened-to-baby-jane-1962"&gt;What Ever Happened to Baby Jane?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-wild-bunch-1969"&gt;The Wild Bunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-wings-of-desire-1988"&gt;Wings of Desire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-winter-light-1962"&gt;Winter Light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/withnail-and-i-1987"&gt;Withnail &amp;amp; I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-the-wizard-of-oz-1939"&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-woman-in-the-dunes-1964"&gt;Woman in the Dunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-woman-under-the-influence-1974"&gt;A Woman Under the Influence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-womans-tale-1992"&gt;A Woman's Tale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-woodstock-1970"&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-wr-mysteries-of-the-organism-1971"&gt;WR -- Mysteries of the Organism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-written-on-the-wind-1956"&gt;Written on the Wind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yankee-doodle-dandy-1942"&gt;Yankee Doodle Dandy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-a-year-of-the-quiet-sun-1984"&gt;A Year of the Quiet Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yellow-submarine-1968"&gt;Yellow Submarine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/great-movie-yojimbo-1961"&gt;Yojimbo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="small"&gt;(and a cache of them &lt;a href="http://sivers.s3.amazonaws.com/ebert.zip"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, just in case)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Learning JavaScript - my experience and advice</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/learn-js</id>
    <updated>2013-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/learn-js"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Since I've &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/prog"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/os"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; that I just learned JavaScript over the last few months, a bunch of people have emailed to ask what I used and recommend to learn it. So here's my experience and best advice for 2013.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
NOTE: I wanted to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; learn JavaScript - not shortcuts, quick tricks, or meta-tools&lt;/strong&gt; that keep me from having to learn JavaScript. I want to learn it, get it, read it, understand it, and memorize it, so that I can understand all the other cool things written in JavaScript for years to come.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First - a bunch of people will tell you to get &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do"&gt;JavaScript: The Good Parts - by Douglas Crockford&lt;/a&gt;. But when I started reading it, it was so dense and succinct that I had no idea what it was talking about!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You know when an expert is talking about their field, and don't know how to simplify it for just anyone? Well, this book felt like it'd be perfect for someone who's been programming for 20 years in C, Java, and C++, and just needs a quick overview of what they should know about JavaScript.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But it doesn't really TEACH you. It doesn't guide you through anything. So I recommend skipping it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Instead, &lt;strong&gt;start with &lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/"&gt;Eloquent JavaScript - by Marijn Haverbeke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It starts so simple, so easy, almost too simple, but this is encouraging. You get your swagger back as you say, “This is easy!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/contents.html"&gt;Do the online version, here&lt;/a&gt;, because you can test and experiment directly in your browser.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then, after a few chapters of that, &lt;strong&gt;switch over to &lt;a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html"&gt;Professional JavaScript for Web Developers, 3rd Edition - by Nicholas Zakas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;THAT is the ultimate tutorial.&lt;/strong&gt; It takes the time to explain everything thoroughly, and it covers pretty much everything. Put aside a few hours per chapter, and &lt;strong&gt;by the time you're done with this one book, you'll know as much as most people who call themselves JavaScript programmers.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Funny thing is, I went back to &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do"&gt;JavaScript: The Good Parts&lt;/a&gt; after finishing this one, and now I understood it. But because &lt;a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html"&gt;Professional JavaScript for Web Developers&lt;/a&gt; was so thorough, it had already covered all of the “good parts”, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course &lt;strong&gt;you have to retain what you're learning&lt;/strong&gt;, so I highly recommend you &lt;strong&gt;write down every new thing you learn&lt;/strong&gt;, ideally into a flashcard program, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;. It's a lot to take in, so you'll have to remind yourself of what you've learned in the weeks and months afterwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
If you're in the mood for more books to really solidify JavaScript in your head, go through:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596806149.do"&gt;JavaScript Cookbook - by Shelley Powers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://effectivejs.com/"&gt;Effective JavaScript - by David Herman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/resig/"&gt;Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja - by John Resig and Bear Bibeault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All of these are great, and you'll notice you go through them much faster now that you're fluent. Do the examples. Play around.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Read some real-world JavaScript code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After a thousand pages of tiny example code snippets, you'll love looking at the code to two very popular and powerful JavaScript projects:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://underscorejs.org/docs/underscore.html"&gt;Underscore.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org/docs/backbone.html"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You'll notice that it all makes sense, now. You're now functionally fluent in reading and understanding JavaScript.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Then jQuery, and more...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://jquery.com/"&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt; is absolutely everywhere, and you must learn it for your JavaScript tutorial to be complete.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now that you've learned the plain-JavaScript long and verbose way of doing things, you'll appreciate the shortcuts that jQuery provides.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I really liked &lt;a href="http://www.headfirstlabs.com/books/hfjquery/"&gt;Head First jQuery&lt;/a&gt;, as goofy as it is. It walks you through jQuery wonderfully well, and has you apply what you've learned, as you go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And if you're still hungry to learn more JavaScript, dive into:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://coffeescript.org/"&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920024309.do"&gt;The Little Book on CoffeeScript - by Alex MacCaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org/"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://javascriptissexy.com/learn-backbone-js-completely/"&gt;following this path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://javascriptissexy.com/learn-node-js-completely-and-with-confidence/"&gt;following this path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Then put down the books and go use it!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You would think this goes without saying, but if I didn't say it, someone would complain. So look at your existing sites, and go apply what you've learned.  Or start a new site from scratch and make it all with JavaScript, even if just as an experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Any other suggestions? What worked for you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well... that's what I did, and I'm quite happy with the results.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please share any other suggestions or experiences, here:
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Human Intervention as a Competitive Advantage</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/hi</id>
    <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/hi"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The listening algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A year after I started CD Baby, when it was still just me in my bedroom, the CEO and VP of a hugely-funded Silicon Valley online music company contacted me, saying they wanted to fly out to New York to meet me.  I said OK, and we met a week later for dinner.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Dinner was a lot of blah blah blah smalltalk, and I wondered what they really wanted.  Then they finally got to the real point:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“The reason we flew out to meet you is because we’ve been looking at many music recommendation engines, and the one that’s powering cdbaby.com is one of the best we’ve found.  Could you tell us a little something about the algorithms and data points you’re using?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Uh...  I was confused, and asked what they meant.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They said, “The «if you like this you will like that» recommendations. We’ve been testing them on your site, but they don’t seem to be sales-driven like Amazon. The music-matching algorithm comes up with incredible recommendations. What software are you using for that?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ah!  I get it.  I smiled and pointed to my ear.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“No software. &lt;strong&gt;I just listen to everything that comes in, and recommend other good stuff like it.&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now they looked confused.  “&lt;strong&gt;But how will that scale?&lt;/strong&gt;  You can’t just listen to every single album!  What will you do when you start getting a hundred albums a day?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I said, “Maybe hire someone just to listen.  I don’t know.  I’m not there yet.  I’ll worry about it then.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(And that’s what I did, when we were getting a hundred albums a day. The coolest full-time job in the world went to Pamela Rooney, who would listen to every new arrival, and do the internal recommendations.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Minimizing or Maximizing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;When everyone else is trying to automate everything, using a little human intervention can be a competitive advantage.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The problem is when business owners see it as a cost, instead of an opportunity.  &lt;strong&gt;Trying to minimize costs, instead of maximize income, quality, loyalty, happiness, connection, and all those other wonderful things that come from real human attention.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can buy a fancy phone routing system, so people have to listen to 9 options, choose option 5, then listen to 6 more options...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... or ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... you can hire a charming person to pick up the phone on the first ring, and make a great impression.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Which one do you think will win you new fans?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can put rules into your online forms, so if someone puts a dash in their phone number, or writes “coming soon” as their URL, it tells them they’re wrong and makes them do it over again....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... or ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
... you can have new submissions be checked-over quickly by a real person.  It’s worth the 10 seconds of human effort, to &lt;strong&gt;keep the end-user experience easy&lt;/strong&gt; but the internal data correct.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s fun for techies to try to find the tech solution to everything, but don’t forget that even a tiny touch from a real person can be the best alogrithm, and a massive business maximizer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who should do the work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I get the mindset.  It’s saying, “By having our software and our users do most of the work, we can keep our business efficient and scalable.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you want them to pay you, if you want to be more valuable, you have to &lt;a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/schlep.html"&gt;take on more of that work&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I meet so many entrepreneurs who are convinced their thing will be as big as Facebook, so they can’t afford to have a personal touch for all those BILLIONS of users that are going to start flowing through their app.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But by removing all human contact, they’re making their app less valuable, so that they’ll never get big enough for it “how does it scale?” to matter.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/carrying_crate.png" alt="carrying crate" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Changing my operating system</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/os</id>
    <updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/os"/>
    <content type="html">﻿&lt;p&gt;
A few months ago, I did &lt;a href="http://foolishadventure.com/audio/derek-sivers-fa132/"&gt;an interview with Tim Conley from Foolish Adventure&lt;/a&gt; on the subject of “changing your operating system” - my metaphor for making deep changes in my life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I got a bunch of emails from people who really seem to like it, so the brilliant &lt;a href="http://emarmusic.com/"&gt;Melissa Rebronja&lt;/a&gt; transcribed it, below.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You can &lt;a href="http://sivers.s3.amazonaws.com/fa132-derek-sivers-success-mindset.mp3"&gt;download the MP3 of the hour-long conversation, here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - or just read the transcript, below.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He brought up some interesting subjects, so I'd love to hear your thoughts or feedback. Leave a comment here, or &lt;a href="mailto:derek@sivers.org"&gt;email me at derek@sivers.org&lt;/a&gt; anytime. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;0:25&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tim:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Welcome to another &lt;a href="http://foolishadventure.com/audio/derek-sivers-fa132/"&gt;episode of The Foolish Adventure Show&lt;/a&gt;. I’m your host, Tim Conley and I’ve got a very special guest here. Mr. Derek Sivers of CD Baby fame, who had sold his company in 2008, which we’re not actually gonna talk about here. There are plenty of interviews of Derek out there about the rise and the sale of CD Baby. But what we’re gonna talk about the time between the sale and now. This is going to be more of a mindset episode and not a how-to episode. So, what’s up Derek?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;1:00&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Derek:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hi Tim! What’s funny is that when I sold CD Baby, I thought that my greatest hits were behind me. You know like somebody who had a hit single in the 80s and that’s all they will ever be known for. I thought it would go onto my gravestone. “Here lies Derek Sivers. He made CD Baby and that’s about it.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/speakers/derek_sivers.html"&gt;I spoke at all the TED conferences&lt;/a&gt;, a year after I sold CD Baby, and now I’m actually more known for that. As I go around the world, everybody’s like, “Hey, you’re that first follower dancing leadership guy from TED! Rock on Dude!” Then people sometimes ask, “So what do you do besides speak at TED?” That’s all they know me for now!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;1:45&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So the sale happened in 2008 and from the stuff that I heard you just wanted to decompress from that. So where did you go? What happened to Derek after the sale?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;2:00&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don’t know if it was decompress as much as de-brainwash. In short, &lt;strong&gt;I wanted to change my operating system&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think all of us have a way that we do things. Say when you’re like a teenager or early 20s, you’re constantly learning new things, growing, changing everything, deciding what your major is gonna be, then going out into the world and getting jobs, doing things, and changing wildly all the time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then people often hit a point in their 30s or so, where they just say, “Well this is who I am. This is the way I do things.”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;2:37&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ah, that just gave me shivers! Ah, that doesn’t feel good at all!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;2:41&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah! You know, “This is the way I like my eggs. This is the kind of music I like. This is my favorite team. This is where I live. This is what kind of person I am. I’m a social person, or I enjoy a beer on a Friday. This is who I am.” And people get that weird kind of stuck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here’s a version of that in the music business: I would go to these music conferences and I’d be invited to speak on a panel. It’s always a panel. And the moderator would ask: “What is the future of the music business?” The guy who’s in the business of selling MP3s would say “The future is selling MP3s! People want to buy MP3s”, and the guy who’s in the business of streaming radio would say: “People don’t want MP3s! People just wanna turn on radio but have it world-wide.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then they’d turn to me, and I was in the business of selling CDs and distributing things, so they’d expect me to say that the future is that. But all I could say is: “Look nobody knows the future. Nobody! Ben Bernanke doesn’t know the future of the world economy and he controls it! So even the people who control this stuff don’t know it. The record labels don’t know the future of the music industry and they somewhat control it. Nobody knows! And anybody who claims to know if full of shit and not to be trusted! Because they’re obviously not thinking clearly or being honest if they claim to know what the future is. Because they don’t. So if they’re opening their mouths and telling you what the future is, they’re lying. They’re not being honest. Or if they think they know, then they’ve deluded themselves or not thinking clearly.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I felt that at CD Baby &lt;strong&gt;I had been seeing the world through one point of view for 10 years&lt;/strong&gt;. I was immersed in my world of independent musicians mailing me a box of CDs directly and having me sell the physical CDs and distribute the digital files off to iTunes, Amazon, Napster, Rhapsody, etc. And that was my whole world for 10 years. I was very head-down at work on that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The day I sold CD Baby, I went to sleep that night with an empty head and a big smile. I was like, “Wow! 10 years of my life. I’m done. I’ve moved on.” It was like graduation day. Wow, I just finished. I went to sleep that night so empty headed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I woke up the next day, had breakfast and by lunch I had a great idea for my next company. And I started sketching it out. It’s called Muckwork. It’s gonna be this service firm, that’s like a professional network of assistants that are already pre-trained to help musicians with all the things that musicians need help with, so that musicians don’t need to kind of micro-manage them. They can just dump their problems on us and we’ll take care of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I was so excited about this idea that I immediately, like that day - January 18th is the day that I had the agreement to sell CD Baby, January 19th is the day that I woke up and had the Muckwork idea - (It’s kind of cute that you can see if you do the “whois” on the domain name, that everything was registered on January 19th, the day I had the idea.) Programming and coding, I registered the domain name, I did all the programming. I worked on that for a few months. I even hired a manager, and I was just about to launch it....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I had the feeling that &lt;strong&gt;I hadn’t yet changed my operating system&lt;/strong&gt;. “If I do this, it’s going to be like CD Baby part 2. Like my life will not change!” Same guy doing the same thing in the same way, but just with a different company name over my head. I am too into the idea of personal growth and development to do something like that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, I kind of just quickly looked at my situation before charging people’s credit cards and beginning. Once somebody pays me the first dollar, I’m on the hook to deliver. And wait a second: I don’t know if I want that yet. So, that’s when I kind of intentionally put the brakes on it. I let go of the manager I hired. Luckily he’d only been working for me for a few weeks, so it was no hard feelings. And I lifted my head up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I often think of life as having different phases. Sometimes you’re just head down and just working. And then sometimes you lift your head up and look around and see what’s up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;7:03&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So when you did this lifting your head up and taking a look around, doing a complete operating system reboot would be pretty difficult for any human, because we are so ingrained in our culture, our language, that sometimes even dictates our behaviours, and to do a complete reboot? What did you start with?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;7:23&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Reading lots of books. Lots of non-fiction books. Particularly a lot about psychology, behavioural economics, studies of happiness - which is a fascinating idea, I’d like to study it directly. Learning what makes people happy, and taking it to heart.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Y’know there’s a cognitive fallacy that we all have, where we think that statistics don’t apply to us. When you hear “9 out of 10 people bla bla bla” you think “Ha, well I’m that 1 out of 10” And we all have that. 90% of people think they are better than average drivers. People asked in a cancer ward in the hospital, 95% of cancer patients say that they are in better health than most cancer patients. So it’s amazing to think that 45% of them are wrong. Like half the people that think they’re better than average drivers are wrong! They are actually worse than average drivers!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then having to look at myself through this new fact. I think this is what I mean about changing your operating system. It’s &lt;strong&gt;taking in new knowledge and actually living by it, applying it&lt;/strong&gt;. Not just reading and going “Hm, alright, well that’s interesting,” then going back to my normal way of doing things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;8:39&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So to be able to apply that… Let’s take happiness. I find that very interesting because we all have concepts of what’s going to make us happy, even while we’re not currently happy. So we have that, and when you read something about how you can be happy, the act of being happy. How do you put that into your life? And this is from somebody who’s now technically retired, right? What did you do that you could make use of that knowledge? Build a framework? Or just sit back and think happy thoughts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;9:11&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I guess that’s where your personal preferences come in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Even in Buddhism, I never understood people who just sit in a temple on top of a mountain or under the Bodhi Tree and just sit there and smile. That’s not enough for me because I’d feel useless in the world if I’m just sitting there being happy. What’s amazing is that just a couple of months ago I went to Thailand, I didn’t even realize there was such a thing as active Buddhism. I’m not an expert on this, but apparently there is a whole chunk of people that believe in applied Buddhism, like this idea of be happy and go out and do things that improve the world. That it’s not enough to just sit there and be happy and meditate. Yes mediate, find your peace, and then go out and make the world a better place. So that’s the one that appealed to me more.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But I felt like &lt;strong&gt;I needed to shatter my habits&lt;/strong&gt;. So my little mini slogan was, “Wherever you used to say ‘yes’ say ‘no’ and wherever you used to say ‘no’ say ‘yes’.” Reversing all of the things you used to do and trying the opposite.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;10:25&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I want everybody that’s listening to actually think about that right now. Think about what it would feel like to actually say “yes” to something that you would normally say “no” to. I guarantee you, there’s going to be a twinge of fear, because that’s scary as it can be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;10:38&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oh, absolutely! Well, that’s the whole point. If you’re not scared, you’re doing something wrong! The whole point is to find the fear.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ve had this slogan ever since I was a teenager. “&lt;strong&gt;Whatever scares you, go do it&lt;/strong&gt;.” I would use that even on a little micro level. I see the gorgeous girl across the room and I’m like “Ahhh!” terrified to talk to her! Then I remember, “Whatever scares you go do it! So here we go..” and I would just walk up to the girl that intimidates me and say hello. Then of course she’s wonderful or not, whatever it is, but I walk away no longer scared. Now I just have that approach through life. I think whatever scares you go do it, because then it won’t scare you anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I had never had an interest in travelling. I had never had an interest in anything but working. I was absolutely - from the age of 14 until 38 - just a workaholic. In college my nickname was “the Robot”. The guys would tease me that I wouldn’t even join them for dinner. The cafeteria had free meals. I went to Berklee School of Music. Everybody would stop for an hour at 6:00 and hang out and eat whatever the cafeteria food was. But I would just breeze through there, and slap some peanut butter and jam on some bread, grab some carrots sticks and throw it in my backpack and head up to the practice room. Friends were like: “Dude.. Common man, hang out!”  But I'd say, “I don’t wanna hang out. I gotta work. I gotta practice.” I was always the first guy in the practice rooms in the morning and the last guy there at night. Everybody was going out to parties on the weekend and I would take that opportunity to read next year’s assignment, and do my homework in advance. So I was that guy that would get teased for never relaxing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So to me, the idea of going to India for a month and walking around and experiencing it was so against my grain, y’know? That’s not me! That’s not what I do! So, therefore that’s what I need to do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There were a bunch of examples that are like that. I just did a bunch of things that were not me, in the name of learning and growing, experiencing new things. The most obvious one that people point at is my wife.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I met this gorgeous girl in NYC. She was born in India, grew up in a Muslim family, and we had only been together a few months when I said, “Come out to California with me. Let me get you out of NYC. Come hang out with me there.”  Because that’s where I lived. That’s my place!  And she said: “Well I can’t. My Mom still thinks I’m a virgin. I can’t go with you unless we’re married.” I was like, “Hmm, married huh? I can do that.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So we had a Muslim wedding. And to make her parents happy I said a few syllables. In fact I Googled “How to convert to Islam” and apparently all you have to do is say these two sentences. I just memorized them phonetically. It’s just “Ash hadu alla ilaha illallah. Ash hadu anna muhammadar rasulullah.“ You say that in front of another Muslim and you have now converted. That’s it. So I read that, and I was like. ”Pffft! I can do that!“ I’m cracking up. Oh wow, I’m gonna do that. This is ridiculous. I was like ”OK, here we go.“
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the name of changing my operating system, it’s not like I’m gonna actually adopt new beliefs or anything like that but the change for me there was actually doing something that is not me to make someone else happy. I had never done that. I’m a California kid. I had always been so proudly, defiantly individualistic. I only do things for me. Always the rebel. So the idea of me, even just having that understanding how this would make her parents very happy. If I say these two sentences. It would let them tell the relatives back in India that their daughter had a proper Muslim wedding. Means nothing to me, it means everything to them. So here we go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;14:56&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That’s something I’ve always had a problem with, is doing things that for some reason I am against, right? It doesn’t mean anything to me, so therefore I shouldn’t do it. And that it something I’ve struggled with, is opening up and allowing other people’s feelings to actually get into my life. And that is something that I still struggle with today, because I don’t actually see my self as actually that empathetic. To look at, oh, y’know what would this really mean to someone else and even further for you, for your wife. Yeah, you could understand it for her, but why that extra layer, y’know? The family, then even further afield, the family back home. For me, that’s always been a struggle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;15:40&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I guess this is what fiction is good at. I don’t read a lot of fiction books, but I do watch a lot of movies. And when done right, the whole idea is to help you get into somebody else’s head really, and understand their process. I guess when fiction is done deeply and done well, when books often excel beyond movies that need to keep things kind of short and entertaining, it’s this idea of &lt;strong&gt;really getting into someone else’s head&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like I don’t know right now whether you consider yourself liberal or conservative, but what’s fascinating is that all the places I lived were just extremely liberal. I lived in NYC, Los Angeles, San Francisco, Portland, Seattle. Y’know, all of the bluest parts of the bluest states, right? Then it was kind of cool starting to have friends, that were extremely conservative, and even going off on the whole Obama birth certificate thing. Having those people actually be friends of mine, that I love and care about. It’s kind of fascinating to get into the whole different mindset. Because it’s not just about the president. It’s like a whole different world view of the way things should be. And getting back to traditional values and all that. Whereas I’m always trying to get rid of traditional values. And how do you even stay dear friends with somebody that looks at the world in different ways? Well, you get into their head.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I guess we all have different sides to ourselves. Like, even if you’re 99% a certain way, like say introvert/extrovert or something, most people will say: “Well I’m kind of both. I’m mostly introvert, but sometimes I like to go out and be with lots of people.” It’s kind of like that. You can understand the other way of looking at things, even if it’s a smaller part of you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I guess now is a good time to transition into talking about world-travelling, huh?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;17:37&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, because having a world view and having it change. That is something that impacted me as well, when I left home. I couldn’t wait to leave home. I grew up in rural southern Illinois. And I knew that the world was awesome, because I could see it on TV.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;17:52&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And then you found out you were allowed to leave!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;17:54&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah. But I grew up really not knowing how to leave. And my only thought was: “Oh, I’ll join the military.” So I looked around at what was available for militarily service. I was like OK, I don’t wanna be on the front lines, so the Marines and Army are out. I don’t wanna be stuck on a ship with a bunch of dudes for six months, because I like the ladies a little too much, and back then there were very few women deployed on the ship. And didn’t want to join the Coast Guard, because well that wouldn’t get me overseas to a certain extent, and I didn’t want to be involved in the drug war, because that’s pretty dangerous living too. And so that left the Air Force. So I joined the Air Force to travel the World, and they sent me to Texas and then to Arizona. And I had to travel on my own dime.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But one of the great things that really helped me out was that I grew up in a very racist area of Southern Illinois called… Southern Illinois! LOL. I always knew there was something wrong with racism. I didn’t know what it was, but I alway knew there was something wrong with it. And then I got into the military, and it was fantastic. Because I met the very first Puerto Rican man I’d ever known and he was just a couple of bunks away from me. Met my first Filipino man. And being able to become very close friends with Blacks, Hispanics, Asians, it was amazing. It was one of the most eye opening experiences of my life. That really rebooted my operating system, because I knew mine was kind of broken. And then I got into that one and then the military said. “Oh no, you’re not going to act like that. That is un-acceptable behavior in this environment,” and it was amazing. I loved it. And so then world travel really broke some of the cultural scripts that I had been ingrained with growing up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So did you travel a lot up until you said you were working a lot? So did you travel much when you sold the company?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;19:57&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No. I had the lucky benefit of when I was 5 years old, we lived in Abingdon, England for a year, because of my Dad’s work. And while we were in England we spent a lot of time in Sicily, Madrid and Paris.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
At the age of 6 I moved to Hinsdale, Illinois, about 25 miles outside of Chicago. That’s where I went to grade school and high school and stuff. So I guess you can say that’s mostly where I kind of grew up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I moved from England to Hinsdale, even though I considered my self a California kid, I had an English accent from living in England for a year. Everybody called me “the English kid”! I was like (in an English accent): “I’m not from England, I’m from California! Mummy, tell them. Oh God, I hate England! No I’m from California!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I guess I’ve always at least had an awareness that there’s a world out there that you could actually live in and not just vacation in.  But no, except for that thing when I was 5 years old, I had not travelled at all.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I travelled a lot around the US. I lived a few years each in Chicago, Boston, New York, Woodstock, Portland, Santa Monica, San Francisco and Seattle.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But when you’re in America, you feel that you’re at the center of everything. Because whether it’s Hollywood, the media, every movie, every TV show, everything is set in America. Everybody has American accents, except for the occasional odd foreign film or something.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;21:15&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And all the aliens invade the United States!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;21:19&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Exactly! That’s where they go, they’re not invading Uruguay. So, you can feel you’re in the middle of everything.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What’s amazing is that after leaving, culturally and in many ways, I realizes America is off on one far extreme of whatever chart you make. America is a very extreme end of things. One extreme end it’s not the middle.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I was almost 40 years old, and I had really spent my whole life in the US, except for that one year when I was 5. So that was a big inspiration for me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’m on this mission to change the way I think, and move ahead in life instead of getting stuck in ruts. Especially when you sell a company and it’s like “Now I’m rich.” It’s so easy to just get stuck in a rut and be the cliché guy either drinking his margaritas for life or being the sad ex-success. Like somebody who had a big hit long ago and now is just stuck in those glory years. Y’know? The 80s musician trying to do things the 80s way still.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I wanted to make it impossible for me to get stuck in a rut. So my mission was to spend the rest of my life outside of the US, mainly because I loved it too much.&lt;/strong&gt; Santa Monica in particular. When I got to Santa Monica, I just felt “This is it, I have arrived. Like I love this place. I love these people. I love the food. I love the weather. I love everything. This is it. This is my home. This is where I belong.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But that feeling kind of scares me, because it’s like that thing when people get to a certain age and say “This is who I am. This is how I like my eggs. This is where I live.” I didn’t feel it was time to stop progressing, even in my physical location. So my challenge to my self is to live the rest of my life outside the US, because I love California too much.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I went to New York City for 3 days, passing through for a friend’s wedding, and I met this gorgeous girl and we had this great first date, we’re all swooning over each other. So on our second date I said, “How would you feel about leaving the US and never coming back?” She looked at me for a second, kind of squinted and said, “Yeah, I could do that.” And so then we had a third date and that’s my wife.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She’s joined me on this mission to spend the rest of our life out of the US, even if it’s uncomfortable. Even if it’d just be the easy and comfortable thing to just go back to Santa Monica to what I know well. It’s the idea of kind of forcing yourself to keep progressing. And so far we’ve only lived in pretty comfortable places. I mean we’ve lived in Singapore…
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;24:40&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
… one of the most modern places in the world!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;24:44&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, exactly! Everybody speaks English. She grew up in NYC, so Singapore’s another big city. It’s very easy and comfortable for her. The bigger challenge is the idea of this being a stepping stone to the idea of living somewhere like Brazil or Taiwan, and the idea of staying long enough until even that feels like your comfort zone. Can you imagine?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Right now I don’t speak Portuguese, I don’t know hardly anything about Brazil. But could you &lt;strong&gt;imagine what it would do for your life to move down there and put up with some initial discomfort and stay until it becomes your comfort zone&lt;/strong&gt;, so that Brazil just feels like home? And Portuguese - you’ve forgotten that’s it’s your second language, cause it feels like your first, and all your friends are there, and you get it, and the mindset feels like your comfort zone?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And even better, that once you get to that point, &lt;strong&gt;then you do it again&lt;/strong&gt;. Then you go to Taiwan. And at first it’s uncomfortable and it’s difficult, and then you slowly adapt and then it feels like home. And then you go to Berlin and do it again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;25:51&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, I found that when traveling I get drawn to comfort zones, where expats are everywhere. When you’re totally out of your element, like my first trip into Asia, I’m as shiny white as can be, and I was about a good 6 inches taller than everyone around me, and I was just being stared at. I’m riding on a bus in rural Sri Lanka and I’m being stared at and touched. It was a really weird experience. So that culture shock really drew me to hanging around other travellers, because it felt comfortable. Even though Americans try to pretend like we’re not much like the Europeans, but we’re very close. As soon as you travel you find out just how closely aligned we really are. And I’m hangin out with Europeans and everything and I’m thinkin’ “Oh man, how cultural of me” right? Where I’m hangin’ out with a guy from France and a woman from Germany and all this yet not hanging out with the people that I actually came to see.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, how do you break from that comfort zone when you’re travelling?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;26:56&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think the main difference is to &lt;strong&gt;really live somewhere instead of visiting somewhere&lt;/strong&gt;. I mean you could do it short term, you could just make yourself talk to people that you’re perhaps intimidated by and give the patience to get deeper.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think whenever you first talk to somebody that’s very different from you, the first you thing you notice is difference in looks. You talked about racism, and the funny thing about racism is that you only notice somebody’s race for the first few minutes. Then it just disappears, and then you’re just talking to a person.  If somebody would to say: “Hey, who was that Chinese guy that you were talking to?”, you’d think “Oh him?” You’ve almost forgotten their race, because it’s just a person.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then to me the next level is the accent or the language differences. That takes a little longer to get past. To kind of hear through the language barrier and communicate heart-to-heart, despite your missing words or misunderstood vowels. Then you can do that when travelling. Like even if you just go somewhere for a week.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I went to India for the first time, at first I was terrified. Mostly thanks to a panic-stricken friend of mine who had been there once years ago and right before I left warned me that it was the most horrible place on Earth and that people are gonna be clawing at me and yanking money out of my pockets. Terrified me. So I went there with my guard up fully, right? Like prepared to be attacked. And I kind of hid at first. I hid in my hotel room. I’d go on little walks around then I’d go back to my hotel room and read a book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It wasn’t until my last week there that I pulled up my CD Baby database and I emailed some musicians that lived in Calcutta. “Hey I coming through Calcutta for a week, would you like to meet up?” Until then I was scared of doing that, y’know I just wanted to be alone. So I set up like three different meeting with three different musicians from Calcutta. And with each of the three people we sat around and talked for hours. Unfortunately it was my last week there. I wish it was my first week, because then I finally got it. Then I kind of felt like…
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;29:20&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
… it would’ve changed your whole experience had it been earlier?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah! They spoke English. And, yes they had the accents, but y’know that disappears after a while. You hear through it after a while. We were sitting there having a really great heart-to-heart talk. It was this bass player from Calcutta and he was telling me about life in Calcutta, and the music scene there. Dude, I felt like I was hangin’ with somebody from Illinois. Y’know? It just felt as home as anything. And that was only just one week in India.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now imagine that you decide to live somewhere, which is even a self definition thing. Like “I’m living here.” vs “I’m visiting here.” So when people say: “Where are you from?” you say: “Well, I live here now, but I moved here from the US” or something. It’s just a different status. But then it’s getting to know people deeper, having a circle of friends that you hang out with and you see each other every week. Get to know them dearly. Yes, they grew up in a very different environment than you, but you find your common ground. And this to me was the cool thing about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So we &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/singapore"&gt;moved to Singapore&lt;/a&gt; two and half years ago. It’s an interesting hybrid where it has all the modern amenities. It has drinkable water and fast internet and stuff. It’s a very comfortable place to visit. Everything works. It will feel familiar enough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But man, under the surface, there are some deep world-view differences. Actually my best friends in Singapore are native Singaporean. They’re very Christian. They are very conservative. And the Asian mindset: It’s one thing to have somebody tell you the Asian mindset is more collective than individualistic. (I’ve heard that a lot in my life and I kind of went “yeah, yeah, OK, whatever. ”) But to really get to know that mindset and to have people that you know and care about tell you that they chose a profession that they didn’t want to do because it was good for the family. My first reaction as an individualistic American is to say: “No, that’s wrong. You gotta stand up for what you wanna do man. What you wanna do is important!” But to understand that no, that isn’t right. That’s one way of looking at things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That’s that whole thing I was talking about where America is kind of off onto one far end of the spectrum of individualism. Whereas a lot of the world values things much more by how good they are for the group. In Singapore in particular, the priorities are what’s good for your country and what’s good for your family. Only one or two generations ago, most people in Singapore were in poverty. It’s really lifted itself out of poverty in just a generation or two.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So when the parents say: “No, you’re not going to be a poet, you’re going to go to a good university and you’re going to get a good paying job at a bank.” It’s kind of non-negotiable, because you’re expected to take care of your parents. There is no social security that’s going to take care of your parents when you’re older. It’s up to the children to take care of the parents. So if you say: “I’m just gonna follow my passion and be a poet,” you’ve just told your parents that they might die sooner than they would’ve if you could take care of them well. It affects the whole group. And so you do what’s best for the group, not just what’s best for you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I thought of a good way to explain this to a friend of mine. A friend of mine was having a hard time understanding this where it all sounded too high-level. So I said, OK, imagine if you found a car unlocked and the keys were left in it. And somebody were to say: “Hey Dude, you should totally steal that car”. And you say, “What are you, insane?” Like that’s just wrong. Why is that wrong? Well because it’s bad for society. It’s not what you do. That’s stealing from someone else. &lt;strong&gt;You have to be a sociopath to think like that&lt;/strong&gt;. Well, that’s the way it seems to be too individualistic in Asia - you’re seen as somewhat of a sociopath. If you say: “Well yeah, I wanna be a poet, even though my parents want me to be a banker.” It’s a little bit like stealing a car and driving away. It’s just bad for the group. It’s bad for everyone. Why would you do this silly idea of following your dreams when you can do the thing that’s best for the group. You know what I mean?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;33:52&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah. One of my closest friends in University was from Taiwan. Over some drinks he admitted to me that he was being very selfish, he was dragging out his college education. We were both in Architecture School together and he was dragging it out. He’s like: “I really have to graduate within the next couple of years, because I have to go back and I have to start adding to the family estate.” He’s like: “I’m the oldest and I’m also a son. I have a ton of responsibility on me, so right now I’m kind of leeching off the family right now.” And he felt really bad about it. And for me as an American, I’m like: “Whatever. Like why would you even think like that? That’s insane.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It took me a while of being friends with him for several years to really understand just how much pressure he was under. Because here he is in the US to get a great education, but also being able to look around and say: “You know if I just stayed here, my life would be amazing.” But instead he knew he was going back to Taiwan and do his duty to his entire family. And I had huge respect for the guy by the time we finished school. I understood exactly where he was coming from and why it was important for him to go back and do what his family wanted. Even though he wanted something else that he could’ve got in the US.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;35:23&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yes! And what’s so hard to get over as an American, is to not think that that’s wrong! Y’know? I still, I find myself - even right now as we’re just talking about it - cringing and still feeling like “That’s wrong! He should stand up for himself and do what’s best for him!” But no, hold on, hold on. That’s my American roots talking. That’s just one way of looking at things. That’s my American point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My whole mission of not living in the US again - it’s because I feel like I’m already about American as I can possibly be. I get it. I lived in five corners of America. And it’s true, I haven’t lived in Mississippi or Montana yet, but for the most part I get it. I get America about as much as anyone can. And now it’s time to push out of that. So it’s still hard for me to get over my American way of looking at things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What’s so cool, is to have dear friends now that are the opposite. When I talk about my individualistic things, they cringe because they grew up in India or Singapore, and for them it’s so hard to get over the feeling that individualism and following your passion is wrong, y’know? It’s so cool to be really close to somebody that sees it from the other point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;36:43&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So the time you spent in Singapore - I read your recent post about global thinking vs local thinking and you had decided you were really gonna think local in Singapore. Was this business or music focused or was it a little more holistic?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;36:57&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It was holistic. It was just everything. It was entirely like, “I live here now.” I’m a permanent resident of Singapore. It’s the equivalent of getting a Green Card in the US. I’ve got permanent residency in Singapore. I might even get citizenship someday. I’m here. So, I want to get to know my community. I want to be a part of the community, and just immerse myself totally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For the last two years, I’ve been totally immersed into the community of Singapore. Mostly just giving, in every way I can. I was immediately, upon moving here, tapped by every university, group, &lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg/"&gt;hackerspace&lt;/a&gt; and everything, asking, “Come speak to our group. Come speak to our class. Come speak to this. Come speak here.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I did a lot of speaking, a lot of mentoring, and a lot of meeting. I had hundreds of one-on-one meetings. I spent a few thousand hours of the last couple of years just sitting down one-on-one with people. Mostly just letting them pick my brain.  It’s always somebody else initiating it saying, “I’d really like to meet with you. I have this idea for a business. Can I pick your brain?” and I would just always say yes, because it’s like well, this is my new home, so yes!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I did really most of the last two years. Online I appeared to be pretty silent. Online people would say, “Hey Dude, I haven’t seen a new blog post from you in like 4 months!” But it’s because every day, for 6 or 8 hours a day, I’m giving to my local community here. Meeting with everybody that wants to meet with me and letting everyone pick my brain. Speaking to every group that asks me to speak.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think I finally had to admit slowly to my self that &lt;strong&gt;it was very one-sided&lt;/strong&gt;. Not 100% one-sided, because I definitely got something out of it. With every person I speak to, of course, I learn something as well. But the nature of the conversations, not quite as lopsided as this one where you said: “Can I interview you?” That’s designed to be a lopsided conversation. But sometimes they were almost this lopsided. Like people who had a bunch of questions that they wanted to ask me. Wanted to ask questions about what I had learned in life or from experience or whatever. So, I would do most of the talking unfortunately. But I would learn a little something about Singapore or about their mindset.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then at the end of last year, I realized &lt;strong&gt;what I really need to do in my life is get back to the idea that I have paused for almost 5 years ago now&lt;/strong&gt; - that Muckwork idea that I was describing. Really, it’s still gnawing at me. I still think it’s worth doing. This company idea that I had the day after I sold CD Baby. I still wanna do it, and it’s been on hold for 5 years and it’s been gnawing at me. I really think that I need to stop doing all this one-on-one meeting, and I need to just focus on my work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Around this time I read a few books that really helped speak to that feeling. The author’s name is Steven Pressfield, and he’s written 3 different books about this: “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/DoTheWork"&gt;Do the Work&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/WarOfArt"&gt;The War of Art&lt;/a&gt;”, and “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/TurningPro"&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/a&gt;” They’re like three of a series, speaking to the same thing. He’s a novelist and he calls it &lt;strong&gt;“The Resistance”: That feeling like when you’re sitting down, “facing your demons”, forcing yourself to try to sit in that chair and work, even though everything in you just wants to get up and grab a snack or take a nap or watch TV or call a friend.&lt;/strong&gt; But no, you need to sit in that chair and wrestle through this difficult paragraph or chapter or idea or whatever it is.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking at my actions in that new light really, really resonated with me&lt;/strong&gt;. Like sometimes if you’re reading something and you hear some new bit of information you go “Hmm that’s interesting. I never thought about it that way before.” And other things you hear and they just hit you in the gut. Like yeah, that is something I’ve known and felt all along and just never put into words before.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;41:23&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Because you were resisting it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;41:25&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yes! And for five years now!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like I told you earlier, how I had that company idea, the day after I sold CD Baby, I spent a few months on it but then I halted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We spent most of this conversation glorifying the world traveller, nomadic, adventure seeking culture of rebooting my operating system kind of life. But what’s kind of crazy is to &lt;strong&gt;look at that all again through a different lens now and realize that was all resistance!&lt;/strong&gt; Resistance against just what I really needed to be doing - to shut up, sit down, and get back to the really difficult work of creating something, and struggling through that painful resistance of making it happen instead of just leaping off to another country and learning another culture and having another conversation with another stranger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The really difficult work can be to shut up, sit down, and do your work. So that’s where I’m at right now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;42:34&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ok Derek, so you’ve been battling this resistance of traveling and getting into new cultures. You’re saying it was mostly resistance. So, what’s that going to do now? How has that actually informed what you’re doing right now?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;42:48&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, I think there are some things you have to work through.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like you just said that traveling inspires you and all that, and helps you be more creative. It’s true that all of this world traveling has opened my mind to many things and there is so much more to go. I feel like I just barely begun. I haven’t yet been to so many countries that I still can’t wait to understand more about. So, I feel like I’m just beginning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But most minimalists are people that used to have too much stuff, and they were pack rats or they were shopping freaks, and they got too much stuff. And then they felt the pain of having too much stuff, and then they got rid of it and felt the greater joy of realizing that you don’t need that stuff, right? So, I feel that way culturally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like the last few years I’ve just been like binging on the culture of the world, and not in a leisurely way, it’s actually been in a very focused working kind of way. In fact one of my first projects that I’m gonna be launching soon: For the last year I’ve been producing &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/"&gt;16 books about doing business in 16 different countries in Asia&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been to most of these countries recently, and interviewed a ton of people and gathered all this research and hired researchers and all this stuff. So I’ve been really binging on the cultures of the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And now that I’ve been through that, I felt the pain of not having created anything. That’s what it took for me to get back to the point of where it’s like, yeah, I could go to yet another country, and meet yet another stranger and learn more about that, but I need to sit down and program.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wanna make Muckwork happen. I have another idea called Songtest, which is like an open source song feedback contest. I had an idea called Cyrano, like a Cyrano de Bergerac tweet kind of thing for people who don’t wanna tweet for themselves. I wanna sit down and make that happen. Each one of these things, the way for me to make it happen is to &lt;strong&gt;sit down and program for a few weeks, or a few months, and launch it&lt;/strong&gt;. And then maybe lift my head up again, then probably keep my head down for a couple of years, and follow through. Get some momentum for it, and make it something that rolls on its own. That’s the hard work that I need to do next.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The question of where to do it becomes moot, because the focus is inward again instead of outward. So I can sit in my apartment in Singapore, I could rent a vacation home in New Zealand. If anything, I’m still banning my self from going back to the US for now. It’s still too familiar to me. It’s too much my comfort zone. Even though I’m inward-focused, I’d almost rather still be in Brazil, India, Sweden, or anywhere else. We’re talking from New Zealand right now. I’m in New Zealand now. I’m down here for a couple of months. One thing I like about New Zealand is it’s so far away from everything that it’s kind of like the antidote to the travel bug. Because when I’m in Singapore, there are so many fascinating cultures, just one hour away.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;46:18&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A little hop on a plane, right?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;46:20&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yes! And not only that but with the discount airfare. For like &lt;a href="http://www.tigerairways.com/sg/en/real_deals.php"&gt;$65&lt;/a&gt; I can be in Bali, or Thailand, or Cambodia, or Malaysia, or Borneo. Ahh, it’s all right there and it’s so tempting. I rented a little vacation place for a few months down in New Zealand to fight the travel bug and stay focused. So that’s what I’m doing right now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;46:44&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One thing you said that I really liked was how you hadn’t created. I think a lot of people have this hollow feeling in themselves where they know they could be creating - and some of them even attempt to do it through business - but it just doesn’t transfer. They fall prey to resistance. They don’t actually get it done. And that hollowness really ends up tainting their own world view. So how do you take that hollowness that you felt of not creating and turn it around, and actually make something from it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;47:22&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Do the work. Shut up, sit down, fight the temptation to do other things, to follow your distractions, and just work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Most of us know what we need to do&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s what’s crazy! I think in any field, any person, what you need to do is usually painfully obvious. We’re all searching for distractions or reading yet another book with yet some more advice. But no, we’ve heard enough advice, &lt;strong&gt;we’ve all got enough advice&lt;/strong&gt;. Really you already know what you need to do. It’s different for everybody.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For me, it’s programming. In order for all of my ideas to happen, it has to start with the website. To me business is still art. It’s something that I create as a personal expression of something that I want to exist. So the idea of saying, “just hire somebody to program it,” is a little like telling the songwriter in the band to just hire somebody to write the songs for them. It’s like, “Well no, this is what I do. This is my art. I want to write the songs.” So, I still want to program my websites, my ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ve never learned JavaScript before. Talking about changing my operating system - I’ve been doing nothing but PHP for 10 years. Then learning Rails. I’ve never touched JavaScript. It always was kind of a silly decoration until a few years ago - it always felt a little like an unnecessary flourishes.  Now it’s really become more core. So I picked up &lt;a href="http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Professional-JavaScript-for-Web-Developers-3rd-Edition.productCd-1118222199.html"&gt;a 1200 page book&lt;/a&gt; that everybody says is the best way to learn JavaScript. And I’m going through it, chapter by chapter, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;jotting down everything I’m learning into flash cards and memorizing it all&lt;/a&gt;, and spending hours a day just making little exercises for myself. Learning JavaScript with the idea of applying it to programming those ideas that I was talking about.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So how do I combat that emptiness and feeling? It’s just willpower. It’s almost like meditation. Again, I’m no Buddhist, but when you learn about mediation first thing you hear is that yes, all of these distractions come into your head, and you’ll be sitting there trying to stay silent and focused and all of a sudden you’ll think about something that somebody told you yesterday, and you have to just learn to let it go - to say “&lt;strong&gt;OK, that’s just a distraction. I can let that go now&lt;/strong&gt;”, and to let it run back out of your head instead of doing something about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think that a problem of our “always on, always connected” internet thing is that a lot of us, all day long, as soon as you have any kind of whimsy or curiosity or thought in your head, you immediately just type a Google query or go check on something. Let me just see how my friends are doing. Let me just check in. Let me make sure I’m not missing anything. Let me go look at &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; or whatever. It’s like mediation: feeling that urge and just saying, “Hello urge, I’m not going to acknowledge you. I’m busy, go away.” To just let it go and not act on it. I think it’s the biggest challenge for me right now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;50:38&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Very cool. Very cool. So, any final words of wisdom you can give everybody listening? We’ve talked about mostly just a philosophical discussion and giving them just a little bit of what not to do. What can they do? What would you say to people that are ingrained in their life, in their culture, in their rut, but want something different out of life? What can you say to them?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;51:04&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, &lt;strong&gt;if you’re feeling in a rut, there are 2 ways out of it&lt;/strong&gt;, and we talked about both of them here:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes what you need to do is to &lt;strong&gt;change everything&lt;/strong&gt;, to just quit your job, move somewhere different. If you’re stuck in a bad relationship, get out of it. If you’ve been with somebody for too many years and it’s a bad relationship, get out and go be single. If you’ve been single for too many years, well then commit. Y’know? If you’ve been doing things one way for too long, do the opposite.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But then the other way out of a rut - the last thing we just mentioned - is to finally have the willpower and discipline to &lt;strong&gt;do the thing that you’ve been avoiding all these years&lt;/strong&gt;. You know what you need to do. To understand that you really need to do it now. That your life is going to get worse and worse and worse if you don’t act on what you know you should be doing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For some people that means starting a company. For some people it means joining a company. For some people it mean making calls that they’ve been scared to make, or confronting their parents about something. Whatever it is, it’s usually the difficult, often long thing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s too tempting to say that it’s going to be a short thing. It’s like “Hey, just make that call that you’ve been meaning to make.” No, you need to learn that programming language that you’ve been meaning to learn, and it’s going to take you a year, y’know? &lt;strong&gt;It can often be that really long, hard, difficult thing&lt;/strong&gt;. How about like changing your eating habits? You’ve been eating crap, you need to start eating mostly vegetables, and it’s gonna be hard!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes I felt like when I was living my travel adventures, jumping off to these new countries and strangers, I often felt that what I was doing was very good for other people. That other people could say: “Wow, that looks so fun. What an adventure.” Whereas telling people no, I need to say no to the 20 people a week that want to meet with me, and say no to the many conferences that want me to come, and say no to all the projects people are asking me to join. And I need to say no to everything, and I need to sit here and spend 6 hours a day programming, and 3 hours a day writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;53:24&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ah, but that’s not glamorous.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;53:25&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Right! It’s not glamorous! &lt;strong&gt;It’s not interesting to others. It’s what needs to be done. It’s the more difficult thing.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So only you know which of these two paths is your path out of a rut. It’s really tempting to think it’s the exciting quick fix adventure thing of hopping on a plane and quitting your job and breaking up your relationship. That’s fun but be really honest with yourself that maybe the thing to get you out of your rut is finally acting on the thing that you have been avoiding for years.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;53:57&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Fantastic, fantastic. Derek, it’s been a pleasure. I’m very happy to have been able to sit down and just chat with you for a while.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Can I get your philosophical view on the world and how that informs our business decisions?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;54:15&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don’t know how much any of this refers to back to business!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;54:17&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Well, I think it does. I think everything we do in our lives, there’s no separation. I use the word business just to be able to say that there is this artificial separation, but what we do in our business is a part of our lives. It’s an active creation. It’s active, as you say art. You can’t separate the art from the artist. That’s why I love these kinds of philosophical mindset discussions. You can’t just go, “I just listened to Derek for an hour and now I can go and succeed in business.” That’s not what it’s for. What it’s for is to, as you said in the very beginning - change your operating system. Put a new program in there. And that new program in time could be the thing that actually helps you out in your business goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;55:07&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, definitely.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The one thing I mention in passing but I didn’t emphasize enough is the importance of reading books. Not just scanning articles. If you think about how many hours and hours you spend skimming articles and reading the news, that quick-fix kind of stuff. If instead, can you imagine if you didn’t do that but instead you put aside two hours a day to pick up some books that speak to something that you either don’t know anything about - like architecture - or to make you a deeper expert in something in an issue that you really care about? So often you learn so much more from that than you would just skimming around.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The idea of &lt;strong&gt;thinking something through deeper and then putting aside time to reflect on your perspective&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s one thing to just sit and read and read and read. Sometimes you need to put aside an hour and half to write your own thoughts about it. Internalize it instead of just taking it in and moving on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, you’re right, so it’s inseparable, this whole business and personal thing. It’s funny sometimes when people would want to pick my brain about their business, and they’d say “&lt;strong&gt;Here’s my business idea, what do you think?&lt;/strong&gt;” and I’d be like “Um, I don’t know, &lt;strong&gt;what kind of person are you?&lt;/strong&gt;” It depends. Do you want some big IPO, or are you looking to get bought, or are you looking to have an adventure? Y’know? It depends on what kind of a person it is. You can’t just say “This is my business advice” until you know who the person is you’re speaking to.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:35&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Right, right.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:36&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And thanks for mentioning that’s it’s inseparable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:37&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Again, I really appreciate it, and I know you’ve got to get your head back down, and back to work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:44&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:45&lt;/small&gt;
Tim:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And I need to do the same over here. So same thing with all the listeners, I want you to go out, and after you’ve taken some time and reflected on your life and put your head down.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;small&gt;56:56&lt;/small&gt;
Derek:
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And enjoy your foolish adventure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It's all who you know?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/xn</id>
    <updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/xn"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
When you hear, “It's all who you know,” it sounds so intimidating - like you need to be a former roommate of Mark Zuckerburg, cousins with Richard Branson, and dating Taylor Swift.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But simply contacting a stranger can lead to a worldwide network of connections.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I was 18, at &lt;a href="http://berklee.edu/"&gt;Berklee College of Music&lt;/a&gt;, we had a guest speaker named &lt;a href="http://www.spiritmusicgroup.com/about/team/mark-fried"&gt;Mark Fried&lt;/a&gt;, who was an executive at &lt;a href="http://www.bmi.com/"&gt;BMI&lt;/a&gt; - a big music company in New York City.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He walked into the classroom just before class began, and I heard him ask the teacher, “Oh, I thought we were going to have food.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The teacher said, “Oh, no, sorry, I thought you ate already! Didn't you have lunch?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Mark said, “Damn. No. And it's a two hour class. Oh well.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hearing this, I quickly ran out of the room and called &lt;a href="http://www.supremepizzapasta.com/"&gt;Supreme's Pizza&lt;/a&gt;, asking them to deliver three large pizzas to classroom #115.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
45 minutes later, the pizzas showed up. I gave one to Mark and shared two with the class.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
He smiled at me and said, “Good move. I owe you one. Here's my card. Call me any time, and let me know how I can help. When you come to New York City, I'll be happy to meet up.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For the next two years, I took him up on that, sending him my new songs for feedback, and he'd tell me his insights and advice about the music industry.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I told Mark I wanted to move to New York, he said, “Send me your resume, and I'll find you a job.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sure enough, a few weeks later, I got a call in my dorm room from Julie Gengo at &lt;a href="http://www.warnerchappell.com/"&gt;Warner/Chappell Music Publishing&lt;/a&gt;, saying, “We need someone to run our tape room, and Mark Fried said we should hire you.  Can you start Monday?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Just like that, I was in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because I was working inside Warner Brothers, it was easy to meet everybody in the New York City music scene.  Every person I met connected me to many more.  A few years later, it was no problem to move to Los Angeles, because I now had a huge network in LA, through one degree of separation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now it's grown worldwide.  Whether I'm visiting Iceland, Shanghai, Rio, Japan, or Silicon Valley, I've got a wonderful network of connections to call on, and people worldwide who can call on me anytime.  Usually we know eachother loosely - having only traded a couple emails - but those quickly turn into real friendships.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All because I bought a pizza for a stranger.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Surrounded by success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Soon after arriving in New York, I was surrounded by successful people.  I was only 20 years old, but &lt;strong&gt;I learned so much from watching how people become successful, hearing their stories, philosophies, and mistakes.&lt;/strong&gt;  Opportunities were everywhere.  (A chance recommendation from my roommate got me a gig touring the world, &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/sakamoto"&gt;playing guitar for Ryuichi Sakamoto&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These people shaped the way I see the world.  &lt;strong&gt;The people you surround yourself with don't just open doors. They change the way you think, and change your self-image of your capabilities!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you're surrounded by successful people, it feels so easy, it's obvious.  Their attitude and actions rub off on you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But I meet so many people that feel that success is so far away, so impossible to imagine, that they act accordingly, aim low, and complete the self-defeating circle.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I know much of success is luck, but I never realized how much the mindset of success comes from who you know.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Luckily, who you know is &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/people-per-week"&gt;up to you&lt;/a&gt;, not luck.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;No need to be in the big city&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I used to advise ambitious people to move to the big city, where everything is happening.  And it's still true that it offers some benefits.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But more and more it feels like &lt;strong&gt;“where everything is happening” is &lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - and &lt;strong&gt;the way to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; there is to &lt;em&gt;create&lt;/em&gt; something that adds to it.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Most of the fascinating and successful people I know now are people I met online.  I see something they've done, or they see something I've done, one of us sends the other an email, and that's it.  A few emails, maybe a phone call, and we're friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What's even more fascinating is finding out that the super-connectors, the people who know everybody and everybody knows, are often physically remote.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For example, some of the most connected people I know now are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://karol.gajda.com/about/"&gt;Karol Gajda&lt;/a&gt; in Poland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tropicalmba.com/about-the-tropical-mba/"&gt;Dan Andrews&lt;/a&gt; in Bali&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://unicornfree.com/"&gt;Amy Hoy&lt;/a&gt; who just moved from Vienna to Philadelphia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kalzumeus.com/"&gt;Patrick McKenzie&lt;/a&gt; in Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sebastianmarshall.com/about"&gt;Sebastian Marshall&lt;/a&gt; who bounces between Mongolia, China, and Taiwan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The reasons they're so connected are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;because they keep creating great stuff and posting it online&lt;/strong&gt;, which gets the attention of their peers, so soon “everyone” knows who they are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;because they reach out to say hello to the people they admire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So if it seems that there's an uncrossable canyon between you and your heroes, don't forget that all it takes is one connection to catch your rope, so you can shimmy across.  And you can do this from anywhere by creating great stuff online, and reaching out to potential friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
No need to attend Harvard with Mark Zuckerburg.  No need to become a cousin of Richard Branson.  And no need to date Taylor Swift.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(See.  There are three things you can cross off your TO-DO list now.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/people-per-week.gif" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Focus, entertain, or both?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/boring</id>
    <updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/boring"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You have a bigger audience than you had just a few years ago.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have more people reading your updates, and wanting to hear something new.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Standing on this virtual stage, you want to be entertaining, post exciting updates, be impressive, and keep their attention.  You’re so rewarded with status when you do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But what happens when the thing you really need to do is boring to others?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/book/Mastery"&gt;path to mastery&lt;/a&gt; requires months and years of practice that isn’t exciting to your audience.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then you’ve got a conflict:  What’s best for you is to &lt;strong&gt;shut up, sit down, and focus&lt;/strong&gt;.  What’s best for them (now) is for you to be entertaining.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You remind yourself that in the future, this will pay off.  The things you’re creating and skills you’re developing will benefit everyone.  But by being online, you’re still on stage.  How can you not entertain?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do you go full recluse, and completely disconnect?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do you stay connected, but stop contributing?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do you give up the deep work, and give in to the shallow rewards of just entertaining?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Or do you somehow keep up your &lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/author/cory_doctorow_1"&gt;obligations&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/"&gt;entertain&lt;/a&gt;, while doing your “shut up, sit down, and focus” &lt;a href="http://craphound.com/?cat=5"&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href="http://www.sethgodin.com/sg/books.asp"&gt;side&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tereneta/107491739/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/audiencetent.jpg" alt="audience" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(No answers.  Just questions, today.  And yes, I’m talking to myself, but I think a lot of people are going through this, so I’m asking you, too.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Yes, learn basic programming</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/prog</id>
    <updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/prog"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
A few people have asked me &lt;strong&gt;whether I think programming is a necessary skill&lt;/strong&gt; for entrepreneurs (or anyone) to have in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I was 14 years old, taking guitar lessons from &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/thomaspecora"&gt;Tom Pecora&lt;/a&gt;, he gave me that this-is-important-so-listen-well look, and told me something that stuck with me for life:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;“You need to learn to sing. Because if you don’t, you’re always going to be at the mercy of some asshole singer.”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
His point of view was from a rock guitarist in the Chicago music scene, trying to put together a band, and all that.  I really took it to heart, and &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/15-years"&gt;learned to sing&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But ever since then I’ve applied that point to other areas.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When I first started CD Baby, I didn’t know any programming, only basic HTML, and quickly had to cry for someone to help me.  &lt;a href="http://hr.linkedin.com/pub/davor-cengija/36/592/391"&gt;Davor Cengija&lt;/a&gt; in Croatia was a big help, but one day he disappeared. (Turned out he broke his foot skiing.)  For weeks I was helpless, as my site had problems, and I didn’t know how to fix them.  That pain got me motivated to learn this stuff myself.  (Necessity is the best motivator.)  I’ve loved programming ever since.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Later, when I needed a new computer, my friend &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/showtimesolutions"&gt;Tony Benjamin&lt;/a&gt; taught me how to build my own from parts.  This was so empowering because this box that I depended on so much was no longer a mystery.  As CD Baby grew, I loved building all the computers for the employees, and even the webservers that ran the site.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_music#Independent_artists_and_technology"&gt;independent musician scene&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DIY_ethic"&gt;DIY ethic&lt;/a&gt; is strong, by necessity.  When it comes to doing all those non-musical things like booking gigs, promoting, publishing, and all of the organizational things, the norm is to &lt;strong&gt;do it yourself until it makes more sense to get someone better to help you&lt;/strong&gt;.  (And even then, maybe choosing to do it yourself just because you want to.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The benefit of doing this yourself at first is that you learn enough about it so when you can afford to hire someone, you’re in a much better position to know if they’re good or not.  Also it gives you the confidence to know that if anyone else flakes, you can step in and do enough to keep going.  The deep joy of self-reliance.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So... back to programming:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The most common thing I hear from aspiring entrepreneurs is, &lt;strong&gt;“I have this idea for an app or site. But I’m not technical, so I need to find someone who can make it for me.”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I point them to &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/how2hire"&gt;my advice about how to hire a programmer&lt;/a&gt;, but as most of the good ones are already booked solid, it’s a pretty helpless position to be in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you heard someone say, “&lt;strong&gt;I have this idea for a song.  But I’m not musical, so I need to find someone who will write, perform, and record it for me.&lt;/strong&gt;” - you’d probably advise them to just take some time to sit down with a guitar or piano and &lt;strong&gt;learn enough to turn their ideas into reality.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And so comes my advice:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Yes, learn some programming basics.&lt;/strong&gt;  Just some HTML, CSS, and JavaScript should be enough to start.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I recommend &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596159924.do"&gt;Head First HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; first, then &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920010906.do"&gt;Head First HTML5 Programming&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Get those basics under your belt.  Make an HTML site respond to things the user is doing.  Save some information in a database, and use it to generate a web page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You could go through those books in a couple weeks of evenings, and you’d already know as much as 50% of the people out there calling themselves webdesigners or web programmers!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s a REALLY amazing feeling. The mystery is lifted. You’ll look at all websites in a new way. You’ll understand what’s going on behind the scenes. You’ll know how to do it yourself. It’s really empowering.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once you’ve done that, you’ll know enough to know what you need next.  Maybe you want to get deeper into web development with &lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/black2/"&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/"&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://learnpythonthehardway.org/book/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://ruby.railstutorial.org/"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/cantelon/"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;.  But &lt;strong&gt;don’t get overwhelmed&lt;/strong&gt;.  When you’re ready, look at the book reviews on Amazon to see which books people are raving about.  Go to &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/"&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; to ask questions or recommendations.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This will give you a good foundation if you want to go on to make iPhone or Android apps, or just know enough to hire someone better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You don’t need to become an expert, just know the basics, so you’re not helpless.&lt;/strong&gt;  You can do all of this in less hours than it takes to watch “The Wire”, and it’s much more rewarding.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(It’s definitely been the most rewarding thing I’ve ever learned.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/plarsen/35590387/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/bicycle-repair.jpg" alt="bicycle repair" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Memorizing a programming language using spaced repetition software</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/srs</id>
    <updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2013-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/srs"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I've been doing this for a year, and it's &lt;strong&gt;the most helpful learning technique I've found in 14 years of computer programming&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Background:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm an intermediate programmer. I didn't go to school for it. I just learned by necessity because I started a little website called CD Baby that just kept growing and growing, and I couldn't afford to hire a programmer, so I picked up a few $25 books on PHP, SQL, Linux, and Apache, and &lt;strong&gt;learned just enough to make it work, then used that little knowledge for years.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But later, &lt;strong&gt;when I worked along side a REAL programmer&lt;/strong&gt;, I was blown away by their vocabulary!  All of these &lt;strong&gt;commands and functions just flowing effortlessly out of their fingers&lt;/strong&gt;.  We were using the same language, but they had memorized so much of it, that I felt like a 3-year-old next to a university professor.  I really wanted to get that kind of fluency.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It made me think about &lt;strong&gt;how much I've learned then immediately forgotten&lt;/strong&gt;, over the years.  I read books or articles about some useful feature, and try it once, but then I get distracted, forget about it, and go about my normal way of doing things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wanted to deeply memorize the commands and techniques of the language, and not forget them, so that they stay at the forefront of my mind whenever I need them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Spaced Repetition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When you hear a new fact, it's forgotten pretty quickly unless it's brought back to the forefront of your mind repeatedly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can do this haphazardly by immersing yourself in a language, for example, where the new words you learn will be brought up by chance occasionally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But memory research shows that &lt;strong&gt;the most effective and efficient time for a new fact to be remembered is right before you were about to forget it&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://quantifiedself.com/2012/06/spaced-repetition-and-learning/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/forgetting-curve-srs.jpg" alt="forgetting curve" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Say if you learn a new word in a foreign language, you'd want to practice it again a few minutes after hearing it, then a few hours, then the next day, then in 2 days, then 5 days, then 10 days, 3 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 8 months, etc.  After a while it's basically permanently memorized with a rare reminder.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Spaced Repetition Software does this for you&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can just &lt;strong&gt;give it a bunch of facts you want to remember, then have it quiz you once a day, and it manages the intervals based on your feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; After each quiz question, if you say that one was easy, it won't be introduced for a long time, but if you were stumped, then it'll ask it again in a few minutes, until you've got it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Go to &lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/"&gt;http://ankisrs.net&lt;/a&gt; and download Anki&lt;/strong&gt; - the free, open source, most popular spaced repetition software program. Available for Mac, Windows, Linux, iPhone, Android, etc. Written in Python.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As for programming, you get where I'm going with this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What if you could &lt;strong&gt;memorize everything about the programming language&lt;/strong&gt; of your choice?  Every command, every parameter, every function.  Every solution to hundreds of the most common problems, all completely memorized at your fingertips?  Imagine going through the documentation or a book, and &lt;strong&gt;permanently remembering every single thing in it?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Enough of the intro, let's get to the HOW-TO:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;First, learn!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, I have to make something really clear:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Flash cards are for &lt;em&gt;remembering&lt;/em&gt; what you’ve learned.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Before you create a flash card for something, you need to actually &lt;strong&gt;learn and understand it, first.&lt;/strong&gt;  Whether you learn from books, lectures, videos, reading through source code, online tutorials, or anything else, create the flash card after you’ve learned and understood.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(This is why it’s not that helpful to look at someone else’s deck.  Those are just reminders.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Convert Knowledge into Small Facts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You're going to be making a bunch of flash cards.  Question on the front.  Answer on the back.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you were just using this to memorize foreign language vocabulary, then the formatting would be easy.  The front would have a word or phrase, and the back would have its translation, and vice-versa.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/anki-cn-1.png" alt="example chinese flash card question" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/anki-cn-2.png" alt="example chinese flash card answer" /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/anki-cn-3.png" alt="example chinese flash card question" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/anki-cn-4.png" alt="example chinese flash card answer" /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you're learning anything else, you're going to have to put a little craft and creativity into making your own flash cards.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It takes some effort to &lt;strong&gt;read through paragraphs of stuff you want to remember, pick out the key facts, break them down into their smallest form, and turn them into quiz questions, for quizzing your future self&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here are my best time-saving tips from a year of doing this:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Turn prose into code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you're learning JavaScript, you come across this information:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“The add (+) operator... if only one operand is a string, the other operand is converted to a string and the result is the concatenation of the two strings.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You test this out yourself, play around with it, and find out that 1 + '1' is '11'.  So you make a flashcard to remember this fact:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var a = 5 + '5';
// what is a?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
'55'
If either side of + is a string, the other is
converted to a string before adding like strings.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes I write an explanation.  Sometimes there's no need, because the answer itself is enough of a reminder of the reason.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Try to trick your future self&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here's another JavaScript fact:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“If the new Array constructor is passed a single number, it creates an empty Array with a length of that number. Any other combination of arguments creates an Array of those arguments.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You test this out yourself, play around with it, and make two flash cards to try to trick your future self:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var a = new Array('5');
// what is a?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
An array with one item, the string '5': ['5'];
&lt;/pre&gt;
... and then an almost-identical question ...
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var a = new Array(5);
// what is a?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
An empty array with a length of 5.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When the program quizzes you, it will shuffle the cards, so that hopefully these examples will intentionally catch you by surprise.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can also try to trick yourself with more complicated examples, to keep these gotchas fresh in your mind:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var a = [20, 10, 5, 1];
// what is a.sort()?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
[1, 10, 20, 5]
// sort treats all values as strings
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Don't forget to &lt;strong&gt;quiz yourself on the solution, too:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var a = [20, 10, 5, 1];
// sort these in numeric order
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
function compare(v1, v2) { return(v1 - v2); }
a.sort(compare);
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Save the cool tricks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find a cool trick you want to remember, turn it into the answer of a small challenge.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
var albums = [
  {name: 'Beatles', title: 'White Album', price: 15},
  {name: 'Zeppelin', title: 'II', price: 7}];
// make this work:
albums.sort(by('name'));
albums.sort(by('title'));
albums.sort(by('price'));
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
function by(propName) {
  return function(obj1, obj2) {
    v1 = obj1[propName];
    v2 = obj2[propName];
    if (v1 &lt; v2) { return -1; }
    else if (v1 &gt; v2) { return 1; }
    else { return 0; }
  };
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Make the answer require multiple solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If there's more than one way of doing something, and you want to remember both, make your future self come up with more than one solution, so you can keep both alternatives in mind.  (Note, I'm switching from JavaScript to Ruby examples now.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
s = 'string like this'
# Show two ways to turn it into 'String Like This'
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
s.split.map(&amp;amp;:capitalize).join(' ')
s.gsub(/\b\S/) {|x| x.upcase}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Turn broad concepts into succinct examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Say you just spent 20 minutes learning something that's more conceptual, and not as much about remembering specific functions.  Sometimes all you need is one succinct example to remind yourself of the concept.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
/(a(b)((c)d))/.match('abcd')
# What will $1, $2, $3, $4 be?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
$1 = 'abcd'
$2 = 'b'
$3 = 'cd'
$4 = 'c'
&lt;/pre&gt;
Another example:
&lt;pre class="anki1"&gt;
class C
  self
end
class D &lt; C
end
d1 = D.new
# which object is self?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre class="anki2"&gt;
class D
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Read “&lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/articles/20rules.htm"&gt;20 Rules of Formulating Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;” by Piotr Wozniak&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The best advice on this stuff is an article called “20 Rules of Formulating Knowledge” by Piotr Wozniak at &lt;a href="http://www.supermemo.com/articles/20rules.htm"&gt;http://www.supermemo.com/articles/20rules.htm&lt;/a&gt;.  So please read that one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Run Through it Daily&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For most efficient results, turn on your spaced repetition software once a day.  If you go too long without, you'll screw up all the timings, and have to re-learn stuff you would have remembered.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You can remember thousands of these facts in only 20 minutes a day&lt;/strong&gt;.  I just make it a morning routine.  Make a cup of boiling tea.  Do my Anki.  Drink my tea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's fun when quizzing yourself to add a little adrenaline, and make yourself go as fast as you can.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's like a mental visit to the gym.  A little intense 20 minutes a day is so worth it for the immediate and long-term results.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Add some new cards whenever you can, and you'll be amazed that everything you saved stays fresh in your mind.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've been doing this for a year, and it's been a HUGE boost to my fluency.  I highly recommend it, as you can tell.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you're interested, you can also use this approach to learn all kinds of things.  See &lt;a href="http://quantifiedself.com/2012/06/spaced-repetition-and-learning/"&gt;this primer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/medtech/health/magazine/16-05/ff_wozniak?currentPage=all"&gt;this interview with Piotr Wozniak&lt;/a&gt; for more inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Feel free to email me anytime (&lt;a href="mailto:derek@sivers.org"&gt;derek@sivers.org&lt;/a&gt;) to ask any questions, or just to let me know how it goes for you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After I posted this, someone showed me &lt;a href="http://www.jackkinsella.ie/2011/12/05/janki-method.html"&gt;this great article on similar approach&lt;/a&gt; - which I think explains it even better than I did here, so &lt;strong&gt;please read that one, too.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also I got many requests to share my Ruby and JavaScript Anki decks.  I don't think it's very useful, because the whole point is that the Anki card is not where you learn - it's more of a reminder you give your future self about something you have already learned.  The learning itself requires more context.  But that said, if you want, &lt;strong&gt;here are my JavaScript and Ruby decks&lt;/strong&gt; as of January 7 2013.  You'll have to use Anki's “File → Import” function to import them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.s3.amazonaws.com/JavaScript-sivers.apkg.zip"&gt;JavaScript Anki deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sivers.s3.amazonaws.com/Ruby-sivers.apkg.zip"&gt;Ruby Anki deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Everything is my fault</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/my-fault</id>
    <updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2012-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/my-fault"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I cut two chapters out of &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/a"&gt;my book&lt;/a&gt; because they were too nasty.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They vented all the awful details about how my terrible employees staged a mutiny to try to get rid of me, and corrupted the culture of the company into a festering pool of entitlement, focused only on their benefits instead of our clients.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Afterwards, I spent a few years still mad at those evil brats for what they did.  So, like anyone feeling victimized and wronged, I needed to vent - to tell my side of the story.  Or so I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So do you want to know &lt;strong&gt;the real reason I cut those chapters?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I realized it was all my fault.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; let the culture of the company get corrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; ignored problems instead of nipping them in the bud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was aloof and away instead of managing or training managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; confused everyone by sharing my daily thoughts before they had cemented into decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; announced decisions, then assumed they were being done, without following-up to ensure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; whimsically delegated to the wrong people, avoiding the mental work of choosing wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(I could list another 20 of these, but you get the idea.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It felt so SO good to realize it was my fault!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;This is way better than forgiving.&lt;/strong&gt;  When you forgive, you’re still playing the victim, and they’re still wrong, but you’re charitably pardoning their horrible deeds.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But to decide it’s your fault feels amazing!  Now you weren’t wronged.  &lt;strong&gt;They were just playing their part in the situation you created.&lt;/strong&gt;  They’re just delivering the punch-line to the joke you set up.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What power!  Now you’re like a new super-hero, just discovering your strength.  Now you’re the powerful person that made things happen, made a mistake, and can learn from it.  Now you’re in control and there’s nothing to &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/complainers"&gt;complain&lt;/a&gt; about.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This philosophy feels so good that &lt;strong&gt;I’ve playfully decided to apply this “EVERYTHING IS MY FAULT” rule to the rest of my life.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's one of those base rules like “people mean well” that's more fun to believe, and have a few exceptions, than to not believe at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The guy that stole $9000 from me? &lt;strong&gt;My fault.&lt;/strong&gt;  I should have verified his claims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The love of my life that dumped me out of the blue (by email!) after 6 years? &lt;strong&gt;My fault.&lt;/strong&gt;  I let our relationship plateau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone was rude to me today? &lt;strong&gt;My fault.&lt;/strong&gt;  I could have lightened their mood beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t like my government? &lt;strong&gt;My fault.&lt;/strong&gt;  I could get involved and change the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;See what power it is?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, the word “responsibility” is more accurate, but it's such a serious 6-syllable word, whereas “everything’s my fault” is a fun rule-of-thumb, and gets me singing Nirvana’s “&lt;a href="http://www.metrolyrics.com/all-apologies-lyrics-nirvana.html"&gt;All Apologies&lt;/a&gt;”.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
Try it on.  Stand up, open the window, look out at the world and shout, “&lt;strong&gt;Everything is my fault!&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Think of every bad thing that happened to you, and say it again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Cool, huh?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That power looks good on you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/superfault.jpg" alt="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathaninsandiego/5972205809/" /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathaninsandiego/5972205809/"&gt;Nathan Rupert&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
P.S. Also see “&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/villain"&gt;Happiness is letting someone make you the villain&lt;/a&gt;.”
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You don't have to be local</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/local</id>
    <updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2012-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/local"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You can focus your time locally or globally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;if you over-commit yourself locally, you under-commit yourself globally&lt;/strong&gt;, and vice-versa.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re &lt;strong&gt;local&lt;/strong&gt;, then you’re probably social, &lt;strong&gt;doing a lot of things in-person&lt;/strong&gt;, and being a part of your community.  But this means you’ll have less time to focus on creating things for the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re &lt;strong&gt;global&lt;/strong&gt;, then you want to focus on creating things that can &lt;strong&gt;reach out through distribution to the whole world&lt;/strong&gt;.  But this means you’ll have less time to be part of your local community.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Neither is right or wrong, but you need to be aware of the choices you’re making.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For me, the reason I’m writing this, is a personal announcement that I’ve tried both ways, felt the difference, and made my choice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some background:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I lived in Woodstock, New York for 3 years.&lt;/strong&gt; While in &lt;a href="http://www.jpfolks.com/ECRoadTrip00/ECpages/cdbaby.html"&gt;my little house in the woods&lt;/a&gt;, I started CD Baby and Hostbaby, and connected with thousands of people.  I was traveling a lot, so all my social time was on the road, and my friends were in New York City and Boston.  &lt;strong&gt;I never met anyone in Woodstock&lt;/strong&gt;.  I just lived there, but didn’t socialize there.  All my attention was focused out to the world, and &lt;strong&gt;it was very effective&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then &lt;strong&gt;I lived in Portland, Oregon for 3 years&lt;/strong&gt;.  I worked every waking hour, growing CD Baby and Hostbaby.  It was incredibly productive.  Still traveling a lot to conferences, I made some &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/friends"&gt;dear and deep friends&lt;/a&gt; worldwide, but &lt;strong&gt;I never hung out in Portland.&lt;/strong&gt;  It was just my place to work and sleep. My attention was still focused outward.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then two years ago, &lt;strong&gt;when I &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/singapore"&gt;moved to Singapore&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to get very involved in my local community.&lt;/strong&gt;  I volunteered my time to all the universities, hacker groups, entrepreneur mentor sessions, and government departments. I had an open door, said yes to every request, met with over 400 people one-on-one, and went to every conference and get-together.  &lt;strong&gt;I spent most of the last two years just talking with people.&lt;/strong&gt;  And I really got to know the Singapore community.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But something never felt right.  After a day of talking, I was often exhausted and unfulfilled.  It was usually one-sided, answering questions, giving advice.  Two hours spent being useful to one person who wants to “pick my brain” is two hours I’d rather spend making something that could be useful to the whole world (including that one person).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then &lt;strong&gt;people around the world email to ask why I’ve been so silent&lt;/strong&gt;.  No new articles?  No progress on my companies?  Nothing?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So there’s the trade-off.  By being so local-focused, I’m not being as useful as I was when I was making things online.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I’m finally admitting : &lt;strong&gt;I’m not local.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I hope I was useful to the Singapore community these past two years, but it was at the expense of everyone else.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I moved around so much that I’m not from anywhere.  I feel equally connected to London, Los Angeles, New York, New Zealand, Singapore, San Francisco, Iceland, and India.  I care about people in all of those places.  They’re all equally home.  Just because I live in one now, doesn’t mean I should ignore the others.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To me, the emphasis on local stuff never felt right.  When I was in Woodstock and Portland, people would ask what I was doing to promote the local music scene there.  I’d argue that I shouldn’t favor Woodstock or Portland any more than Wellington or Prague.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But that’s just me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some people feel a strong separation between inside and outside.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you’re a part of their family, neighborhood, church, school, or a friend-of-a-friend, then you’re an insider.  Everyone else is an outsider.  They say, “The reason you go to university is for the connections you’ll have for life.”  In business, they give preferential treatment to their inside circle.  (This is &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cronyism"&gt;cronyism&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Other people feel no separation.&lt;/strong&gt;  You’re treated equally, no matter where you’re from or who you know.  There are no outsiders.  If extra-strong bonds are made, it’s based on who you are now - not where you came from or where you’ve been.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One will feel more natural to you.  Like your tendency to be an introvert vs extrovert, or conservative vs liberal, &lt;strong&gt;these base world-views will shape your preferences for being local-focused or global-focused.&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Each industry has their own version of this decision.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you want to make vegetarian food, you can make &lt;a href="http://www.hungrygowhere.com/singapore/new_green_pasture_cafe/"&gt;a great local vegetarian restaurant&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href="http://www.amys.com/about-us/our-kitchen"&gt;widely distributed line&lt;/a&gt; of vegetarian meals.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you’re a musician, you can do 100 gigs or write and record 100 songs.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Etc.  Different focus.  Different approach.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Both are necessary.&lt;/strong&gt; Neither is right or wrong, but you need to be aware that you can choose the local/global balance that feels best to you, no matter the norms.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For me, for now, I’m going to stop doing all these in-person meetings, and turn my attention back to &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/blog"&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://50pop.com/code"&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/uncommon"&gt;recording&lt;/a&gt; things that can benefit anyone anywhere.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: I updated this article 5 days after posting, to be clearer that I'm not against in-person contact - just this local-focused in-person one-sided volunteering of my time.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/iceland-house.jpg" alt="http://www.flickr.com/photos/planetcam/6227872212/" /&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo of Iceland house by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/planetcam/6227872212/"&gt;Erik-Jan Vens&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Push, push, push. Expanding your comfort zone.</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/comfort</id>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2012-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/comfort"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I’m 40 meters underwater. It’s getting cold and dark. It’s only the third dive in my life, but I’m taking the advanced training course, and the Caribbean teacher was a little reckless, dashing ahead, leaving me alone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The next day I’m in a government office, answering an interview, raising my right hand, becoming a citizen of Dominica.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m in a Muslim Indian family’s house in Staten Island, washing my feet, with the Imam waiting for my conversion ceremony. Next week they will be my family in-law. The Muslim wedding will make her extended family happy. I’ve memorized the syllables I need to say. “Ash hadu alla ilaha illallah. Ash hadu anna muhammadar rasulullah.”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m backstage at the TED Conference, about to go on, but I can’t remember my lines. In the audience are Bill Gates, Al Gore, Peter Gabriel, and a few hundred other intimidating geniuses. Heart pounding so fast and hard, I think I’m going to explode. They call my name. Ack! I still can’t remember my lines! But &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_how_to_start_a_movement.html"&gt;I hit the stage&lt;/a&gt; anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m alone on a bicycle in a forest in Sweden. I left from Stockholm 6 hours ago, headed south, with only 50 kronor, and I’m getting hungry. I don’t know the way back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We’re in a filthy dorm-room apartment in Guilin, China, studying at the local university. At the local grocery store, we choose from a bin of live frogs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The India Embassy official hands me a pseudo-passport that says I am now officially a “Person of Indian Origin” - a pseudo-citizen of India.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m in the back of a truck in Cambodia, soaking wet, hitching a ride back to Phnom Penh after an all day bike ride. The roads were flooded but we rode our bikes through anyway, Mekong River water waist-high.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That week I speak at four conferences in Cambodia, Singapore, Brunei, and Indonesia. By the 4th one, my American accent has started to morph into something kind of Asian.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We’re in a hospital in Singapore, having a baby. It’s a boy, which means he’ll serve 2 years in the Singapore military in 2030. The birth certificate says his race is Eurasian, a word I’ve never heard.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m on a diplomatic mission in Mongolia, with the Singapore Business Federation, talking with the Mongolian government’s head of business development, walking with the next mayor of Ulaanbaatar.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I suppress a laugh at the ridiculousless of this situation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I’m just a musician from California! What the hell am I doing here?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;But that feeling lets me know I’m on the right track.&lt;/strong&gt; This is exactly what I wanted.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.fourhourworkweek.com/blog/category/physical-performance/"&gt;Some people&lt;/a&gt; push themselves physically, to see how far they can go. I’ve been doing the same thing culturally, trying to expand my California-boy perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I love that when we push push push, we expand our comfort zone. &lt;strong&gt;Things that used to feel intimidating now are as comfortable as home.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I remember how scary New York City felt when I moved there in 1990, just 20 years old. Two years later it was “my” city - my comfort zone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now previously-exotic Singapore is my long-term comfortable home, while I push myself into exploring foreign places, new businesses, and different perspectives.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After years of stage fright, performing over 1000 shows, I have a strong case of “stage comfort”. Being the lead singer or speaker on stage is now my comfort zone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A lot of my musician friends feel this when playing on stage with their legendary heroes. You push push push, then one day find yourself on the very stage you used to dream about. And it feels so natural - almost relaxing. It’s your new comfort zone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The question is - what scares you now? What’s intimidating? What’s the great unknown?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I keep using that question to guide my next move.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/Mongolia-meeting-table-DerekSivers.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Mongolia-meeting-table-DerekSivers-600.jpg" alt="Mongolia meeting" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(click for picture of me at last week's diplomatic mission in Mongolia)&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Smart people don't think others are stupid</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/ss</id>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2012-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/ss"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
The woman seemed to be making some pretty good points, until she stopped with, “Ugh! Those &lt;em&gt;(people she disagrees with)&lt;/em&gt; are just so stupid!!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
She could have said Southerners, Northerners, Republicans, Democrats, Indians, or Americans. It doesn’t matter. She had just proven that she wasn’t being smart.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are no smart people or stupid people, just people being smart or being stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(And things are often not as they seem, so people who seem to be doing something smart or stupid, may not be. There’s always more information, more context, and &lt;a href="/horses"&gt;more to the story&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Being smart means thinking things through&lt;/strong&gt; - trying to find the real answer, not the first answer.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Being stupid means avoiding thinking by jumping to conclusions.&lt;/strong&gt; Jumping to a conclusion is like quitting a game : you lose by default.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That’s why saying “I don’t know” is usually smart, because it’s refusing to jump to a conclusion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So &lt;strong&gt;when someone says “They are so stupid!” - it means they’ve stopped thinking.&lt;/strong&gt; They say it to feel finished with that subject, because there’s nothing they can do about that. It’s appealing and satisfying to jump to that conclusion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So if you decide someone is stupid, it means you’re not thinking, which is not being smart.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Therefore: &lt;strong&gt;smart people don’t think others are stupid.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/dunce.jpg" alt="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lord-jim/6449796821/" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Advice on moving to Los Angeles</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/la</id>
    <updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2012-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/la"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Someone moving to Los Angeles asked my advice.&lt;/strong&gt;  Here it is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I lived in LA from 2002 to 2009 and loved it. There are a few things to understand:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It’s not really a city.&lt;/strong&gt; Not long ago, it was just a bunch of small towns: Venice, Pasadena, Burbank, Encino, Beverly Hills - but then for tax reasons they drew a circle around about 30 small towns and decided to call it Los Angeles. So if you go just understanding it’s a bunch of adjacent towns, each quite different in character, and don’t go expecting a city, then it won’t be so frustrating. When someone says they hate LA, you have to ask, “Which neighborhood?” Because Santa Monica is not like Silverlake is not like Van Nuys is not like Hollywood, but they’re all inside that circle called LA. It’s completely de-centralized. (And “downtown” is just another neighborhood. It's not the center of things, like most cities. Most people have no need to go there.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Americans are already quite individualist, but Los Angeles is the most individualist part of America. Because so many people are employed by the entertainment industry, many are self-employed freelancers. They’re very focused on themselves. &lt;strong&gt;People talk about themselves a lot because they feel they have to, for survival, for self-promotion.&lt;/strong&gt; Just as you can’t fault anyone in the world for doing something for survival, try not to fault them for being so self-promotional. Learn to lovingly listen like you’d listen to an 8-year-old who excitedly tells you about their train set for an hour.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
You know you need a car, but you also need to use it to go exploring, the way you’d go on a random walk in London, strolling down streets you’ve never seen. Do this in your car, and stop and get out in different places that seem interesting. Most of the best parts of LA are on little side-streets you’d never run across. &lt;strong&gt;Avoid the highways and take the backroads&lt;/strong&gt;, for this reason. (Get GPS so you can always do this fearlessly.) Find Little Tokyo, Topanga Canyon, Eagle Rock, etc.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Get into nature often.&lt;/strong&gt; Go hiking up in the hills. Go hiking in Will Rogers State Park in Pacfic Palisades, the beach in Malibu. East to Palm Springs, etc. It’s all so close.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Every culture values different things.&lt;/strong&gt; In some places, it’s your bloodline. In others, your university. In others, it’s where you live. &lt;strong&gt;In LA, it’s who you know.&lt;/strong&gt; Since the entertainment industry is all about short-term projects, everyone survives by their next project, and these projects always come from a connection. So everyone is collecting contacts. (Again: it’s survival.) Friendships are pragmatic and often short. Don’t fault them for talking about who they know, the same way you wouldn’t fault someone from India asking about your family. Introducing people to each other, people who could potentially work together, is the most valuable thing you can do, as it raises your value and theirs. LA people want (NEED!) to have powerful well-connected friends, to survive and thrive.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Not just LA but California is &lt;strong&gt;the most optimistic place on earth&lt;/strong&gt;. The side-effects of this can confuse outsiders. When you say, “Will you come to my event?” or, “Want to help with this project?” - &lt;strong&gt;they will almost always say yes&lt;/strong&gt;, full of enthusiasm, and actually 100% sincere, fully intending to be there, to help, whatever. They honestly and optimistically think that they will be there and do it. They have the best of intentions. But when it actually comes to that time, and they’ve optimistically said “yes!” to a dozen other things too, or perhaps they’re just nestled in the comfort of their California home, then... well... they reluctantly “flake” - and won’t follow through. Don’t get bitter and write them off as fake, or backstabbers. Just understand that it’s a side-effect of sincere optimism, and adjust your expectations accordingly.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As with any place, if you really want to experience it, don’t just sneer and condemn it, &lt;strong&gt;dive in and live it like a local&lt;/strong&gt;. (Most people are from somewhere else anyway, so you're just as local as they are, now.) Drive around the different neighborhoods. Be totally optimistic. Aim to meet as many people as possible, and get something out of your short-lived friendships. Introduce them to each other. Have lots and lots of lunches, and enjoy the conversations. Go to the beach and hike in the hills.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It may feel fake, but faking it is fine. (Kurt Vonnegut wrote, “You are whatever you pretend to be.”) If you throw yourself into it whole-heartedly for a while, you’ll learn something useful from it, and have it as a great life experience, as you go back to whatever culture feels a better fit for the real you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disagree? More to add? Please leave a reply, below…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/la.jpg" alt="Los Angeles" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Friends from memory</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/friends</id>
    <updated>2011-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2011-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/friends"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Here’s a great project, that will fill you full of gratitude and reminiscing:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Try to write down all the friends you’ve ever had - from memory.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No address book, no phone, no Facebook.  Just memory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Remember all those people you met and connected with that made a difference in your life.
It’s amazing how many are still in your head.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
childhood friends you haven’t seen since you were 8
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
teachers
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
old crushes and flings
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
random encounters with great conversation
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are some you’ll remember who don’t remember you.
(There are some you’ve forgotten who remember you well.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I did mine chronologically, walking through my life from past to present.
These are only people I met in-person and spent at least a few hours with.
What a trip.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some are dead.
Some might be.
Some have changed their names.
Some hate me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some day I’ll be dead, and this will still be posted.
(A reverse funeral! The dead remembering the living. Wow.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;To those listed here:&lt;/strong&gt; I remember you off the top of my head, think of you fondly, and you permanently affected me, even if we haven’t talked in years.
If you find this some day when Googling your name, &lt;a href="/"&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; to say hello.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mark Hemstreet
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Theresa Mucha
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lizzy Daymont
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sharon Danesi
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Greg Miller
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Della Stoody
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Andy Blaszczak
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pam Blaszczak
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mark Strigl
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Scott Lane
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jenevaire Nieponski
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Efi Panagiotaros
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Wendy Tu
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Michelle Kim
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lisa Kim
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bob Conforti
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Cathy Richardson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kathy Lauer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mandy Perry
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Matt Mead
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Adriana Rodek
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kimo Williams
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Chantelle Hougland
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Eddie Martinez
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Cameron Wiley
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mark Salvati
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Don Corey
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Matt Lambiase
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rob Bailey
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jack Perricone
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Warren Senders
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Megan Miceli
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Derek Phillips
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ted Lowe
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Nikki Alcazar
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melissa Ferrick
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Dan Charneco
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Diana Dora Gonzales
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tarleton Reynolds
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Greg Morell
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
John Walkonen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ray Grins
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Travis Bear
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Peter Schaeffer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Stephen King
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ryan Dekoe
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Milee Hill
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kenli and Daniela Mattus
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
David Friendly
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rachael Sage
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Meredith Kleinman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Zooey Tidal
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mark Fried
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jeff Cohen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kenny MacPherson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Paula Rogers
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rob Weitzner
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sam Anderson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Loey Nelson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lorraine Ferro
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tina Shafer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jane Kelly Williams
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Harvey White
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Nick Ruechel
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Allan Tepper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tony Benjamin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Hoover Li
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ryuichi Sakamoto
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sienna Madoka Isobe
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Masako Marky Muto
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Brandon Macaraeg
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Camille Collins-Lovell
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jim Collins
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Susan Lovell
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sally Kim
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Aurelie Jezequel
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Amelia Winger-Bearskin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rodney Ledbetter
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pete Williamson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Christine Clarke
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Elisabeth Bruksås
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Gary Henry
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Gillian Perrone
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jessica Hardin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Caroline Hay
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rasmus Jensen and Tina
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
John Steup
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
David Hooper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sarah S:t Clair Renard
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Nicole Sligar
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Richard Lynch
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tom Chernaik
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jen Drobny
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ariel Hyatt
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mark Roemer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Carolyn Ballen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Linus Gelber
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Joyce Dollinger
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Margee Fagelson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Holly Figueroa
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Brian Austin Whitney
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Noel Ramos
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ben Kihnel
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Dan Abell
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Margaret Morris
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Alex Steininger
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pamela Rooney
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Stacy Bias
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Michele Kaeder
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Chad Dahlstrom
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jamie Chvotkin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kristen Arnett
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jennifer Marks
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sam Shaber
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Seth Swirsky
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Teddy Goldstein
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Larkin McLain
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Michael Laskow
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tony Van Veen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sarah Fimm
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Talia Paul
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lee Rone
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Michele Citrin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bird York
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Julie Delpy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kat Parsons
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Milt Olin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Hank Barry
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Dina LaPolt
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jac Holzman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ian Rogers
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jackie Brubaker
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bruce Haring
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melinda Newman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lynn Grossman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Charlotte Martin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Benjamin Groff
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Larry Weintraub
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jody Whitesides
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jason Fiber
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Gary Jules
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jude Cristobal
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
John and JoAnn Braheny
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jon Kertzer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Joy Ann Maphisto
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ari and Daneka Soudak
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Terami and Kevin Benson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tracy Spuehler and AJ
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jennifer Yeko
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jenny Toomey
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Whitney Brousard
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Xeni Jardin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Hal Bringman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rebekah Del Rio
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Hans Veldhuizen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Heather Q
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ronna Jones
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Peleg Top
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Robert Kaye
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jared Rose
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kaitlin McGaw
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Steve Seskin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Danelle Romain
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kristin Mitsu Shiga
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jeremy Kemper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jason Fried
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tracy Biggerstaff
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Damiana Merryweather
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Robby Russell
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Amber Turner
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lori Purifoy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Damiana Merryweather
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Denise Whitney
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pam Lovall
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Karla Starr
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Megan Bassett
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
John Buckman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Clem Chambers
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Claire Pettifor
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kay Elizabeth
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Shona Rose
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Emma Partridge
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Steve Zipper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kerry Albright
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lisa Tennant
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Louise Boddy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Andrew Dubber
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melanie Hersch
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tim Ferriss
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jeff Patterson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Brian Zisk
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Antony Brydon
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Celine Zaphiratos
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bigir and Kola
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Diana Tauder
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Nina Storey
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Mara Hitner
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Laura Roeder
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tina Su
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Gina Wong
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Kevin Leflar
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tynan
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ben Scofield
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Chad Fowler
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Andy Hunt
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Amber Rubarth
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Laura Cayer
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Marina V
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jeff Marx
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pilar Otero
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tracy Dempsey
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Aly Tadros
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ashley Dorr
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Tamara Nile
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Maya Solovéy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Bruno and Flavia Pinaud
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Alê Braga
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Carla Hall
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Valerie Cho
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Alex Dalessio
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ramit Sethi
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Maria Popova
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Marian Spear
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melissa Rebronja
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Calitin Roper
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Peter Gregson
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rick Goetz
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Dan Goldman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sandira Calviac
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Dustin Curtis
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Greg Galant
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Anna Pillsbury
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Joke Sitsen
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Rob Newberry
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Peter Spellman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Harry Beckwith
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Seth Godin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Amber Rae Lambke
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Ishita Gupta
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Robert Gupta
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Vijay Nair
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Gaurav Vaz
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Lakshmi Pratury
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jay Narayanan
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pragnya Alekal
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Wally Tham
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Amizadai Lee
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Shahnila Islam
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Meng Weng Wong
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melissa Lewis
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Hugh Mason
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Benjamin Joffe
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Carl Coryell-Martin
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pete Kellock
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Alex Marquez
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Cherry and Jon
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Barry and Martine Nijenhuis
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Andrew and Nora Crothers
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Fredrik and Elaine Härén
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jeremy Snyder and Kelly
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Juanita Sabapathy
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Michael Maltese
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Melanie Hui
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Jason Ong
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Min Xuan Lee
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Patrick Turner
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Benson Engelbert
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Arief Aziz
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Daniel Ziv
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Chris Guillebeau
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Josh Kaufman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Sajitha Begum Jahangir (now Saj Sivers)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;To those not listed:&lt;/strong&gt;  Memory isn’t perfect.  Sorry!
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The co-op business model: share whatever you've got</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/sharing</id>
    <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2011-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/sharing"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I feel like I know almost nothing about business, because the only business I’ve ever done is the &lt;strong&gt;co-op / sharing&lt;/strong&gt; model.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It goes like this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1. You already have something that people want.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It might be something you own, something you’ve learned how to do, or access to valuable resources, space, or people.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Find a way to share it with everyone who needs it.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Share because it’s what you do for friends, because it’s the right thing to do, because it makes the world a better place, and because it’ll make you deeply happy. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Share as your contribution in return for all the things and ideas that people have shared with you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(If you’re having a bad day, or someone has recently wronged you, you may not feel the world has shared much with you, but &lt;a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/x8m5d0_everything-is-amazing-and-nobody-i_fun"&gt;here’s a reminder&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. If it takes some effort for you to share it, you can charge a little something for your effort, to ensure that this giving can continue.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
My examples:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
In 1994, the U.S. Copyright office still didn’t have their &lt;strong&gt;copyright forms&lt;/strong&gt; online.
You still had to mail a letter to Washington DC to ask them to mail you some blank forms, if you wanted to copyright your songs.
&lt;br /&gt;
I scanned all the forms, and put them on my website for free as printable downloads, for any musician who needed them.
&lt;br /&gt;
For the next year or two, until the government started putting the forms online, my site was the only place to get them.
This was my first effort to contribute back to this great invention of the internet.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
In 1995, I learned &lt;strong&gt;how to trademark my band name.&lt;/strong&gt;
It took many hours of work to figure out the legalese, but I did it.
&lt;br /&gt;
I wrote out the step-by-step instructions and put them on my band’s website for free.
&lt;br /&gt;
For years it was the go-to resource for musicians who wanted to trademark their name.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
In 1996, I had &lt;a href="http://artificialrecords.com/"&gt;a little record label&lt;/a&gt;, so I got a &lt;strong&gt;UPC barcode account&lt;/strong&gt;, so I could put unique UPC barcodes on my CDs.
I had to pay $750 to the Universal Code Council to get a company account, but that meant I was allowed to create 100,000 products under my account.
Musician friends asked how, so I showed them how, but also said they could use one of my product IDs.
&lt;br /&gt;
At first, I did this for free, as a favor, until friends started sending strangers my way.
Because it took a little work to generate the number, create their EPS/TIFF graphic barcode, and keep track of their unique IDs forever, I charged $20.
&lt;br /&gt;
Over the next 12 years, this made me almost $2 million.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
In 1997, I got a &lt;strong&gt;credit card merchant account&lt;/strong&gt; to sell my own CD at live shows.
It cost $1000 in set-up fees and took three months of red-tape paperwork.
Then I built a little online shopping cart, which also took months of work, just to sell my own CD.
Musician friends asked if they could use mine instead of having to go through all of that work, so I said OK.
&lt;br /&gt;
At first, I did this for free, as a favor, until it was taking up all of my time.
Because it took me 45 minutes of work to digitize, stock, set up a new album in my system, I charged $35 per new album.
Because it took 10 minutes of work to pick, pack, and ship a purchased CD, I charged $4 per CD sold.
&lt;br /&gt;
Over the next 12 years, this made me about $20 million.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
In 1999, I had learned a lot about &lt;strong&gt;hosting websites.&lt;/strong&gt;
Linux, Apache, PHP, SQL, FTP, DNS, Qmail, SpamAssassin, etc.
I had done it for myself for my band’s website, then for CD Baby, and bought my own servers.
So when friends would complain about their existing web-hosting company, I’d host them on my servers instead.
&lt;br /&gt;
At first, I did this for free, as a favor, until it was filling up my server.
Because each server cost me $300/month, and I had to hire a full-time person to manage this, I charged $20 per month.
(In 1999 this was way cheap.)
&lt;br /&gt;
Over the next 9 years, this made me about $5 million.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Since 2000, I’ve been sharing &lt;strong&gt;everything I’ve learned&lt;/strong&gt; for free.
I’m not the smartest guy, &lt;a href="/below-average"&gt;probably below average&lt;/a&gt;, but it costs nothing to share, and it’s the right thing to do, so I do.
&lt;br /&gt;
Over the last 11 years, this made me incredibly happy and lucky, because of all the interesting people I’ve met by doing it.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Point being:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
None of these things looked like a business venture.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All of them were just sharing something I already had.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
People often ask me if I have any suggestions for what kind of business they should get into.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I tell them the only thing I know how to recommend: “&lt;strong&gt;Start by sharing whatever you’ve got.&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/sharing.jpg" alt="http://www.sexysocialmedia.com/brrwr-sharing-is-caring/" /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
