<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://sivers.org/en.atom</id>
  <title>Derek Sivers</title>
  <updated>2016-01-18T19:43:18+08:00</updated>
  <link href="http://sivers.org/"/>
  <author>
    <name>Derek Sivers</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>nownownow.com</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/now3</id>
    <updated>2015-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/now3"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	A month ago I announced &lt;a href="/nowff"&gt;the /now page movement&lt;/a&gt;, where many personal websites are adding a “/now” page to answer the question, “What are you focused on now?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	At the time, only ten websites had a /now page.
	Now there are over 280.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s incredible.
	People are saying it helps them prioritize and focus.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://gregalbritton.com/now"&gt;Greg Albritton&lt;/a&gt; emailed to say he made a list of everyone with a /now page.
	So I turned that into its own website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://nownownow.com/"&gt;nownownow.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s been a fun programming project.
	I’ve been doing it full-time for the past month.
	&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/nownownow.com"&gt;See the code&lt;/a&gt;, if interested.
	It’s all open source.
	(Thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/SaschaKrause"&gt;Sascha Krause&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin for contributing a better design.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then Greg wanted to do feature profiles, so he came up with six questions that I asked everyone.
	Now if you click the (+) by any link on &lt;a href="http://nownownow.com/"&gt;nownownow.com&lt;/a&gt;, it will bring you to a page where you can get to know the person behind the site.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s addicting and inspiring to browse these profiles, and visit their sites.
	There’s a Twitter account — &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NowNowNow"&gt;@NowNowNow&lt;/a&gt; — that tweets out a link to a new profile every hour.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	People have told me they are getting a good amount of traffic to their site from people browsing &lt;a href="http://nownownow.com/"&gt;nownownow.com&lt;/a&gt;, so…
&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;How to add yours?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;If you already have a website&lt;/strong&gt;, just add a new page.
	If you’re using WordPress, look for “Pages” on the left, and choose “Add New”.
	Give it a “permalink” of /now.
	(Sorry I can’t help with tech support.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Write something about what you’re doing now, and publish.
	&lt;strong&gt;Once it’s online, email me the link at &lt;a href="mailto:derek@sivers.org"&gt;derek@sivers.org&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll add it to nownownow.com.&lt;/strong&gt;
	After it’s up, I’ll ask you the questions for a profile page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t have a website&lt;/strong&gt;, but have been meaning to get one, create a free one at &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com/"&gt;wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;.
	Before you announce it, I highly recommend getting your own domain name at &lt;a href="https://www.hover.com/"&gt;hover.com&lt;/a&gt;.
	Point your domain to your WordPress blog, and use that.
	(Again, sorry I can’t help with tech support, but this is very common stuff, so anyone else can.)
&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;What now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Someone asked me what my vision is for the /now page movement.
	But I’ve never had one.
	I just enjoy being of service.
	&lt;strong&gt;People tell me what they want, and if it’s something I can do, I do.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So if you have a good idea for what this could use or could be, please leave a comment here, or email me at &lt;a href="mailto:derek@sivers.org"&gt;derek@sivers.org&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://nownownow.com/"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/nowclock.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The /now page movement</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/nowff</id>
    <updated>2015-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/nowff"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	People often ask me what I’m doing now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Each time I would type out a reply, describing where I’m at, what I’m focused on, and what I’m not.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So earlier this year I added a &lt;a href="/now"&gt;/now&lt;/a&gt; page to my site:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="/now"&gt;sivers.org/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A simple link.
	Easy to remember.
	Easy to type.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s a nice reminder for myself, when I’m feeling unfocused.
	A public declaration of priorities.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	(If I’m doing something that’s not on my list, is it something I want to add, or something I want to stop?)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It helps me &lt;a href="/no2"&gt;say no&lt;/a&gt;, too.
	When I decline invitations, I point them to that page to let them know it’s not personal.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Anyway, &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt; the brilliant Gregory Brown announced that &lt;strong&gt;he added &lt;a href="http://practicingdeveloper.com/now/"&gt;a /now page&lt;/a&gt; to his site!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I re-tweeted his announcement, and &lt;strong&gt;within hours, 8 more people made a /now page!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mikevial.com/now/"&gt;mikevial.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theubergeekgirl.com/now/"&gt;theubergeekgirl.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blitzprog.org/now"&gt;blitzprog.org/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.notkindacool.com/now/"&gt;notkindacool.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.marclittlemore.com/now/"&gt;marclittlemore.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://marcjenkins.co.uk/now/"&gt;marcjenkins.co.uk/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://lewiswalsh.com/now/"&gt;lewiswalsh.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://garrickvanburen.com/now/"&gt;garrickvanburen.com/now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	I love it!
	I wish &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; had one!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;If you make a /now page on your site, please add the URL in the body of a comment, below.&lt;/strong&gt;
	Use the full http:// URL, so it will be a clickable link.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update: all /now pages listed at &lt;a href="http://nownownow.com/"&gt;nownownow.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	(You do get what’s going on here, don’t you?
	Gregory Brown has &lt;a href="/ff"&gt;started a movement&lt;/a&gt;!)
☺
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/ff" title="First follower: leadership lessons learned from a dancing guy"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/dancing-guy.jpg" alt="first follower dancing guy"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Relax for the same result</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/relax</id>
    <updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/relax"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	A few years ago, I lived in Santa Monica, California, right on the beach.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There’s a great bike path that goes along the ocean for 7½ miles.
	So, 15 miles round trip.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	On weekday afternoons, it’s almost empty.
	It’s perfect for going full-speed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So a few times a week, I’d get on &lt;a href="http://surlybikes.com/bikes/pacer"&gt;my bike&lt;/a&gt; and go as fast as I could for the 15 mile loop.
	I mean really full-on, 100%, head-down, red-faced, sprinting.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’d finish exhausted, and look at the time.
	&lt;strong&gt;43 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;
	Every time.
	Maybe a minute more on a really windy day.
	But basically always 43 minutes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	After a few months, I noticed I was getting less enthusiastic about this bike ride.
	I think had mentally linked it with being completely exhausted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So one day I decided &lt;strong&gt;I would do the same ride, but just chill&lt;/strong&gt;.
	Take it easy, nice and slow.
	OK not &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt;-slow, but dialing it back to about 50% of my usual effort.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	And ahhh....
	What a fun ride.
	I was relaxed, and smiling, and looking around.
	Not red-faced.
	I was barely giving it any effort.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I saw two dolphins in the water.
	A pelican flew right over me in Marina del Ray.
	When I looked up to say “wow!”, he shit in my mouth.
	I can still remember that taste of digested shellfish.
	I had to laugh at the novelty of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’m usually so damn driven, always doing everything as intensely as I can.
	It was so nice to take it easy for once.
	I felt I could do this forever, without any exhaustion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I finished, I looked at the time.
	&lt;strong&gt;45 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	What?!? How could that be?
	Yep. I double-checked.
	45 minutes, as compared to my usual 43.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So apparently all of that exhausting, red-faced, full-on push-push-push I had been doing only gave me a &lt;strong&gt;4%&lt;/strong&gt; boost.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I could just take it easy, and get &lt;strong&gt;96% of the results&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	And what a difference in experience!
	To go the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; distance, in about the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; time, but one way leaves me exhausted, and the other way rejeuvenated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This was really profound for me, and I think of it often.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I notice I’m all stressed-out about something, or driving myself to exhaustion, I remember that bike ride, and try dialing back my effort by 50%.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s been amazing how often everything gets done just as well and just as fast, with what &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; like 50% of the effort.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Which, of course, makes me realize that much of my effort apparently wasn’t effort at all, but just ineffective stress added on top of something to make it &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I’m doing the best I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/bikesand.jpg"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;
	Bicycle photo &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mike-dean/12008975114"&gt;© Mike Dean&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Saying no to everything else</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/no2</id>
    <updated>2015-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/no2"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://www.stevenpressfield.com/about/"&gt;Steven Pressfield&lt;/a&gt; had called himself an author for years, but he’d never actually finished a book.
	He just went through life feeling smug, feeling better than those regular schmucks, because he thought of himself as an author.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But the psychological pain of not producing kept building until he couldn’t stand it anymore.
	He decided to finally beat that devil he calls “The Resistance”.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	He created a situation with no escape.
	Rented a cabin with only a typewriter, and shut off all other options.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	“I had a book in mind and I had decided I would finish it or kill myself.
	I could not run away again, or let people down again, or let myself down again.
	This was it, do or die.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	“I didn’t talk to anybody during [that year].
	I didn’t hang out.
	I had no TV, no radio, no music.
	No sex, no sports.
	I didn’t read the newspaper.
	I just worked.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	After an incredibly difficult year of wrestling with those inner demons and avoiding all temptations, he did it.
	He finished his first book.
	It wasn’t a success, but it didn’t matter.
	He had finally beat The Resistance.
	He went on to write many successful novels.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	He told this story in the great book “&lt;a href="/book/TurningPro"&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/a&gt;”, the third in his series of little books about the creative struggle, including “&lt;a href="/book/WarOfArt"&gt;The War of Art&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href="/book/DoTheWork"&gt;Do the Work&lt;/a&gt;”.
	Read all three.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I read it in 2012, my own psychological pain of not producing had built up to an unbearable level.
	I had loudly announced &lt;a href="http://muckwork.com/"&gt;Muckwork&lt;/a&gt;, my brilliant new business idea, in 2008, but never finished making it.
	I had loudly announced &lt;a href="/song-contest-idea"&gt;Songtest&lt;/a&gt;, a free open song contest idea, in 2009, but never finished making it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I started many times, but each time decided to chase some other distraction that didn’t put my ass on the line, instead.
	There are always more emails to answer, always more things to learn, and always more people with enticing requests for me to help them achieve their dreams.
	(Each one swearing it’ll be just an hour of my time, tops.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	To make it worse, I was living in distracting Singapore, surrounded by so many interesting people.
	And with a short flight I could be in &lt;a href="http://www.tigerair.com/sg/en/real_deals.php"&gt;16 countries for under $200&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So I decided to do my version of the Steven Pressfield cabin.
	I &lt;a href="/here"&gt;moved to New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;.
	I shut off all other options.
	Time to finish what I started.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Except for better or for worse, I still answer my email.
	I still get a hundred requests a week, but now it’s easier to say no to all of them, since &lt;a href="/local"&gt;I’m not local&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s not the nicest mantra, saying “no”, “no”, “no” all day, but it is a reminder of why I’m here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’m posting this now because a few people have asked why &lt;a href="/now"&gt;I say no to all requests&lt;/a&gt;, so I hope this helps explain.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But also this makes it a follow-up to my popular “&lt;a href="/hellyeah"&gt;Hell Yeah or No&lt;/a&gt;” post.
	There’s another level beyond that.
	It’s &lt;strong&gt;saying yes to one thing, and no to absolutely &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; else&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/nopink.jpg"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/lilivc/643831993/"&gt;Lili Vieira de Carvalho&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
	
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“Just tell me what to do”: compressing knowledge into directives</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/2do</id>
    <updated>2015-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/2do"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;h3&gt;
	Internalizing books
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Wanting to be successful, I’ve always read every book I thought could help.
	Even if a book had just one useful insight, it was worth the $20 and my time spent reading and thinking.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A few years ago, I realized I was forgetting the lessons I’d learned from past books.
	So I started taking detailed notes while reading, saving every important idea.
	I wanted to permanently remember what I’d learned, and act on it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I saved these notes as text files and put them on my phone, so I could review them often.
	Now I also share them on my site at &lt;a href="/book"&gt;sivers.org/book&lt;/a&gt;.
	There are over 200 books there now, with my top recommendations at the top. Enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	“Just tell me what to do.”
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	When I’d tell my friends about a great book I’d just read, they didn’t want to read it.
	They didn’t want 300 pages of anecdotes, explanations, and supporting arguments.
	They’d say, “Just tell me what to do.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I realized that for some things, I also don’t want the full 20-hour explanation.
	I’d be happier with just the conclusions — the actions — the directives.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For example, I’d heard great things about Michael Pollan’s book “&lt;a href="http://michaelpollan.com/books/the-omnivores-dilemma/"&gt;The Omnivore’s Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;”.
	But 450 pages about the history of food?  Eh...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then two years later he wrote “&lt;a href="http://michaelpollan.com/books/in-defense-of-food/"&gt;In Defense of Food&lt;/a&gt;”.
	It sounded like a tighter argument at 250 pages, but... eh....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then he wrote “&lt;a href="http://michaelpollan.com/books/food-rules/"&gt;Food Rules&lt;/a&gt;”, a tiny little book that &lt;strong&gt;compresses all of his advice into 64 sentences&lt;/strong&gt;.
	&lt;a href="/hellyeah"&gt;Hell yeah!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It takes only 30 minutes to read, with succinct advice like “Eat only foods that will eventually rot.” and “Avoid food products that make health claims.”
	Each point has just a few sentences of explanation.
	That’s all I needed, because I already trust him.
	But you can reference his previous book if you want the supporting evidence behind the advice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Compressing wisdom into directives — (“Do &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;.”) — is so valuable, but so rarely done.
	It feels arrogant and imperial to tell people what to do.
	Who am I to order people around?
	On the other hand, who am I &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to?
	It’s useful to people, so do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’m humble.
	I don’t expect anyone to actually do what I say.
	It’s just a succinct and powerful way to communicate an idea.
	Focus on the action.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Compressing all this wisdom into directives
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	So I spent the last few months going through all my notes for 220 books.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	First I extracted just the most essential and counterintuitive points.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then the hardest part was turning observations into advice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For example, this observation —
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	“Behavioral psychologists Stephen M. Garcia and Avishalom Tor showed that merely knowing there are more competitors in a competition decreases our performance.”
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
	— turns into this advice:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	“Avoid awareness of competitors.”
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But what about this observation?
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	“Half a group was shown that extraverts are more successful.  Other half shown that introverts are more successful.  Then when asked to recall events from their past to help determine which they were, they remembered just the events that support the successful group they were told.”
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
	How would you turn that into advice?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	The result?
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	I’ve now got hundreds of these wise directives.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I tried turning them into a 30-minute talk for a conference, but it was a disaster.
	Fun for the first three minutes, then overwhelming.
	A 30-minute TO-DO list that would take a lifetime to complete.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I would just list them all here, but I think that would be less useful.
	I like presenting &lt;a href="/1idea"&gt;one idea at a time&lt;/a&gt;.
	With just the directive and a short explanation, it’s a good blog format.
	I’ll link them back to this page for a meta-explanation, and update this page with links to them when I do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Maybe I’ll turn them into a book.
	(I like the title “Do This”.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Any other ideas?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;To be notified when I post these&lt;/strong&gt;, please get on &lt;a href="https://sivers.org/list"&gt;my private email list&lt;/a&gt;.
	You can also follow my 
	&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sivers"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
	&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/sivers"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
	&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+DerekSivers1/"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;, or
	&lt;a href="http://sivers.org/en.atom"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="/images/bonsai.jpg" width="600" height="398" alt="picture of Bonsai tree"&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Bonsai photo by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/grufnik/408948777"&gt;Grufnik&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Simplify: move code into database functions</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/pg</id>
    <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/pg"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
If you are a web or API developer, programming code that uses an SQL database, this is for you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ve found a very different and useful way to structure code.
It’s made such a big difference for me that I had to share it here.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
How things are
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Most web development — whether custom or using frameworks like Rails, Django, Laravel, Sinatra, Flask, and Symfony — tends to work the same way:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
At the core is a &lt;strong&gt;database&lt;/strong&gt;, which is just the storage of data.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; is in Ruby/Python/PHP/JavaScript classes.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
Why that’s bad
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These norms have some dangerous implications:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Everything&lt;/strong&gt; must go through these Ruby/Python/PHP/JavaScript classes — including shell scripts and other things not part of this website.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nothing&lt;/strong&gt; else may access the database directly, since doing so may break the rules defined by these surrounding classes.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;database is treated as dumb storage&lt;/strong&gt;, even though the database is smart enough to have most of this logic built-in.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
But if you add business rules into the database itself, it’s now &lt;strong&gt;duplicated&lt;/strong&gt;, requiring changing in multiple places if the rules change.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
These two systems — the database and its surrounding code — are &lt;strong&gt;coupled and dependent&lt;/strong&gt; on eachother.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
If it’s ever advantageous to &lt;strong&gt;switch languages&lt;/strong&gt; (say from Ruby to JavaScript, or Python to Elixir), you’re going to have to &lt;strong&gt;re-write absolutely everything&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
Simple vs complex
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please go watch this amazing 35-minute talk as soon as possible:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rI8tNMsozo0"&gt;Simplicity Matters by Rich Hickey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here are his important points for this article:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
“&lt;strong&gt;Complex&lt;/strong&gt;” is objective.
It means &lt;strong&gt;many things tied together&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
“&lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt;” is objective.
It means &lt;strong&gt;one ingredient&lt;/strong&gt; — the opposite of complex.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
These are unrelated to “easy”.
It is easy to install and bind yourself to something very complex (like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-relational_mapping"&gt;ORM&lt;/a&gt;), and can be hard to build something simple.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Classes, models, and methods (&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming"&gt;OOP&lt;/a&gt;) are an &lt;strong&gt;unnecessary complication&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Information is simple, so &lt;strong&gt;don’t hide it&lt;/strong&gt; behind a micro-language.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Work with values directly&lt;/strong&gt;: hash/map of strings.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Since a &lt;strong&gt;JSON API&lt;/strong&gt; — a hash/map of strings — is often the eventual interface, it’s even more reason to skip the abstractions and work with values directly.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
Why this hit home for me
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’ve been using the same SQL database since 1997: same data, values, and SQL tables.
But the code around it has changed so many times.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In 1997, I started in Perl.
In 1998, I switched to PHP.
In 2004, a rewrite in Rails.
In 2007, &lt;a href="/rails2php"&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; to PHP.
In 2009, minimalist Ruby.
In 2012, client-side JavaScript.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Each time I’d have to re-write all of the logic around the database&lt;/strong&gt;:
how to add a new person into the database,
how to verify an invoice is correct,
how to mark an order as paid, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;that whole time, my trusty PostgreSQL database stayed the same&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since most of this is &lt;a href="http://rob.conery.io/2015/02/21/its-time-to-get-over-that-stored-procedure-aversion-you-have/"&gt;data logic, not business logic&lt;/a&gt;, it should be in the database.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I'm putting this data logic directly into &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/about/"&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;, since I plan to stay with it for many more years, but plan to keep experimenting with programming languages.
(TO-DO: &lt;a href="https://www.haskell.org/"&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://elixir-lang.org/"&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://racket-lang.org/"&gt;Racket&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.lua.org/about.html"&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
How things could be
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Web developers have been treating the database as dumb storage, but it’s actually &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/server-programming.html"&gt;quite smart&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s &lt;strong&gt;simple&lt;/strong&gt; to have all of this intelligence &lt;strong&gt;in the database itself&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s &lt;strong&gt;complex&lt;/strong&gt; to have it tied to surrounding outside code.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once you put all of the intelligence directly into the database, then the outside code disappears!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then &lt;strong&gt;the database is self-contained, and not tied to anything&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Your outside interface can &lt;strong&gt;switch&lt;/strong&gt; to JavaScript, Haskell, Elixir or anything else with ease, because your core intelligence is all inside the database.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
How to do it
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
Table constraints
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The easiest place to start is &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/ddl-constraints.html"&gt;constraints&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
CREATE TABLE people (
  id serial primary key,
  name text NOT NULL CONSTRAINT no_name CHECK (LENGTH(name) &gt; 0),
  email text UNIQUE CONSTRAINT valid_email CHECK (email ~ '\A\S+@\S+\.\S+\Z')
);
CREATE TABLE tags (
  person_id integer NOT NULL REFERENCES people(id) ON DELETE CASCADE,
  tag varchar(16) CONSTRAINT tag_format CHECK (statkey ~ '\A[a-z0-9._-]+\Z')
);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Define what is considered valid/invalid data here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In my people example above, it says name can’t be empty, email must match that pattern with “@” and “.” and no whitespace.  Then it says tags.person_id has to exist in the people table, but if the person is deleted then delete the tags, too.  And the tag has to fit that regexp pattern of lowercase letters, numbers, dot, underscore, dash.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It helps to name your constraints for later use in error catching.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
Triggers
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For things that happen before or after you alter data, use &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/trigger-definition.html"&gt;triggers&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
CREATE FUNCTION clean() RETURNS TRIGGER AS $$
BEGIN
  NEW.name = btrim(regexp_replace(NEW.name, '\s+', ' ', 'g'));
  NEW.email = lower(regexp_replace(NEW.email, '\s', '', 'g'));
END;
$$ LANGUAGE plpgsql;
CREATE TRIGGER clean BEFORE INSERT OR UPDATE OF name, email ON people
  FOR EACH ROW EXECUTE PROCEDURE clean();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This example cleans the input before it’s put into the database, in case someone accidently put a space in their email address, or a line-break in their name.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
Functions
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Make little re-usable functions for things you’ll use often inside your code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
CREATE FUNCTION get_person(a_name text, a_email text) RETURNS SETOF people AS $$
BEGIN
  IF NOT EXISTS (SELECT 1 FROM people WHERE email = a_email) THEN
    RETURN QUERY INSERT INTO people (name, email)
      VALUES (a_name, a_email) RETURNING people.*;
  ELSE
    RETURN QUERY SELECT * FROM people WHERE email = a_email;
  END IF;
END;
$$ LANGUAGE plpgsql;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That’s one I use often:
Given someone’s name and email, if they’re not already in my database, add them.
Then, either way, return the database info for this person.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
Views for JSON
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Instead of requiring outside code to convert your data into JSON, you can have the &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/functions-json.html#FUNCTIONS-JSON-CREATION-TABLE"&gt;database create JSON directly&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For this, use &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/sql-createview.html"&gt;views&lt;/a&gt; as JSON structure templates.
Inside the view, use &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/functions-aggregate.html"&gt;json_agg&lt;/a&gt; for nested values.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
CREATE VIEW person_view AS
  SELECT *, (SELECT json_agg(t) AS tags FROM
    (SELECT tag FROM tags WHERE person_id=people.id) t)
  FROM people;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This will be used in the API functions, below:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
API functions
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These are the only functions your outside code will access.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They return only JSON.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
CREATE FUNCTION update_password(p_id integer, nu_pass text, OUT js json) AS $$
BEGIN
  UPDATE people SET password=crypt(nu_pass, gen_salt('bf', 8)) WHERE id = p_id;
  js := row_to_json(r) FROM (SELECT * FROM person_view WHERE id = p_id) r;
END;
$$ LANGUAGE plpgsql;

CREATE FUNCTION people_with_tag(a_tag text, OUT js json) AS $$
BEGIN
  js := json_agg(r) FROM
    (SELECT * FROM person_view WHERE id IN
      (SELECT person_id FROM tags WHERE tag = a_tag)) r;
END;
$$ LANGUAGE plpgsql;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No matter what you need to do with your database, the &lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/xplang.html"&gt;procedural languages built-in to PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.4/static/plpgsql-overview.html"&gt;PL/pgSQL&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;not the most beautiful language&lt;/strong&gt;, but the &lt;strong&gt;simplicity&lt;/strong&gt; of having everything in the database is worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you like JavaScript, check out the promising &lt;a href="https://github.com/plv8/plv8/blob/master/README.md"&gt;plv8&lt;/a&gt;, with a good &lt;a href="http://plv8-talk.herokuapp.com/"&gt;presentation about it, here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
Now, if you need a REST API:
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
require 'pg'
require 'sinatra'
DB = PG::Connection.new(dbconfig)

def qry(sql, params=[])
  @res = DB.exec_params('SELECT js FROM ' + sql, params)
end

after do
  content_type 'application/json'
  body @res[0]['js']
end

get '/people' do
  qry('get_people()')
end

get %r{/people/([0-9]+)} do |id|
  qry('get_person($1)', [id])
end

put %r{/people/([0-9]+)} do |id|
  qry('update_password($1, $2)', [id, params[:password]])
end

get '/people/tagged' do
  qry('people_with_tag($1)', [params[:tag]])
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
Or if you need a client library:
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
require 'pg'
require 'json'
DB = PG::Connection.new(dbconfig)

def js(func, params=[])
  res = DB.exec_params('SELECT js FROM ' + func, params)
  JSON.parse(res[0]['js'])
end

def people
  js('get_people()')
end

def person(id)
  js('get_person($1)', [id])
end

def update_password(id, newpass)
  js('update_password($1, $2)', [id, newpass])
end

def people_tagged(tag)
  js('people_with_tag($1)', [tag])
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
That’s it!
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now whether a REST API or client library, &lt;strong&gt;all it really has to do is pass the arguments into the database functions, and return the JSON&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I simplified the tiny code examples here, but feel free to see &lt;strong&gt;some real working examples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/db-api/blob/master/peeps/tables.sql"&gt;table definitions&lt;/a&gt; with constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/db-api/blob/master/peeps/triggers.sql"&gt;triggers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/db-api/blob/master/woodegg/views.sql"&gt;views&lt;/a&gt; for JSON creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/db-api/blob/master/peeps/functions.sql"&gt;functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/50pop/db-api/blob/master/HTTP/woodegg.rb?ts=2"&gt;REST API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my little &lt;a href="https://github.com/sivers/pg"&gt;PostgreSQL experiments&lt;/a&gt; where I try out ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I’m not trying to convince everyone to do things this way.
But I hope you find it useful or at least interesting to consider.
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting out of a bad place</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/bad</id>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2015-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/bad"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	This was actually a private email to a good friend.
	But he loved it and forwarded it to some people, and they all suggested I should post it on my site.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	A few months ago I was in a really bad place.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Really upset ALL the time about the whole situation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Couldn’t think straight.
	Very reactionary.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Wanting to make some big drastic change, just to ease the discomfort of uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt; — that pain of living with an unknown future.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’re definitely in that place now.
	So &lt;strong&gt;here’s how I got out.&lt;/strong&gt;
	Maybe it helps.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
#1.
	Ask myself “What’s wrong RIGHT NOW?” — this very second.
	Am I in physical pain or danger?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	No.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’ve got mental pain, but that’s just me &lt;strong&gt;imagining&lt;/strong&gt; things, or &lt;strong&gt;remembering&lt;/strong&gt; things.
	None of it is real.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If I put aside the mental torture I’m giving myself, the only thing that’s real is this physical moment.
	Is it so bad?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Hm.
	No.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Look around.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Nice day.
	Nice place.
	Nice food.
	Nice people.
	Nice work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Of course the mental anguish is still there, but it’s a nice reminder that it’s all in my head.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
#2.
	Observe now. Act later.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I'm feeling so cloudy, my decisions and actions will be cloudy too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So I wait a few days before acting on anything.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Just &lt;strong&gt;watch the emotions pass by like a thunderstorm&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	And the longer I wait, the &lt;a href="/walkways"&gt;smarter I get&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
#3.
	Raise standards.
	Say no to anything less than great.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Every person that doesn’t &lt;strong&gt;rejeuvenate&lt;/strong&gt; me and make me feel better, say no.
	Blacklist them.
	Banned.
	Not allowed in, not even for a minute.
	No explanation needed.
	No compromise.
	No favors.
	Done.
	Gone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	More fountains, less drains.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Every thing I’m doing that isn’t good for me.
	Every thing I’m eating or drinking that isn’t making me more healthy.
	Stop.
	Say no.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This even means saying no to half-ass conversations that are not whole-hearted and unconflicted.
	People that are “fine” and I “kill time” with, but don’t actually love and actively enjoy?
	&lt;a href="/hellyeah"&gt;Nope.&lt;/a&gt;
	Not good enough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Doing this gave me a huge feeling of self-worth.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Setting the bar really high for something to take my time.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It means more empty time, but that leaves room for POSSIBILITY!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Empty time has the POTENTIAL to be filled with nourishing and awesome new actions and people, whereas filling it with half-ass things and people kills all that potential and possibility.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
#4.
	Focus on my goal/mission/path
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The empty space created by #3 — no longer chasing distractions — helped me remember what I’m really doing with my life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Creating, learning, improving, whatever.
	For me, it’s writing, parenting, and health.
	For you, it’s something else.
	It’s the 10-year-plan type stuff.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Clearing the clutter helps you see the horizon.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s a HUGE energy-filled feeling of “Oh yeah! That’s where I’m going! I had forgotten! I can see it now! Let’s go!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It really helps make the “say no” thing stick, because once you’re heading towards a spot on the horizon, you just don’t let any crap get in your way.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
#5.
	Do ALL the daily mundane stuff
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This sounds silly, simple, and shallow, but it’s surprisingly effective:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I’m upset, I don’t feel like doing anything but wallowing in it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But despite feeling that way, I brush, floss, go to the gym, make healthy meals, take the kid out to play, do the dishes, clean the house, pick up clutter, vacuum, pay my bills, answer my emails, take my vitamins, do the laundry, play with the kid some more, brush and floss again, turn off the computer early, turn off the phone, and get to bed early.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s so mundane, but it really helps to feel on top of things.
	Things in life well-sorted so I don’t need to worry about them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	(And when I ask, “What’s wrong right now?” — it really helps me say “nothing!” when I look around and see this clean house, paid bills, happy child, and have a good night’s sleep.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s really peaceful to go through the motions, &lt;strong&gt;even though I don’t really feel like it&lt;/strong&gt;.
	It’s more time to think and process.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s a great reminder that I have to eat, even if I’m not feeling hungry.
	I have to clean the house, even if my mind is a mess.
	I have to sleep, no matter what!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Like #1, above, &lt;strong&gt;it separates the mental anguish from the physical reality.&lt;/strong&gt;
	Keeps me focused on what’s real versus what I’m just imagining.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	There’s more to it than that.
	Lots of diary time, friends, reading &lt;a href="/book"&gt;healthy new thoughts&lt;/a&gt;/philosophies, etc.
	But those are the big 5.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I hope it helps.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Derek&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/grasscrack.jpg" width="700" height="525" alt="John Keogh blades"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;small&gt;photo &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/jvk/279801645"&gt;by John Keogh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to change or build your career</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/career</id>
    <updated>2014-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/career"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I get emails from many people wanting to change or build their career.  I always recommend the best book on the subject: “&lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/a&gt;” by Cal Newport.  Here are a few of its best points:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forget passion and purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Forget “follow your passion” or “find your true calling”.  Stop thinking like that.  Here’s why:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Words like “passion” and “purpose” are dangerous because they sound huge and romantic.
If you think you haven’t found your passion yet, you’re probably &lt;strong&gt;expecting it to be overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt; — to hit you like lightning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Looking for your passion, purpose, or calling is an example of the &lt;a href="/mindset"&gt;fixed mindset&lt;/a&gt;.
You’re assuming that this is an inherent and unchanging thing inside of you, like trying to read your DNA or blood type.
But you won’t find passion and purpose there, because &lt;strong&gt;that’s not where those feelings come from.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Passion and purpose are &lt;strong&gt;emotions that come after expertise and experience.&lt;/strong&gt;
The way to get them is to commit to &lt;a href="/book/Mastery"&gt;the path of mastery&lt;/a&gt;, get great at something, and do great work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So instead of looking for passion and purpose, just keep mastering whatever work you’ve started, becoming more and more valuable in your field.
Passion and purpose will follow a great career.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Great careers are only for the rare and valuable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Think of what makes a great career:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good pay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;room to grow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;freedom and control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;positive impact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotionally rewarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Jobs like this are rare and valuable.
A great career isn’t something you &lt;strong&gt;find&lt;/strong&gt; - it’s something you &lt;strong&gt;earn&lt;/strong&gt; when you’ve got &lt;strong&gt;rare and valuable skills to offer in return.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In other words, you can only earn a great career by building your expertise and experience.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Solution: focus on the craft, not passion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The solution to this problem is what’s called “the craftman’s path” — the long-term path to mastery.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Everyone who became great at something has a similar story:
For years, they worked on their craft every day, even if they weren’t in the mood.
Always pushing, practicing, working, and improving.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It doesn’t matter if you’re feeling passionate about it that day or even that month.  You keep working and keep improving.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It doesn’t matter whether your work environment is ideal or you’re being wonderfully rewarded yet.  You keep working and keep improving.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes it takes thousands of hours of practice, but that’s good news!
&lt;strong&gt;It’s a clear path and it’s under your control&lt;/strong&gt;, instead of dwelling on unanswerable questions like “What is my true calling?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You forget the self-centered concerns about your passion and purpose, and instead just keep improving and getting really damn good.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It doesn’t matter if your current job isn’t perfect.
&lt;strong&gt;You just keep improving&lt;/strong&gt;, no matter where you are, &lt;strong&gt;becoming more and more valuable&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By building your skills, experience, and value, you earn a great career.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By building your skills, experience, and value, &lt;strong&gt;passion and purpose come to you&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By building your skills, experience, and value, you are building your “career capital”.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Career capital: use it to make a change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
“Career capital” is a metaphor.
Think of it like gold tokens you’re earning over years of building your expertise, experience, connections, and reputation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The important point is to &lt;strong&gt;remember how valuable it is&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you want to make a change to your career, you spend this career capital you’ve earned.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you’re really sick of your current field and want to switch to another field, &lt;strong&gt;don’t just quit and throw away all the career capital you’ve built up!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;If you’re thinking of quitting your job to follow your passion, please don’t miss this point!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Think of ways you can &lt;strong&gt;use the value you’ve built up&lt;/strong&gt; to make the transition to another field.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="/tarzan"&gt;Like Tarzan&lt;/a&gt;, use your connections, reputation, experience, and expertise to &lt;strong&gt;transition&lt;/strong&gt; into a better situation in the new field before leaving the old one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Realize the career capital you’ve built up already, and don’t just throw it away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Starting from scratch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you’re starting from scratch anyway, jump into any growing field and start building your skills, expertise, connections, and reputation.  Pick a niche and dominate it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you have no ideas, check out &lt;a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/rfs/"&gt;this list of what startup investors want to invest in&lt;/a&gt;.
And &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=jwt+things+to+watch"&gt;JWT’s “Things to Watch”&lt;/a&gt; is always fun and inspiring.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Read “&lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The ideas here are just a little incomplete intro to an amazing book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“&lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/a&gt;” by &lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/"&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;, is the best I’ve ever read on the subject of building or changing your career.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I just searched my email out-box and found out that I’ve personally recommended it to people over 92 times in the past two years.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If this subject interests you at all, please &lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;get and read the full book&lt;/a&gt;, not just my summary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/SoGood.gif" width="124" height="187" alt="Book cover"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fixed mindset vs Growth mindset</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/mindset</id>
    <updated>2014-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/mindset"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
One of the most important concepts I’ve learned is the difference between the “fixed” mindset and the “growth” mindset.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s a little bit like “nature vs nurture”:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
People in a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset believe you either are or aren’t good at something, based on your inherent nature, because it’s just who you are.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
People in a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset believe anyone can be good at anything, because your abilities are entirely due to your actions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This sounds simple, but it’s surprisingly deep.
&lt;strong&gt;The fixed mindset is the most common and the most harmful&lt;/strong&gt;, so it’s worth understanding and considering how it’s affecting you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For example:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a fixed mindset, you believe “She’s a natural born singer” or “I’m just no good at dancing.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a growth mindset, you believe “Anyone can be good at anything. Skill comes only from practice.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The fixed mindset believes trouble is devastating.&lt;/strong&gt;
If you believe, “You’re either naturally great or will never be great,” then when you have any trouble, your mind thinks, “See? You’ll never be great at this. Give up now.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The growth mindset believes trouble is just important feedback in the learning process.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Can you see how this subtle difference in mindset can change everything?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More examples:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you want to hide your flaws so you’re not judged or labeled a failure.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, your flaws are just a TO-DO list of things to improve.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you stick with what you know to keep up your confidence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you keep up your confidence by always pushing into the unfamiliar, to make sure you’re always learning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you look inside yourself to find your true passion and purpose, as if this is a hidden inherent thing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you commit to mastering valuable skills regardless of mood, knowing passion and purpose come from doing great work, which comes from expertise and experience.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, failures define you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, failures are temporary setbacks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you believe if you’re romantically compatible with someone, you should share all of eachother’s views, and everything should just come naturally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, you believe a lasting relationship comes from effort and working through inevitable differences.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;fixed&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, it’s all about the outcome. If you fail, you think all effort was wasted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; mindset, it’s all about the process, so the outcome hardly matters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And yes, the mindset itself is not fixed.  You can change your mindset just by thinking it through.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’ve talked about this in &lt;a href="/ml"&gt;my “Meaning of Life” talk&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="/failure"&gt;my “Why You Need to Fail” talk&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re interested in checking those out, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But I get no credit for these insights.  This is all from &lt;a href="/book/Mindset"&gt;Carol Dweck’s book, “Mindset”&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="/book/ArtOfLearning"&gt;Josh Waitzkin’s book, “The Art of Learning”&lt;/a&gt;, both of which I highly recommend.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="/book/Mindset"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/Mindset.gif" width="121" height="187" alt="Mindset - by Carol Dweck"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href="/book/ArtOfLearning"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ArtOfLearning.gif" width="124" height="187" alt="Art of Learning - by Josh Waitzkin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I love being wrong</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/lw</id>
    <updated>2014-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/lw"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Most of the time I feel smart, successful, and driven - like I’ve got it all figured out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But last month a bunch of stuff knocked me on my ass.  I’ve never felt so wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I vulnerably called on friends for help.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.homesweetpdx.com/our-story/"&gt;Amber&lt;/a&gt; reminded me to pull my head out of today, and think &lt;a href="/time"&gt;long-term&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Marx"&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt; told me to get my swagger back and relish the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ariel_Hyatt"&gt;Ariel&lt;/a&gt; said I should really accept and feel this pain, instead of moving on so fast like I always do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Each different perspective made me feel good for a while, then I’d fall back into the whirlpool of destructive thoughts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Whenever something’s wrong in my life, I’ve asked myself this amazing question:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;“What’s great about this?”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But now my only answer was, “Nothing. This just sucks.”  I tried asking it again every day or two, but the answer was the same.  Down the whirlpool I went.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After moping at the bottom of the ocean for a few weeks, I got a bright memory from my former self.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I actually love being wrong&lt;/strong&gt;, even though it cracks my confidence, &lt;strong&gt;because that’s the only time I learn.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I actually love being lost&lt;/strong&gt;, even though it fuels fears, &lt;strong&gt;because that’s when I go somewhere unexpected.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="/book"&gt;I pursue these things&lt;/a&gt; in small digestable doses.  I love little lessons that surprise my expectations and &lt;a href="http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/the-fireplace-delusion"&gt;change my mind&lt;/a&gt;.  &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;(This is why I aim to make &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/speakers/derek_sivers#talks"&gt;my TED talks&lt;/a&gt; surprising. If we’re not surprised, we’re not learning.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But I finally answered “What’s great about this?”:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Getting knocked on my ass made me humble as hell.  It’s been years since I’d called for help.  It’s been years since my &lt;a href="http://thebuddhistblog.blogspot.com/2007/08/zen-story-cup-of-tea.html"&gt;cup was so empty&lt;/a&gt;.  It’s been years since I was so open to advice. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I smiled, thinking of how much I’ve learned from my friends these past few weeks.  I realized how ultimately happy it makes me to be so empty, even if it really hurts at first.  &lt;strong&gt;It’s better than thinking I’ve got it all figured out.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And with that, the sun came up and the whirlpool went away.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you life.  Thank you friends.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/whirlpool.jpg" width="700" height="469" alt=""&gt;
&lt;p class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/30884177@N08/4107290250"&gt;David O’Hare&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The philosophy of great customer service</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/cs</id>
    <updated>2014-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/cs"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
I was honestly surprised that my company, CD Baby, was such a runaway success.  But I was even more surprised to find out why.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
CD Baby had lots of powerful well-funded competitors, but after a few years they were all but gone, and &lt;strong&gt;we dominated our niche&lt;/strong&gt; of selling independent music.  150,000 musicians, 2 million music-buying customers, $139 million in revenue, $83 million paid directly to musicians.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What was the secret to CD Baby’s success?&lt;/strong&gt;  I never did any marketing.  Everyone came by word-of-mouth.  But why?  I honestly didn’t know.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So whenever I was out talking with my musician clients, &lt;strong&gt;I’d ask them&lt;/strong&gt;.  For years, I asked hundreds of clients why they chose CD Baby instead of the alternatives.  Or I’d just listen as they’d rave to others nearby about why they loved it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Was it the pricing?  The features?  Nope.  &lt;strong&gt;The #1 answer, by far,&lt;/strong&gt; almost every time someone raved about the company, was this:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;“You pick up the phone!  I can reach a real person.”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They called and got a real person on the 2nd ring, instead of an automated call-routing system.  Or they emailed and got a surprisingly helpful personal reply, instead of an impersonal scripted FAQ response.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;And that was it.&lt;/strong&gt;  Who could have guessed?  That despite all efforts put into features, pricing, design, partnerships, and more, &lt;strong&gt;clients would choose one company over another mainly because they liked their customer service&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I structured the business to match this priority.  Out of 85 employees, 28 people were full-time customer service.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since then, many entrepreneurs and interviewers have asked for my customer service tips and tricks, but I recently realized it’s not something you can add on top, it’s really a philosophy - a mindset that has to come from the core.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’m no expert on the subject, but I’ve learned a few things from 16 years of experience, so here are the 6 key mindsets that I think guide great customer service:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(Actually, I prefer the term &lt;strong&gt;“client care”&lt;/strong&gt;, since &lt;strong&gt;“client” implies a relationship, instead of “customer”, which is transactional.&lt;/strong&gt; But I'll use the normal term instead of confusing things by using mine.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#1: You can afford to be generous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The #1 most important mindset to start with, underlying everything, before engaging in communication with a customer or client, is that &lt;strong&gt;your business is secure&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Even if it’s not, you have to feel that it is.  Money is coming your way.  You are doing well.  You are one of the lucky ones.  Most are not so fortunate.  You can afford to be generous.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All great service comes from this feeling of generosity and abundance.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Think of all the examples of great service you’ve encountered.  Free refills of coffee.  Letting you use the toilets even if you’re not a customer.  Extra milk and sugar if you need it.  A rep that spends a whole hour with you to help answer all your naive questions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Contrast it with all of the bad experiences you’ve had.  Not letting you use the toilets without making a purchase.  Charging an additional 50 cents for extra sauce.  Salespeople who don’t give you a minute of their time because you don’t look like big money yet. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All bad service comes from a mindset of scarcity&lt;/strong&gt;, feeling like they’ll go out of business if they don’t fiercely guard their bottom line.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They say the reason those in poverty so often stay in poverty is that short-term thinking of desperate survival doesn’t leave room to think of long-term solutions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you really feel secure, abundant, that you have plenty to share, then this feeling of generosity will flow down into all of your interactions with customers. Share. Be nice. Give refunds. Take a little loss. You can afford it. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course &lt;strong&gt;it’s also just smart business&lt;/strong&gt;. Losing 10 cents on extra sauce can mean winning the loyalty of a customer who will spend $1000 with you over the next 10 years, and tell 20 friends that you’re awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#2: The customer is more important than the company&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Think of a time where you had to make a big decision.  For example, the choice between a job that pays more money versus another that pays less but gives more freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do you remember how it felt when you were conflicted between these two choices?  Weighing pros and cons, going back and forth?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The way you resolved this was to finally &lt;strong&gt;decide which value was more important to you&lt;/strong&gt;.  For example: more money or more freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Most of us don’t decide which value is most important to us until we’re forced to make this decision.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But if you want great customer service, you need to &lt;strong&gt;make this value choice up-front, and decide that your customer’s happiness is your top priority&lt;/strong&gt;, above company profitability, then make sure that everyone in the company knows this and acts upon it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can’t micro-manage the details of every possible scenario, so make sure everyone in the company knows that whenever they have to make decision about what is the right thing to do, &lt;strong&gt;always do what’s best for the customer, what would make them the happiest, and don’t worry about the company&lt;/strong&gt;.  The customer is more important than the company.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#3: Customer service is a profit center&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Companies put so much energy into sales - getting people to buy - but they don’t put as much effort into the customer experience &lt;strong&gt;after people buy&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyone can see the reason to focus on getting customers to buy.  It’s obvious profit.  But it takes some wisdom, experience, and long-term thinking to understand that &lt;strong&gt;keeping your existing customers thrilled is even more profitable&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Customer service is not an expense to be lessened.  It’s a core profit center&lt;/strong&gt;, like sales.  It’s something you &lt;strong&gt;put the best people on&lt;/strong&gt;, not the cheapest.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You’ve heard the old business truism that &lt;strong&gt;it’s 5 times harder to get a new client than it is to get repeat business from an existing client&lt;/strong&gt;, so this is where you put it into practice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hire the sweetest most charming people and make sure they have all the time in the world to spend with your clients, making sure they’re so heard, and so happy with your service, that they’ll tell everyone they know.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hire enough people so that they have the time to pick up the phone, instead of routing people into an automated system.  If they’re so busy that their communications are getting too succinct, it’s time to hire another.  It’s worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#4: Every interaction is your moment to shine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Probably only 1% of your customers or clients ever bother to make a customer service interaction.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So when they do, this is your time to shine.  &lt;strong&gt;Three minutes spent talking with them is going to shape their impression of your company more than your name, price, design, website, or features all combined&lt;/strong&gt;.  This is your shining moment to be the best you can be, to &lt;strong&gt;blow them away with how cool it was to contact you&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If your customer service is taught to be &lt;strong&gt;efficient&lt;/strong&gt;, it sends the message, “I don’t really want to talk with you. Let’s get this over with quick.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since that’s what everyone else does, do the opposite.  &lt;strong&gt;Take a few inefficient minutes to get to know anyone who contacts you.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For example, at CD Baby, if someone would call, saying, “I’d like to talk with someone about selling my music through you,” we’d say, “Sure. I can help. What’s your name? Cool. Got a website? Can I see it? Is that you on the home page there? Very cool. Is that a real Les Paul? Awesome. Here, let me listen to a bit of the music. Nice, I like what you’re doing. Very syncopated. Great groove. Anyway... so... what would you like to know?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I can tell you from my own experience of being a self-promoting musician for 15 years that it’s SO hard to get anyone to listen to your music.  So when someone takes even a couple minutes to listen to you, it’s so touching that you remember it for life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This isn’t some sales technique, &lt;strong&gt;it’s just good human behavior&lt;/strong&gt;. It makes life better. It makes work more fun. It’s the right thing to do. And it pays off.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When people would call to buy music, we’d ask them where they heard of the artist, not in some monotonous scripted way, but as part of engaging the customer in a little conversation, sincerely interested in the details, maybe asking if they often discover new music that way, or whatever.  Then we’d include these details in the order on the backend, so the musician could see it, too.  It helped the musician be more connected to their fans, and helped both them and us understand why people were buying music.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Imagine what you’d do if Paul McCartney called&lt;/strong&gt;.  You’d drop everything, gush some praise, be thrilled that he’d contact you at all, and give him all the time in the world for whatever he wants.  So that’s how we should treat everyone that contacts us.  Why not?  You don’t have time?  Make time.  &lt;strong&gt;It’s how everyone deserves to be treated.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You know there’s research that says that we don’t smile because we’re happy.  We smile first, and the physical act of smiling makes us happy.  So I think the act of acting your best, being sincerely interested in others, taking the time to make each person happy, even if you weren’t in the mood at first, is a great way of actually being your best.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#5: Lose every fight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Customer service often starts when someone has a problem, and is upset.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But kind of like you need to feel secure for your business to be generous, you need to feel secure enough to lose every fight.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Whenever they’re upset, let them know that they were right, and the company was wrong.  They win.  You lose.  And you’re prepared to &lt;strong&gt;do whatever it takes to make them happy again.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I’m saying this, but let’s admit that it’s so hard to turn off our human nature to feel things are directed at us - to lash back, and show them they’re wrong, to not lose this fight.  Occasionally, still, I start typing a response that’s not so nice, but after years of getting burned for doing that, I catch myself, and replace it with something angelic instead.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But you know that scene in the movies, where someone is saying something nasty or secret, and then realizes their microphone is on, so they immediately straighten up, correct themselves, and say the publicly-acceptable thing instead?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Well, &lt;strong&gt;your microphone is on&lt;/strong&gt;.  There is no private communication in customer service.  Anything you say is likely to be put onto someone’s blog or Facebook, retweeted, and seen by everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So you must &lt;strong&gt;be the best version of yourself&lt;/strong&gt;.  You must let them win every fight.  You must humbly bow to your superior, and make them happy.  And kinda like I said about how smiling makes you happy, I think the act of doing this every day is very peaceful.  It feels like &lt;strong&gt;daily empathy practice&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Over the years, my company had some huge evangelists: people who loudly told everyone they met that they absolutely must use CD Baby to sell or buy their music.  Funny thing is, when I’d look back through that person’s history of communication, I’d often find out that the first time they contacted us, they were loudly upset about some problem.  I think the lesson learned is that &lt;strong&gt;loud people are loud people, whether complaining or praising&lt;/strong&gt;, so when you get some loud complaint, take it as an opportunity to do whatever it takes to make them so happy that they become a loud evangelist.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#6: Rebelliously right the wrongs of the world&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You know there’s this little passive-aggressive move we all do, when we don’t like how someone is behaving, we instinctively “take the high road” to show them how to behave?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like if someone is talking too loudly in a quiet place, you speak extra-quiet to them.  If someone is being a complete slob, you clean up your zone before confronting them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s a kind of defiant act that says, “No. You’re doing it wrong. Here. Watch me. I’ll show you how it’s done.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Well, I think &lt;strong&gt;your business is your little part of the world where you can right all the wrongs of the world, and show them all how it’s done.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To do this, you need to be rebellious.  &lt;strong&gt;Don’t follow norms&lt;/strong&gt;.  Don’t do what the other businesses are doing.  Instead, think of the worst you’ve experienced, and do the opposite.  Show them how wrong they were.  It’s very cathartic.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What do you think? Did I miss any important ones? I’d love to hear any suggestions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/onphone.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="girl on phone by Mark Roy" /&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/electricnerve/3136696489"&gt;Mark Roy&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Loving what I used to hate</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/hate</id>
    <updated>2014-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/hate"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
From now on, when I say I hate something, remind me to add “&lt;strong&gt;… today&lt;/strong&gt;” to the sentence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here's why:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tom Waits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first time I heard Tom Waits was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEttHwPXARk"&gt;this performance on David Letterman&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I hated it.
I hated it passionately.
I complained to my friend that it was the worst thing I'd ever heard, and it must be some kind of joke.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The second time I heard Tom Waits was a year later, when my roommate played me “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c0I4k9qqAjA"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;”, and I hated it just as much.
I still thought it must be some kind of in-joke.
Maybe it's a dare, like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/H%C3%A1karl"&gt;hákarl&lt;/a&gt;?
Someone wouldn't actually listen to this for pleasure, would they?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The third time I heard Tom Waits was “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RASG2JmtDeQ"&gt;It's All Right With Me&lt;/a&gt;”, and &lt;strong&gt;suddenly I got it&lt;/strong&gt;.
Maybe it's &lt;a href="/mirror"&gt;because it's a cover&lt;/a&gt;, or maybe I was sick of all normal music that day, but his American exotic theatrical junkyard sound was just what I needed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I bought the great &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/music/Tom+Waits/Rain+Dogs"&gt;Rain Dogs&lt;/a&gt; album, and it's one of my favorite albums of all time.
(Especially “&lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/music/Tom+Waits/Rain+Dogs/Tango+Till+They%27re+Sore"&gt;Tango Till They're Sore&lt;/a&gt;”, which I hated before, and now love the most.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Indonesia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The best TEDx Conference I've ever been to was in &lt;a href="http://www.tedxjakarta.org/"&gt;Jakarta, Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JdVLYMb8IGE"&gt;cross-gender dancer&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRVrm3svaUk"&gt;leader of games&lt;/a&gt;, I got such an &lt;strong&gt;overwhelming dose of Indonesian talent, culture, and pride that day&lt;/strong&gt;, that a part of me will forever feel Indonesian, or at least a big fan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A week later, I had to laugh when I suddenly remembered that I used to hate Indonesia!  Why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because at my old company, CD Baby, whenever we'd get a big order from Indonesia, and ship the CDs across the world, the credit card company would contact me months later to tell me that order was placed with a stolen credit card.
Every time, it was Indonesia.
Small orders, big orders, every one of them was always credit card fraud.
I lost thousands of dollars before I finally had to block all Indonesian visitors to cdbaby.com, and silently delete any orders with an Indonesia shipping address.
I remember cursing that “nation of thieves” and its horrible inhabitants.
I'm sure at the time you couldn't have paid me to go to that awful place.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Oops.
Wrong.
Once I &lt;a href="/id14"&gt;got to know it&lt;/a&gt;, I loved it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Weight lifting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ever since high school, when I was solidly in the “&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freaks_and_Geeks"&gt;freaks&lt;/a&gt;” category, I've made fun of people who spend a lot of time at the gym, lifting weights.
Stupid jocks, mindlessly lifting pieces of metal.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A few years ago, some people I know all recommended &lt;a href="http://www.mensjournal.com/magazine/print-view/everything-you-know-about-fitness-is-a-lie-20120504"&gt;old-fashioned barbell training&lt;/a&gt; as a great all-around fitness habit.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I tried it, and they were right.
I love it.
Three times a week, I'm in the gym (for only 30 minutes), doing squats and deadlifts, &lt;a href="http://startingstrength.com/index.php/site/about"&gt;as described here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have to smile, thinking what my former self would say.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But the former self is not always right
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;We don't need to preserve our first opinions as if they are our pure, untarnished, true nature.&lt;/strong&gt;
They're often just ignorance or inexperience.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now when I catch myself saying that I hate (or love!) something, I try to remember to add “&lt;strong&gt;… today&lt;/strong&gt;” to the end of the sentence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Opinions are likely to change at any time, but are much harder to change if you've carved out your self-identity, declaring “&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is what I love! &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is what I hate!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Though I'm happy to say this is what I hate or love &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/cocoon.jpg" width="673" height="1024" alt="cocoon"/&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="https://flic.kr/p/bF6RXh"&gt;aussiegal&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Meaning of Life</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/ml</id>
    <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/ml"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s just figure out the meaning of life, once and for all, in under 20 minutes, OK?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This is a 19-minute talk I’ve given at four conferences in Ireland, Taiwan, India, and New Zealand.
	I’ve improved it after each, and finally consider it done, so this is now the best and final recording of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The video doesn’t add much, so if you would rather just listen, &lt;a href="/file/DerekSivers-MeaningOfLife.mp3"&gt;download the MP3&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The video should be visible below, but if not, &lt;a href="/file/DerekSivers-MeaningOfLife.mp4"&gt;download the MP4 video&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zzcCWEb-tyk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Huge thanks to some friends who suggested great improvements:
&lt;a href="http://www.michellewelsch.com/"&gt;Michelle Welsch&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://tynan.com/"&gt;Tynan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://alytadros.com/"&gt;Aly Tadros&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Marx"&gt;Jeff Marx&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Also thanks to a hundred drunk programmers in Ireland who shouted and sang their way through my first performance of it, standing on chairs at the end of a Saturday night.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If you would like to make a better video for this talk, please do.
	&lt;a href="/file/DerekSivers-MeaningOfLife.wav"&gt;Download the master WAV audio&lt;/a&gt;, and let me know when it’s done.
	Assuming I like it, I’ll be happy to link to it here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Here’s the full transcript, if you hate surprises and my charming voice:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	Transcript:
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	There’s a true story about the student who showed up late to math class.
	He copied the problem that was already written on the board, assuming it was homework, and solved it that week.
	Only afterwards did he find out the teacher put it on the board as an example of an unsolvable problem.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This question - “What is the meaning of life?” - is the classic unsolvable problem.
	For thousands of years, people have been trying to figure it out.
	It’s the punchline cliché of unanswerable questions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But right now, let’s be the naive ones that don’t know it’s considered unsolvable, and just figure out the meaning of life in under 20 minutes.  OK?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	LIFE IS __________
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	What word do you think goes in that blank?
	Life is what?
	Any ideas?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s look at some of the different options that philosophers and smarties have said.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	LIFE IS TIME
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Some say life is time.
	Life is all about time.
	The definition of life is the time between when you’re born and when you die.
	So the literal meaning of life is time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So if life is time, the way to have a good life is to use time wisely.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you use time wisely?
	Five ways.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
	Remember it’s limited
&lt;p&gt;
	If you find out tonight that you’ve only got one year left to live, you’ll make the most of this next year.
	If you act like life is infinite, you won’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	To achieve great things, two things are needed: a plan, and not quite enough time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Give yourself tight deadlines.
	Remember you could die at any time.
	Don’t delay.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you use time wisely?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Be mostly future-focused
&lt;p&gt;
	Make most of your current actions serve your future self.
	Learn, practice, exercise, delay gratification, save and invest your money, and build towards your ideal future.
	People who do this are more successful and even happier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But too much future focus leads to being a successful person on your 4th marriage, with no true friends.
	Too much future focus can take time away from important things that need you to be in the moment.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you use time wisely?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Be somewhat present-focused
&lt;p&gt;
	Sometimes, pull your head out of the future, and give your full attention to the present.
	Relationships, communication, and sex require this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But too much present focus is hedonism: living only for immediate gratification with as much excitement and novelty as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Too much present focus leads to an empty bank account and no impulse control.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Too much present focus robs you of the deeper happiness of delayed gratification, achieving long-term goals, and developing valuable expertise.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you use time wisely?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Be somewhat past-focused
&lt;p&gt;
	To remember your past is to live twice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Keep your life in the context of the past, to see how far you’ve come.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Put aside time to re-interpret your past events, as a powerful reminder that you can re-interpret your present and future, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you use time wisely?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Get in the zone
&lt;p&gt;
	You know the feeling of flow - where you’re focused on work that’s not too easy and not too hard - where the work itself has clear goals and is its own reward.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	People at the end of their life who claimed to be the happiest with their life were the ones who had spent the most time in this state of flow.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For a good life, pursue the work that puts you in this state, and avoid the things that pull you from this state.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s say life is time.  What do you think?  Pretty good argument?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s look at another perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	LIFE IS CHOICE
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Some say life is choice.
	Life is all about choice.
	You make a hundred little choices a day, and a hundred big choices in your life.
	These choices change your entire life.
	Your life is created by your choices.
	Therefore life IS choice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So if life is choice, the way to have a good life is to make good choices.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you make good choices?  Four ways.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
	Let instinct trump logic
&lt;p&gt;
	The different parts of your brain started developing at different periods in evolution.
	The oldest part of your brain, the one that’s been evolving since we were fish, deals with instincts, fears, and gut feelings.
	The newest part of your brain, the one that’s pretty uniquely human, deals with logic, language, and predictions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This newest part is still in beta.
	A $5 calculator can beat it at math.
	But this oldest part was launched a billion years ago, and has been in production and development ever since.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Everything you observe and learn is first processed by your logical brain, but then the results are permanently stored as instincts, fears, and gut feelings.
	Your instincts and emotions hold the culmination of everything you’ve ever observed and learned.
	So you’ll make better choices if you listen your instincts, instead of relying too much on your $5 calculator beta brain.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you make good choices?  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Stop at good enough
&lt;p&gt;
	You now have more options than ever.
	You try to choose the best option, the best career, the best school, and the best boyfriend/girlfriend/partner/spouse.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But thinking this way makes you feel worse about the choices you’ve made.
	You’re more aware than ever of all the options you didn’t choose, and the benefits of each.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So don’t seek the absolute best. Stop when you find an option that is good enough.
	You’ll make an equally good choice, but more importantly, you’ll feel much better about it.
	Happiness counts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you make good choices?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Set limits
&lt;p&gt;
	Every choice you have to make causes a little bit of pain.
	Having choice in life is good, but having more choice is not always better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’re happier when you let other people make some choices for you.
	If you’re very sick, you want your doctor to choose what’s best, not say, "There are dozens of good options. What do you want to do?"
	This is the appeal of religion.
	It gives you rules.
	It makes many of the choices for you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So set limits to your choices in life.
	Cut off some options.
	Give yourself rules.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you make good choices?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Choose important not urgent
&lt;p&gt;
	You know the difference between what’s long-term important versus short-term urgent.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	What’s urgent are emails, texts, tweets, calls, and news.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	What’s important is spending a thousand hours to learn a new skill that will really help you in your life or work.
	What’s important is giving your full undistracted attention to the important people in your life.
	What’s important is taking time to get exercise, or to collect and share what you’ve learned.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But none of these things will ever be urgent.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So you have to ignore the tempting cries of the urgent, and deliberately choose what you know is important.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	So life is choice?
	What do you think?
	Pretty good argument?
	Let’s try another.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	LIFE IS MEMORY
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Some say life is memory.
	The future doesn’t exist.
	It’s something we imagine.
	The present is gone in a millisecond, so everything we experience in life is a memory.
	You could live a long life, but without a lot of memories, you only experienced a short life.
	If you don’t remember your life, it’s like it never happened.
	So life is memory.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So if life is memory, the way to have a good life is to make more memories.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you make memories?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Change routines.
	Break monotony.
	Move.
	Make a major change whenever you can.
	These are your chronological landmarks.
	These are the hooks where you’ll hang your memories.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Document it.
	Blog it.
	Not in a company’s walled garden, but in a format you can archive and look through in 50 years, or your grandkids can look through in 100 years.
	Keep a private blog for your future self, and tell the tales of where you’ve been, what you did, and the quirky people you’ve met along the way.
	You’ll be surprised how much you forget if you don’t record it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Socrates said the unexamined life is not worth living.
	What about the forgotten life?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So life is memory?
	What do you think?
	Want to do another?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	LIFE IS LEARNING
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Both my smart friends and my spiritual friends insist that the meaning of life is learning - that the reason you’re here is to learn.
	Not just for your own sake, but for everyone alive, and future generations, the meaning of your life is to learn.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So if life is learning, the way to have a good life is to learn a lot.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	How can you learn a lot?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Instead of talking about learning techniques, let’s talk about getting the right mindset, so you can learn more than you realize.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’ve probably heard about the Fixed mindset and the Growth mindset.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The Fixed mindset says, "I am good at this" or "I am bad at this".
	This starts in childhood when your parents say, "You’re so good at math!"
	You think, "I’m good at math!"
	But then when you do poorly on one test, you think, "They were wrong.  I’m not good at math.”
	Most people think this way.
	You can hear it when they say, “She’s a great singer” or “I’m just no good at dancing.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The Growth mindset says, "Anyone can be good at anything. Skill comes only from practice."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Two impossibly hard tests were given to hundreds of children.
	After the first test, all of the students were praised, but half of the students were privately told these 6 words: "You must be good at this."
	The other half were privately told these 6 words: "You must have worked really hard."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When they were given the second test, the students who were told, "You must be good at this", did 20% worse on the 2nd test.
	Those 6 words encouraged a fixed mindset that made them feel there was no point in trying.
	You either are or you aren’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The students who were told "You must have worked really hard", did 30% better on the 2nd test.
	Those 6 words encouraged a growth mindset that made them feel that working harder made all the difference.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So that’s a +-50% difference in performance because of 6 quick words by one teacher.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Multiply that by all the people in your life, all the days you hear feedback, and all the things you tell yourself, and you can see how this simple difference in mindset can make or break a life of learning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Parents, pay attention to this.
	You may be harming your kids when you tell them they’re good at things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Successful people, pay attention to this.
	You may be harming yourself if you believe the praise that people give you.
	People tell you you’re great at what you do, never just that you must have worked hard.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So... life is learning?
	What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Something else?
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
	Should we look at the Buddhist idea that life is SUFFERING?
	Nah, that’s no fun.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Life is LOVE?
	Too ambiguous.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Life is NOTHING BUT REPLICATING DNA?
	Too accurate.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s change the subject.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Chinese
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	A few years ago, I started learning Chinese.
	I’m fascinated with the writing.
	I’m trying to memorize how to write these characters.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Chinese characters look complicated, but they’re mostly made up of smaller simpler characters, the way that English words are made up of Latin roots and such.
	So you can remember the meaning of each character by knowing the meaning of its ingredients.
	For example:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	语 language = words 讠+ five 五+ mouth 口
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So... Language is words that at least five mouths speak? Brilliant!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	谢 thank you = words 讠+ body 身+ inch 寸
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Hmmm... This one is not so obvious.
	Maybe the idea is that when you say thanks, you speak words that give a body an inch of respectful space?
	That’s interesting.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	名 name = evening 夕 + mouth 口
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So your real name is what’s spoken by a mouth in the evening?
	That’s kind of romantic.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I get so curious about the historical or cultural meaning behind each one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Let’s change the subject.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Talking Heads
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Talking Heads were a great band from the late-70s to mid-80s.
	Their lyrics were really evocative and mysterious.
	They made you wonder what they were really about. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then I read an interview with the Talking Heads where they said that many of their lyrics were just random.
	They would write evocative phrases onto little pieces of paper, then throw them into a bowl, and shuffle them up.
	Then they’d pull them out, and put them into the song in that order.
	They did this because they liked how the listener creates meaning that wasn’t intended.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	We assume that if someone writes a song, then sings it on stage into a microphone, that it must have meaning to them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But nope.
	It was just random.
	Any meaning you think it contains was put there by you, the listener, not the writer.
	Like a Rorschach test.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Back to Chinese
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	I got so curious about the historical meaning of these Chinese characters that I got a Chinese etymological dictionary that tells the full history behind every one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I looked up the examples I gave here, and found out those characters were just phonetic!
	Those composite character bits were NOT chosen for their meaning at all, just their sound!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So it seems I’ve just been putting the meanings into them, myself.
	They actually had no meaning at all!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It blew my mind.
	I had been memorizing hundreds of characters for months, reading all kinds of meaning into the ingredients of each one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	After recovering from that, I thought:
	How many other things in life really have no meaning?
	What else have I been putting my own meaning into, thinking it was true?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Wired
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	I know that we’re wired to do it.
	I know we survived on the savannah for eons because we evolved to look for patterns.
	Our ancestors are the ones who noticed the patterns of the tiger stripes or the lion face in the grass.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;A moth is so deeply wired to fly towards the light that it may never accept that your light bulb is not the moon.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;We are so deeply wired to find patterns that we may never accept that many things are just random.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	We should have the same sympathy for our faulty wiring as we do for the moth.
	Evolution taught us to do this thing, but didn’t teach us to stop.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Give us some dots and a line, and we’ll see a face.
	Burn some toast and we’ll find Elvis in it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A carrot from my garden looks like Jesus.
	What does it mean?
&lt;br&gt;
	A black cat crossed my path as I walked under a ladder on Friday the 13th.
	What does it mean?
&lt;br&gt;
	An old friend calls just a minute after I was thinking about them.
	What does it mean?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that you went to a prestigious well-known school? 
	What does it mean that you didn’t?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that your good friend died? 
	What does it mean that you’re tall?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that you have a lot of followers online?
	What does it mean that you don’t?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that you’re female?
	What does it mean that you’re male?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that you’re an entrepreneur?
	What does it mean that you’re not?
&lt;br&gt;
	What does it mean that all of your previous attempts at something have failed?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Nothing!  Nothing at all.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Nothing has inherent meaning.
	Everything is only what it is and that’s it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So let’s get back to our original question and wrap this up.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Life Is _____
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	What is the meaning of life?  LIFE IS ______
&lt;br&gt;
	TIME?
&lt;br&gt;
	CHOICE?
&lt;br&gt;
	MEMORY?
&lt;br&gt;
	LEARNING?
&lt;br&gt;
	SUFFERING?
&lt;br&gt;
	LOVE?
&lt;br&gt;
	REPLICATING DNA?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You can tell by the variety of answers that they are just projected meanings.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You can choose to project one of these meanings onto your life, if it makes you feel good, or improves your current actions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But you know the real answer is clear and obvious now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Life is (just) life.
	It doesn’t &lt;strong&gt;mean&lt;/strong&gt; anything.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Erase any meaning you put into past events.
	Erase any meaning that’s holding you back.
	Erase those times where people said that this means that.
	None of it is real.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Life has no inherent meaning.
	Nothing has inherent meaning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Life is a blank slate.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’re free to project any meaning that serves you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’re free to do with it, anything you want.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Change careers like Tarzan</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/tarzan</id>
    <updated>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/tarzan"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I get emails from many people who want to make a big change in their career.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Each one wants to quit their current career, and boldly leap into their new venture or preferred lifestyle.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When they ask my advice, they think I'm going to say, “Yes! Quit! Go for it!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But instead, they're surprised at my suggestion:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Remember how Tarzan swings through the jungle?
He doesn't let go of the previous vine until the next vine is supporting his weight.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/tarzan-600x450.gif" width="600" height="450" alt="Tarzan swinging on vines"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So my advice is: Change careers like Tarzan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Don't let go of the old one until the new one is supporting you.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And &lt;strong&gt;make sure you don't lose momentum&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;
P.S.  I highly recommend reading the book “&lt;a href="/book/SoGood"&gt;So Good They Can't Ignore You&lt;/a&gt;” for more thoughts on this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
P.P.S.  Full credit for the “momentum” metaphor goes to &lt;a href="http://philippantar.com/"&gt;Philipp Antar&lt;/a&gt;, from the comments, below.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What if you didn't need money or attention?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/full</id>
    <updated>2014-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/full"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You know that feeling you have after a big meal?
Where you're so full that you really actively don't want anything more?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ever wonder what that would feel like in other parts of your life?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We do so many things for the attention, to feel important or praised.
But what if you had so much attention and so much praise that you couldn't possibly want any more?
What would you do then?
What would you stop doing?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We do so many things for the money.
It's so deeply built into our culture that it takes a real effort to realize it's the reason behind so many of our actions.
But what if you had so much money that you couldn't possibly want any more?
What would you do then?
What would you stop doing?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And then…
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you stopped doing all these things you're just doing for the money, or the attention, what's left?
Who are you, if you don't do these things?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Many of my friends are touring musicians.
One has been quite unhappy with it lately.
She realized it was once a dream, but now she's just doing it for the fear of being forgotten.
But if she stops, what's left?
She's defined herself by this pursuit for so long.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Many of my friends are entrepreneurs.
A few have mentioned this deep hollow conflicted feeling.
Their business ideas are not things the world wants.
They're following the current tech entrepreneur stereotype, building social apps and pursuing investors.
They're hating it, and having to admit they're doing it only for the jackpot.
But if they stop, what's left?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;If you were completely satiated, then what?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After an understandable period of relaxing, what would you pursue?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Not&lt;/strong&gt; just “sit around and do nothing”, because that's still just relaxing.
I mean after that, &lt;strong&gt;when you're ready to be useful to others again.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What would you do then, if you didn't need the money, and didn't need the attention?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, we need money to live.
We need attention to live, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But I find it healthy to make sure they are just side effects of doing good work, or living a good life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/pigeon.jpg" width="600" height="600" alt=""&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/villes/2865833414/"&gt;ZeroOne&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How will this game end?</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/game</id>
    <updated>2014-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/game"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You might have heard this one before.  If not, pay attention.  It’s a good one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Imagine I announce &lt;strong&gt;I am going to sell a $100 bill by auction, and the bidding starts at only $1.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The only rule of the game is this: &lt;strong&gt;if you are the 2nd-highest bidder, you still have to pay what you bid&lt;/strong&gt;, but you don’t get the $100 bill. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course I get some bids for $1, $2, $3.  Why not?  Hey - a chance to get $100 for $3!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The bids keep coming in.  By $51 I’m happy - I’m going to profit now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once they get to $90, there’s less enthusiasm, but reason to stay in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Once they get to $99, though, the person offering $98 thinks, “Uh oh. The other person isn’t backing down,” and raises their bid to $100 so as not to be 2nd-lowest and lose the entire $98.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But now the person offering $99 raises their bid to $101.  Better to lose only $1 than $99, right?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Soon they’re offering $110, $120, $150.  This game could go on forever.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The real problem: not thinking it through in advance.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When the game starts, it’s easy to think short-term and say, “Ooh! Good deal!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then when it’s too late, you slowly realize, ”Uh-oh. What have I done?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A lot of people get into life situations like this.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The entrepreneur who borrows a lot of money to test an idea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The homeowner who bought a house at the top end of their budget.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The romantic who gets into a relationship with someone who is already in a relationship.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can hear them whining about how they’re so in debt, or their sweetheart is cheating.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Oops!  Didn’t think that one through, huh?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The game was clearly rigged against them, so the smart choice is to not play that game at all.
We should always ask, “How will this game end?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It’s &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; to think through the long-term implications of everything we’re doing now.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s hard, but it’s worth the effort.  I’m just posting this here as a reminder (to myself, too).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/bull.jpg" width="650" height="502" alt="bull staring at man"/&gt;
&lt;div class="small"&gt;(Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vinothchandar/6748059859/"&gt;Vinoth Chandar&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Imitate. We are imperfect mirrors.</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/mirror</id>
    <updated>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/mirror"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
You know that song you love, that you wish you wrote?  Copy it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You know that existing business, that you wish you had thought of?  Copy it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because humans are imperfect mirrors.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Like a funhouse mirror that distorts what it reflects&lt;/strong&gt;, even if you try to imitate something, it will turn out much different than the original.
Maybe better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When a musician covers someone else's song, they clearly reveal their own warped perspective, since we know what the original looks (sounds) like.
Because of this, a cover song is actually a great way to define who you are as an artist.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When a musician writes a new song, imitating someone else's song, it's usually unrecognizable.
You have to tell people of its inspiration, for them to make the connection.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So an entrepreneur can imitate someone else's business, and still be adding a unique service to the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I resisted this lesson as long as I could.&lt;/strong&gt;
It offended my instincts as an artist.
I felt that everything I did had to be 100% original.
Everything “not invented here” was out of the question.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Back in my CD Baby days, my only direct competitor had one awesome advantage: old fashioned credit card swiping machines that musicians could use to sell CDs at gigs, even without electricity or a 3G connection.
Musicians would tell me how much they loved that service, and even told me they wish we had it too.
I said, “Yeah. Damn. Oh well.”
Because imitating their offering didn't even enter my mind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It took a whole year for me to swallow my pride, and realize I'd be doing my clients a favor if I imitated that idea.
&lt;strong&gt;It turned out to be one of the most successful things I ever did.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Those little credit card swiping machines charged over $8.5 million for thousands of musicians, which meant $7.75 million paid out to the musicians, and $750k profit for us.
And the whole thing only took two weeks to make, and one employee to run.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So look around at those existing ideas in the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Get over that self-important resistance, and do the world a favor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/mirror.jpg" width="420" height="627" alt="funhouse mirror" /&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Vietnam</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/vn14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/vn14"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is by Jeremy Wellard, who is based in Hanoi at &lt;a href="http://c3vietnam.com/"&gt;C3 Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, and is founding director of &lt;a href="http://communehanoi.com/"&gt;Commune Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;, a co-working cafe and creative hub.  This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing most people know of Vietnam is the Vietnam War.  In Vietnam, they call it the American War, and it’s just old history.  There is so much more to this youthful, thriving country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has long been considered the cultural and artistic heart of Asia, and the Vietnamese are the “Italians of Asia”. Highly social and heart-driven, with a penchant for drama and performance they are quick to raise their voices to sway a discussion, but equally quick to laugh off a misunderstanding. One of the greatest strengths of Vietnamese is their ability to find joy in everyday moments. Whether laboring in the fields or rushing through busy urban lives, they still find any excuse to put down their tools and laugh in conversation over a cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since opening up to the world in the late 1980s, the Vietnamese have been racing ahead at full speed. Years of struggle under a system of collective production left people ready to enthusiastically embrace capitalist ideals. Since the late 1990s, Vietnam has had one of the highest economic growth rates in the world. This rapid growth created a highly entrepreneurial environment where everyone seems to have a second or third business on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is the world’s only “Socialist-Oriented Market Economy”. This means the government maintains a large ownership and control of major companies, while small and medium businesses are left to develop freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget any notions of the frugal communist lifestyle. Wealth and possessions are flaunted as signs of success. People will spend many months’ salary for a status symbol like an iPhone, fancy motorbike, or designer clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there’s a deep-seated habit of saving money wherever possible. This can be seen in shops, where the air-conditioning is turned off until a customer walks in, or in the recycling culture where even used plastic bags have value. Vietnamese take great pride in their bargaining skills. When a new purchase is shown to friends, someone will immediately ask how much they paid for it. Ability to negotiate a good price demonstrates not just savvy but strong relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading on relationships is key.  A popular saying is, “First your family, second your friends, third comes money.”  This means people will always look out for family and friends, but for outsiders their help comes at a price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong family networks define the career and social lives of many Vietnamese. The government strongly recommends families have only two children, and most do. There are highly traditional expectations regarding responsibility to family, education, career choices, gender roles, marriage, and children. Newly wed couples live at the home of the husband’s parents until they can afford to buy their own house. Three generations often live together under one roof, and grandparents play an important role in providing childcare. Because of this in-home care, mothers usually return to work much sooner than the six months of maternity leave given by Vietnam’s labor laws, which strongly favor worker’s rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Vietnam, the year and date of a person’s birth is very important. It influences their whole life, including when they are allowed to marry, open a business, hold important meetings and have children. Social interactions and forms of address are determined by age, so upon meeting a new person, one of the first questions Vietnamese will ask is what year they were born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of a strongly collective past, where standing out from the crowd was potentially dangerous, new ideas may be regarded with caution.  But once the viability of an idea is demonstrated, acceptance, imitation and adaptation rapidly follow.  This tendency to follow others can lead Vietnamese to seem unoriginal in their thinking. But in fact their ability to quickly see an opportunity and willingness to capitalize on it creates a very dynamic and exciting environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the collective past, upwardly mobile Vietnamese have fully embraced the concept that the individual who works smarter and has more relationships can have more than their neighbor. A new “me-first” culture is rising. But there still remains a highly structured society underneath. In many ways, Vietnam is perhaps both the most-collective and least-collective of the Asian cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese have been living with occupation, change and uncertainty for thousands of years and have developed community-based social systems that preserve order and personal freedom at a micro level, regardless of macro changes. As the local saying goes, “The rules of the village are stronger than the rules of the king.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike common misconceptions regarding Communist states, Vietnam is actually a democracy, and all citizens have the right to vote every three years. Although they can only choose candidates from one political party, within this party there are factions with very different viewpoints. Individuals have a lot of freedom in most areas of everyday life. Overall though, they tend to avoid openly discussing political issues. Speaking against the government, protesting high-level corruption, or promoting other political systems can incur severe punishments for locals and expulsion for foreigners.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is chaotic, but far from lawless. The country has an advanced legal system. But there are many ways in which rules can seem more like guidelines. A “no” can become a “yes” with the right timing and persuasion. This can seem daunting, but those who understand the system are great at navigating its complexities. This is one of the main reasons foreign business people need a trusted local partner or good lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreigners are surprised that sociopolitical tensions are actually highest with China, rather than the United States, France, or Japan.  Vietnam is increasingly wary of China’s growing power and territorial ambitions.  This has caused a strong wave of anti-China sentiment where Chinese products, particularly food, are considered poor quality and unhealthy. It has also driven a celebration of products “Made in Vietnam” and is combining with a growing awareness of health and safety to birth a clean-food movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing constant in Vietnam is change. Trends come and go, businesses open and close, and construction is a constant. The pervasive dust and noise are the sweat and tears of progress. But underneath this turmoil, there is a country that remains deeply Vietnamese, and people who are proud, ambitious, and happy to be open to a world of opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;&lt;img src="https://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-VN-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Singapore</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/sg14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/sg14"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tell people I live in Singapore, the most common misunderstandings I hear are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How can you live in that sterile squeaky-clean police state?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Isn’t that where they cane people for chewing gum?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Disneyland with a death penalty! Haha!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What part of China is that in?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not surprised when people misunderstand Singapore, because it requires a little explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First - some important context:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore is an island so small you can drive around the whole country in two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1819, it was set up by the British as a tax-free trading port, instantly attracting business from the entire region.  So it’s always had a mix of Malay, Indian, and Chinese people, though the majority are Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It quickly became an anything-goes town, with opium, prostitution and gambling, run by secret societies.  Its nickname was “Sin-Galore”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1963, Singapore became a part of Malaysia.  But racial tensions between the Malay and Chinese populations led to ongoing race riots.  So in 1965, Singapore was kicked out of Malaysia, making it suddenly (and reluctantly) an independent country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Singapore had no natural resources, no local industry, and was geographically vulnerable, few people believed it would survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being a do-or-die survival situation, the government and people of Singapore got extremely focused, pragmatic, and competitive to do whatever it takes to make this tiny island thrive against the odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their main survival strategy was to focus on making Singapore an ideal place for big business — attracting multinational corporations to set up their Asian headquarters here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these historical ingredients are important for the rest of this explanation to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why so clean?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Singapore is so small, keeping it clean is a manageable job.  (You can’t easily clean India or China.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really the cleanliness is marketing.  What better way to prove to multinational corporations that Singapore is a stable, trustable, and efficient place to set up your headquarters?  It’s no coincidence that the highway leading from the airport to downtown has the most perfectly manicured landscape.  First impressions matter to visiting CEOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why the country’s leaders all wear white.  It’s a show of incorruptibility — a metaphor for being orderly and transparent with attention to detail.  Getting to know Singapore’s government is like looking under the hood of a Ferrari.  It’s incredibly well-designed and well-run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore is always selling itself to the world.  The chairman of the government’s Economic Development Board told his colleagues, “We are in the hospitality business.”  The government works hard to stay competitive on every international measure.  Any time there are international rankings comparing countries, you’ll find Singapore near the top of the list.  Except for free speech, but I’ll cover that next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly: why no chewing gum?  Purely pragmatic.  It was gumming up the subway system, causing delays, and was too hard to clean off surfaces, so the sale of it was banned.  Keeping the country clean and running smoothly was more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s why Singapore has an international reputation for being so clean.  It’s brilliant marketing — visual proof of the order and cleanliness you can expect if you set up your business or banking here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why so strict?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three reasons: transformation, size, and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: transformation.  To quickly turn Singapore from “Sin-Galore” to being the Switzerland of Asia would require great strategy and strict, uncompromising execution of that strategy.  We’re used to seeing this in corporations, like Jack Welch at GE or Steve Jobs returning to Apple, but it’s surprising to see it carried out successfully in a government.  (Many say Singapore is more like a corporation than a country.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it worked!  In one generation, Singapore went through the most dramatic increase in the standard of living that the world has ever seen.  In one generation, this tiny dot went from being broke to being one of the richest countries in the world, without any natural resources, purely by strict execution of a great strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its lack of corruption was an important ingredient in its success.  In a region where political corruption is rampant, Singapore is the only country that severely punishes corruption.  It regularly ranks in the top 5 least corrupt countries in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next: size.  Singapore’s UN representative once said, “America is like an aircraft carrier.  If you jump up and down, it’s not going to shake.  Singapore is like a canoe.  If you jump up and down, it will sink.  If you lose stability in Singapore, you lose everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly: marketing.  When an American teenager vandalized 18 cars in Singapore, he was sentenced to jail and caning.  This turned into an international incident, with Bill Clinton asking Singapore not to prosecute him.  But as a government official said, “It was a way of demonstrating that Singapore was prepared to stand up against the mighty America.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, that’s brilliant marketing.  A memorable way for a country to prove to the world that they obey the rule of law, without exception, and don’t waive the laws for special requests from powerful people.  I think this kind of approach makes corporate leaders more likely to do their business and banking in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, you could argue that Singapore is not so strict — less strict than Switzerland or California — because it’s a &lt;em&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/em&gt; “do what you want” approach where life and business are not regulated for most of us in the middle.  Only the behavior that clearly hurts others or society is punished.  Everyone else gets to live in an incredibly safe, crime-and-corruption-free place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So very pragmatic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common thread behind everything here is pragmatism.  The country’s leadership consistently makes rational choices to improve the strength and profitability of Singapore.  It’s pragmatic, not dogmatic.  It’s not that the leaders of Singapore hate chewing gum or are neat freaks.  These were just rational decisions to do what was best for the country at that time.  The prime minister has a degree in Computer Science, as does the deputy prime minister.  This is a country run by engineers and economists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s important to know that these things are changing fast.  The government is constantly but conservatively re-assessing its stance on everything, to keep up with the times.  The last few years have seen a huge move towards more democracy and free speech, with the theater and arts scene blossoming because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore’s #1 enemy is complacency.  Now that Singapore is one of the most successful countries in the world, the top priority is to keep that competitive edge.  This “keep on your toes” message is constantly communicated at all levels — a reminder to never assume that things will stay this good.  Keep pushing.  Stay on top.  Don’t let your guard down.  Always be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singapore was founded on the ideals of the Age of Enlightenment — the age of reason and rationality — and its founder built those lofty ideals into its blueprint.  So to understand Singapore, you need to understand that it’s always been designed top-down, from the beginning, to realize these rational ideals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-SG-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Indonesia</title>
    <id>http://sivers.org/id14</id>
    <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <published>2014-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <link href="http://sivers.org/id14"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danielziv"&gt;Daniel Ziv&lt;/a&gt;, who has worked in Indonesia for 14 years as a journalist, editor, and now filmmaker. He wrote the bestselling book “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/9799589878"&gt;Jakarta Inside Out&lt;/a&gt;” and directed the award-winning new documentary film &lt;a href="http://jalananmovie.com/"&gt;JALANAN&lt;/a&gt;, about the lives of three Jakarta street musicians.  This is the first chapter of my new &lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia 2014 book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia is the world’s 4th biggest country by population, but is still a work in progress - a beta version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia 1.0 began in 1945, when they gained independence from the Dutch and became a country.  Suddenly, 17,000 islands, 300 ethnic groups and 700 languages needed to be held together under one flag and one language.  These indigenous cultures were officially co-opted as caricatures rather than being allowed to grow organically.  The new official language was imposed very effectively at the expense of preserving local dialects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia 2.0 began in 1998, with the toppling of Suharto, the country’s dictator of 32 years. This new era of reform and democratization has seen impressive stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s talk about the best part of Indonesia - its people: warm, open-minded, easygoing and always lots of fun. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians are acrobats.  They’ve learned the hard way not to trust the system, but also to rarely challenge it. So they find resourceful ways of solving problems, relying on each other and adopting an optimistic, can-do attitude in any circumstance. Flexibility, elasticity and teamwork are key in nearly every walk of life, and Indonesians prize the following traits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-confrontation:&lt;/strong&gt; Indonesians put a premium on getting along and not making each other lose face. Confrontation is truly a last resort. Indonesians love group consensus as a solution to any debate. The outcome is not as important as the fact that the decision was arrived at inclusively.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patience:&lt;/strong&gt; A favorite Indonesian phrase is “jam karet”, which literally means “rubber time”, suggesting that time is a flexible, unpredictable commodity. It’s common for Indonesians to arrive an hour late to a meeting, and just as common for their colleagues to accept this as routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule-bending:&lt;/strong&gt; If time is rubber, so are rules, which are meant to be delightfully broken. Fees are waived, timetables sped up, and restrictions ignored, all for the right payment, family member, or childhood buddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-reliance:&lt;/strong&gt; In a society where very few people have health insurance, social security, or even life savings, mutual help is very common. If someone is very ill, the entire family and even neighbors pitch in to cover costs. If an uncle can’t afford his own motorbike, his son-in-law and two school friends will cover the down payment. If the government won’t fix an awful road, local residents mobilize their own resources to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians are fundamentally good, honest people born into a system that is utterly corrupt. So deeply rooted is the graft that just to get things done, one must either be corrupt or play along with corruption. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corruption is therefore a double-edged sword: it’s totally unjust and results in exorbitant costs, but it also allows people to get things done easily and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians resent paying huge bribes just to start up a small, legitimate business, yet love paying $25 to obtain an instant drivers license instead of the official $10 with its days of bureaucracy and road tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some cynically view low-level corruption as a tax system in a non-tax-paying society  Since the government cannot afford to pay police or teachers a livable wage, traffic cops demand petty bribes from drivers wanting to avoid hefty official fines, while teachers will accept payment to give students passing grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pleasure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you thought this is a conservative nation of Muslim puritans, think again. Indonesia is a surprisingly hedonistic society that could teach America a thing or two about the “pursuit of happiness” and pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians sometimes have it rough - with poverty, poor health, traffic jams, and pollution - but they constantly and unapologetically compensate themselves for these hardships. In Western countries, salons and spas are for the affluent, while in Indonesia even slum dwellers set aside the time (and as little as 50 cents) for a cream bath scalp massage or foot reflexology at a local spa shack. Infidelity, drugs and prostitution are rampant across all social classes in Indonesia.  Why?  Because people enjoy it, and deny themselves very little. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Religion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See all the young women wearing headscarves on the streets? Muslim extremists? Not even close. In fact many probably work as office girls for multinational companies and might even join colleagues at a karaoke lounge at night. Indonesia is a constant interplay between surface and substance, and nowhere is this more apparent than in the confusing, paradoxical attitude toward religion. The country is a cradle of “nominal Islam” – around 85% identify themselves as Muslims, yet very few are religious in the orthodox sense.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government dictates that every citizen must belong to one of the country’s six official religions, and this gets listed on every Indonesian’s ID card.  But for most Indonesians, religion is more of an identity label, security blanket or family tradition than a matter of orthodox belief or practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These official religious labels mask over society’s far deeper influences: pre-Islamic animist and Hindu roots, folk superstitions, and possibly more time spent worshiping English football matches or pop stars than praying in mosques or churches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Openness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesians take humble pride in their own culture and achievements, but are incredibly open to outside influence. (Unlike the Thais, for example.) They are very welcoming and adaptive toward foreigners.  There’s no xenophobia here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extends to the business world too: foreigners have been welcomed into many of Indonesia’s largest conglomerates as both senior directors and shareholders, while many have started major local companies of their own. This open-minded society has resulted in an open market full of opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This openness may explain why travel is booming.  Indonesians are increasingly traveling overseas, interacting more intensively with the world and global economy.  Indonesian expats are returning from years overseas to participate in the nation-building at home, becoming local entrepreneurs, academics, NGO types, lawyers, etc.  And Indonesians are suddenly eagerly touristing locally, discovering their own country in a way they never did before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future looks bright for Indonesia. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been three democratic, peaceful regime changes in the 15 years since the big reform, and no real fear that Indonesia will return to dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia is today the most democratic country in Southeast Asia, having surpassed more “progressive” neighbors like Thailand, the Philippines and Malaysia. (Just fifteen years ago, Indonesia would have trailed far behind.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite criticism of the current government - which in itself is a breath of fresh air - President Susilo Bambang Yudhoyono managed to steer the economy very skillfully, attracting huge foreign direct investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Indonesia, one must always look beyond the surface at the substance. It’s easy to be intimidated by corruption, traffic and pollution. But those frustrations are merely superficial distractions in a country that is unbelievably welcoming and more open for business than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;&lt;img src="https://woodegg.com/images/we14/we14cover-ID-200.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia 2014&lt;/a&gt;” is one of &lt;strong&gt;16 books about moving to and doing business in 16 countries in Asia:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kh"&gt;Cambodia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/cn"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/hk"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/in"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/id"&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/jp"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/kr"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/my"&gt;Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mn"&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/mm"&gt;Myanmar&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/ph"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/sg"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/lk"&gt;Sri Lanka&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/tw"&gt;Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/th"&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://woodegg.com/vn"&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all ebooks for under $10 each, sold at LeanPub, Amazon, and Apple iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
